<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Comparative Biochemistry</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Interdisciplinary Graduate Group in Comparative Biochemistry offers unique opportunities for students to obtain the PhD degree in a broad range of disciplines that use biochemical and molecular approaches to problems in the biological sciences. Opportunities for research exist with faculty from diverse departments and research units on the Berkeley campus including Molecular and Cell Biology, Nutritional Sciences, Plant and Microbial Biology, Chemistry, Public Health, Environmental Science and Policy Management, and the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. </p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/comparative-biochemistry/">Comparative Biochemistry</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Comparative Biochemistry</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_compbio294" data-toggle="#cb_compbio294">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">COMPBIO 294</span> 
<span class="title">Comparative Biochemistry Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_compbio294">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
The objective of this course is to provide an overview of the research activities conducted by faculty members of the Graduate Group in Comparative Biochemistry. The lectures will cover a wide range of interdisciplinary research topics reflecting the breadth of the Group. An important goal of this course is to enhance intellectual and collaborative interactions between students and faculty of the Graduate Group by increasing awareness of the range</span><span class="deschide"> of research projects. The course will be conducted in a seminar format and is required for students new to the Graduate Group. It is also recommended for advanced students currently in the Group.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Comparative Biochemistry Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="286" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Comparative Biochemistry/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Comparative Biochemistry Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_compbio299" data-toggle="#cb_compbio299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">COMPBIO 299</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_compbio299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Graduate student research.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="115" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in the Comparative Biochemistry Graduate Group</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 2.5-30 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1.5-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of research/laboratory per week per unit.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Comparative Biochemistry/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Adam Arkin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Systems modeling.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/adam-arkin"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mina J.Bissell, <i>Distinguished Scientist</i>. </strong>Breast cancer research, enhanced role of extracellular matrix (ECM), nucleus environment to gene expression in normal  and malignant tissues.<br/><a href="http://www2.lbl.gov/LBL-Programs/lifesciences/BissellLab/main.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven Brenner, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, computational biology, evolutionary biology, bioengineering, structural genomics, computational genomics, cellular activity, cellular functions, personal genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14469"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George A. Brooks, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Exercise and environmental physiology, metabolism, lactate shuttle, crossover concept, lactate, lactic acidosis, traumatic brain injury, obesity, diabetes, the Warburg Effect in cancer, aging biology, isotope tracer technology, arterial-venous difference measurements, clamp technology, muscle biopsies, cell culture, mitochondrial biogenesis, energy substrate partitioning, carbohydrate metabolism, lipid metabolism, fatty acid reesterification, menopause.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14171"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Judith Campisi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mechanisms that link tumor suppression and the development of cancer to aging and the major diseases associated with aging .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jamie Cate, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular basis for protein synthesis by the ribosome, RNA, antibiotics, a thermophilic bacterium, escherichia coli.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14485"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Susan E. Celniker, <i>Biochemist Senior Scientist</i>. </strong>Biological Systems and Engineering, Environmental Genomics and Systems Biology.<br/><a href="http://biosciences.lbl.gov/profiles/susan-e-celniker/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jhih-Wei Chu, <i>Biological Faculty Engineer</i>. </strong>Molecular Biophysics and Integrated Bioimaging.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Douglas S. Clark, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biochemical engineering and biocatalysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/douglas-clark"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer A. Doudna, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>RNA machines, hepatitis C virus, RNA interference, ribosomes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14290"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kenneth Downing, <i>Biophysicist Senior Scientist</i>. </strong>Development and application of electron methodology for determination of macromolecular and subcellular structures .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter H. Duesberg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetic structure of retroviruses, carcinogenesis, aneuploidy, virology, HIV-AIDS.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13885"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lin He, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Comparative genomics, developmental biology, cell biology.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/lin-he"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sona Kang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Epigenetics, chromatin remodeling, gene expression, diabetes, metabolic diseases .<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sona-kang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gary H. Karpen, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Gene expression, cell biology, chromosome structure and function, drosophila melanogaster, centromere identity and function.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13892"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jay Keasling, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microorganism metabolic engineering for environmentally friendly product   .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jay-d-keasling"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sung-Hou Kim, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational genomics, Structural Biology, drug discovery, disease genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14921"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Judith P. Klinman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Catalytic and regulatory mechanisms in enzyme-catalyzed reactions, kinetic, spectroscopic, stereochemical biological techniques, peptide- derived cofactors, Nuclear tunneling and role of protein dynamics in catalysis, enzymatic activation of molecular oxygen.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13893"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Isao Kubo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Agriculture, insect biology, pest management.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14938"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Kuriyan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Structural and functional studies of signal transduction, DNA replication, cancer therapies, phosphorylation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13895"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stuart M. Linn, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biology, enzymology of DNA metabolism, DNA repair and replication in mammalian cells, mechanisms of DNA damage by reactive oxygen species, structure of iron: DNA complexes, DNA damage and repair, DNA polymerases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15063"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fenyong Liu, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15029"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sangwei Lu, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Pathogenesis and Transmission of Salmonella, Foodborne Pathogens, Foodborne Diseases-Detection and Prevention.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sangwei-lu"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jian-Hua Mao, <i>Geneticist Senior Staff Scientist</i>. </strong>A systems biology approach to identification of genetic networks controlling susceptibility to genomic instability and carcinogenesis induced by radiation.<br/><a href="http://biosciences.lbl.gov/profiles/jian-hua-mao-2/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gerard Marriott, <i>Biochemist Faculty Scientist</i>. </strong>Molecular Biophysics and Integrated Bioimaging, Cellular and Tissue Imaging.<br/><a href="http://biosciences.lbl.gov/profiles/gerard-marriott/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anastasios Melis, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Photosynthesis, Metabolic Engineering, bioenergy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15342"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anders Naar, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Gene expression, microRNAs, Mammalian Cell Metabolism, Metabolic Diseases, obesity, Type 2 diabetes, NAFLD/NASH, cancer therapies .<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/people/faculty"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joseph L. Napoli, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Metabolism, nutritional biochemistry, fat-soluble vitamins, retinoids, retinoic acid, retinol, vitamin A, vitamin D, analytical biochemistry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15165"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Olzmann, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Cell biology, organelle biogenesis, lipid droplet regulation, lipotoxicity, lipid storage, cell death, protein quality control, systems biology, metabolic disease, cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16268"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Randy W. Schekman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Saccharomyces cerevisiae, organelle assembly, intracellular protein transport, assembly of cellular organelles, Alzheimer's Disease.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13908"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martyn T. Smith, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, genomics, toxicology, molecular epidemiology, exposome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15044"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hei Sook Sul, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15684"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nir Yosef, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Computational biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/nir-yosef"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Bruce N. Ames, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, cancer, aging, mitochondrial decay, oxidants and antioxidants, micronutrient deficiencies and DNA damage, chronic inflammation and cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14339"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nancy Amy, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Nutritional science and toxicology, nutrition, cell metabolism, trace elements.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14374"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George W. Chang, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Microbial biology, health and nutrition, food safety.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14489"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ben De Lumen, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Cancer prevention, academic enterpreneurship.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14535"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barry Shane, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Montgomery Slatkin, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Evolutionary theory, genetic evolution, natural populations of plants and animals populations, human populations, natural selection structure genomes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15458"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

