<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Data Science Undergraduate Studies</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Data Science Undergraduate Studies offers a diverse range of opportunities for undergraduates interested in exploring the fast-growing field of data science.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">The </span><a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/academics/undergraduate-programs/data-science-major">data science major</a> incorporates technical foundations and the study of <a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/degrees/human-contexts-and-ethics">human contexts and ethics</a>, along with more than two dozen <a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/degrees/domain-emphasis">domain emphases</a>, or areas of application. The <a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/academics/undergraduate-programs/data-science-minor">data science minor</a> features a flexible design to serve students from a range of majors.</p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Undergraduates also can explore related topics through the departments of </span><a href="https://eecs.berkeley.edu/academics/undergraduate">Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences</a> and <a href="https://statistics.berkeley.edu/programs">Statistics</a>, as well as through data science offerings such as <a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/education/modules">Modules</a>, <a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/research/discovery-program/about-discovery">Discovery</a>, and <a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/education/connectors">Connectors</a>. </p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a"><a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/education/courses/data-8">Data 8: Foundations of Data Science</a></span> provides an introduction to students from any major. It is designed specifically for students who have not previously taken statistics or computer science courses. </p>
<h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Key Features</span></h3>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Depth: Our program draws on the University’s world leading scholars in computer science, statistics, and a range of other disciplines.</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Integration: We offer data science curricula in the context of courses spanning the humanities and social and natural sciences, mirroring the cross-cutting nature of data science. </span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Impact: Students and researchers tackle real-world problems and grapple with the societal, human, and political ramifications of data science. </span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Engagement: Hundreds of students every semester engage as full partners in curriculum design, research, advising, and communications.</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Leadership: We provide resources on our curriculum and educational approach to educational institutions around the world through workshops, open source materials, and other collaborations.</span></p>
	</li>
</ul>
<h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a">Undergraduate Programs</span></h3>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-279f9375-7fff-ff2a-7a77-b75138e7170a"><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/data-science/">Data Science Major</a> (offered through the College of Letters and Science)</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/data-science/">Data Science Minor </a></span><span>(offered through the Division of Computing, Data Science, and Society)</span></p>
	</li>
</ul>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

