<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Science and Math Education</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Minor</h3>
<p>The Science and Math Education minor is offered by the CalTeach program. CalTeach is a program for undergraduate STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) majors interested in exploring a career in education.</p>
<p>CalTeach at UC Berkeley is working to increase the number of qualified STEM educators in K–12 classrooms. Courses in the CalTeach program are open to any STEM major with a desire to promote math and science education and equity.</p>
<p>CalTeach is unique from other education programs in that it is focused on learning and applying those skills in local classrooms. All the courses in the Science and Math Education minor have <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/field-placements.php">field placements</a> in local K-12 STEM classrooms. By the time students graduate with the minor, they will have spent over 100 hours honing their teaching in local classrooms. </p>
<p>The CalTeach program offers STEM students the opportunity to complete both a bachelor’s degree and a California teaching credential as an undergraduate. See <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/cal-teach-credential.php">teaching credential and minor with CalTeach</a> for more information.</p>
<p>The courses in the Science and Math Education minor cover topics including inquiry-based learning, creating and assessing student learning outcomes, equity in urban education, project-based instruction, methods of conducting and presenting research, and positive teacher-student interactions. The knowledge and skills gained in these courses are integral to success in any field that requires the communication of knowledge to others. This includes, but is not limited to, education, business, scientific/engineering industry, and public service.</p>
<p>Additional <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/scholarships-and-opportunities/">scholarships, internships, and research opportunities</a> are provided to students in the CalTeach minor.</p>
<h3><span class="s1">Applying for the Minor</span></h3>
<p>It is recommended to schedule a meeting with the CalTeach student services coordinator to discuss your planning and educational goals as early as possible. Learn more about advising resources <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/advising-and-resources.php">here</a>.</p>
<p>After completing the introductory course and all five upper division minor courses, speak with the student services coordinator about completing the appropriate paperwork to be awarded the minor.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<minorrequirementstext name="Minor Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p>The minor in Science and Math Education demonstrates a passion and excellence in K-12 STEM Education. Additionally earning the Science and Math minor allows you to apply to the Cal Teach science and math credential program and earn your California Teaching Credential as an undergraduate.</p>
<p>To learn more, schedule or plan, and to declare the minor please schedule an appointment with the <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/advising-and-resources.php" target="_blank">Cal Teach Student Services Coordinator. </a> </p>
<h3>Guidelines</h3>
<ol>
	<li>All minors must be declared no later than one semester before a student's Expected Graduation Term (EGT). If the semester before EGT is fall or spring, the deadline is the last day of RRR week. If the semester before EGT is summer, the deadline is the final Friday of Summer Sessions. To declare a minor, contact the department advisor for information on requirements, and the declaration process.</li>
	<li>Enroll in and complete <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="UGIS 82">UGIS 82</span></span>.</li>
	<li>Speak with the Cal Teach student services coordinator about fitting the courses for the minor into your schedule.</li>
	<li>The minor in Science and Math Education requires five courses. Note that two of these courses also fulfill American Cultures and Historical Studies breadth requirements (EDUC 131AC, and HIST 138T/180T/182AT, respectively). </li>
</ol>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Required Courses</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Take these three courses in sequence after completing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDSTEM 82">EDSTEM 82</span> and/or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDSTEM 82T">EDSTEM 82T</span>:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 130">EDUC 130</span></td><td>Knowing and Learning in Mathematics and Science</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 131AC">EDUC 131AC</span></td><td>Classroom Interactions in Science and Mathematics: A Focus on Equity and Urban Schools</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDSTEM 187">EDSTEM 187</span></td><td>Project-Based Instruction</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Complete the following two courses at any point after completing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDSTEM 82">EDSTEM 82</span> and before the completion of your bachelor's degree:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="UGIS C122">UGIS C122</span></td><td>Research Methods for Science and Mathematics K-12 Teachers</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass even"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDSTEM 189">EDSTEM 189</span></td><td colspan="2"> Integrating Research Methods into K-12 Teaching in Mathematics and Science</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="HISTORY 100ST">HISTORY 100ST</span></td><td>Special Topics in the History of Science (CalTeach)</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="HISTORY 138T">HISTORY 138T</span></td><td>History of Science in the US CalTeach <sup>1</sup></td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass even lastrow"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="HISTORY 180T">HISTORY 180T</span></td><td colspan="2"> History of the Life Sciences Since 1750 (Cal Teach)</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass even lastrow"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="HISTORY 182AT">HISTORY 182AT</span></td><td colspan="2"> Science, Technology, and Society (Cal Teach)</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<dl class="sc_footnotes" aria-label="Footnotes"><dt> <sup> 1 </sup> </dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent">The course offered varies by semester. Check <a href="https://classes.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">classes.berkeley.edu</a> for which course is offered in the upcoming semester.</p></dd></dl>
]]>
</minorrequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

