<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Comparative Biochemistry</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The interdisciplinary Graduate Group in Comparative Biochemistry administers the PhD degree for students interested in a biochemical and molecular approach to problems in the biological sciences. Students work under the supervision of faculty from diverse disciplines including Molecular and Cell Biology; Nutritional Science and Toxicology; Plant and Microbial Biology; Chemistry; Chemical Engineering; Environmental Science, Policy, and Management; Public Health; and the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext name="Doctoral Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Normative Time Requirements</h3>
<p class="Normal1">Normative time is defined as the elapsed time in years that under normal circumstances would be needed to complete all requirements for the PhD degree assuming that the student engaged in full-time, uninterrupted study and is making desirable progress toward the degree. The normative time for Comparative Biochemistry is five years. Requirements include completion of course work, an oral qualifying exam, and a Ph.D. dissertation. Listed below is a sample of courses that students may take to satisfy the course requirements. The exact courses taken will vary depending on the student's research focus and goals. </p>
<h3>Curriculum</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Courses Required (examples)   </span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Advanced Biochemistry/Molecular Biology:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MCELLBI 110">MCELLBI 110</span></td><td>Molecular Biology: Macromolecular Synthesis and Cellular Function</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MCELLBI 200A">MCELLBI 200A</span></td><td>Fundamentals of Molecular and Cell Biology</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Enzymes/Metabolism/Cell Biology/Plant Microbial Biology:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PLANTBI 200A">PLANTBI 200A</span></td><td>Plant Developmental Genetics</td><td class="hourscol">1.5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUSCTX 250">NUSCTX 250</span></td><td>Advanced Topics in Metabolic Biology</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MCELLBI C214">MCELLBI C214</span></td><td>Protein Chemistry, Enzymology, and Bio-organic Chemistry</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MCELLBI 230">MCELLBI 230</span></td><td>Advanced Cell and Developmental Biology</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Physical Biochemistry:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MCELLBI 206">MCELLBI 206</span></td><td>Physical Biochemistry</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 270A">CHEM 270A/270B</span></td><td>Advanced Biophysical Chemistry I</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPBIO 294">COMPBIO 294</span></td><td>Comparative Biochemistry Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Grad Elective Courses per approved study list</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Grad Elective Seminar per approved study list</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPBIO 299">COMPBIO 299</span></td><td>Graduate Research</td><td class="hourscol">1-12</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Comparative Biochemistry</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_compbio294" data-toggle="#cb_compbio294">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">COMPBIO 294</span> 
<span class="title">Comparative Biochemistry Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_compbio294">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
The objective of this course is to provide an overview of the research activities conducted by faculty members of the Graduate Group in Comparative Biochemistry. The lectures will cover a wide range of interdisciplinary research topics reflecting the breadth of the Group. An important goal of this course is to enhance intellectual and collaborative interactions between students and faculty of the Graduate Group by increasing awareness of the range</span><span class="deschide"> of research projects. The course will be conducted in a seminar format and is required for students new to the Graduate Group. It is also recommended for advanced students currently in the Group.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Comparative Biochemistry Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="707" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Comparative Biochemistry/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Comparative Biochemistry Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_compbio299" data-toggle="#cb_compbio299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">COMPBIO 299</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_compbio299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Graduate student research.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="951" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in the Comparative Biochemistry Graduate Group</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 2.5-30 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1.5-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of research/laboratory per week per unit.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Comparative Biochemistry/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Adam Arkin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Systems modeling.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/adam-arkin"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mina J.Bissell, <i>Distinguished Scientist</i>. </strong>Breast cancer research, enhanced role of extracellular matrix (ECM), nucleus environment to gene expression in normal  and malignant tissues.<br/><a href="http://www2.lbl.gov/LBL-Programs/lifesciences/BissellLab/main.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven Brenner, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, computational biology, evolutionary biology, bioengineering, structural genomics, computational genomics, cellular activity, cellular functions, personal genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14469"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George A. Brooks, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Exercise and environmental physiology, metabolism, lactate shuttle, crossover concept, lactate, lactic acidosis, traumatic brain injury, obesity, diabetes, the Warburg Effect in cancer, aging biology, isotope tracer technology, arterial-venous difference measurements, clamp technology, muscle biopsies, cell culture, mitochondrial biogenesis, energy substrate partitioning, carbohydrate metabolism, lipid metabolism, fatty acid reesterification, menopause.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14171"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Judith Campisi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mechanisms that link tumor suppression and the development of cancer to aging and the major diseases associated with aging .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jamie Cate, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular basis for protein synthesis by the ribosome, RNA, antibiotics, a thermophilic bacterium, escherichia coli.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14485"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Susan E. Celniker, <i>Biochemist Senior Scientist</i>. </strong>Biological Systems and Engineering, Environmental Genomics and Systems Biology.<br/><a href="http://biosciences.lbl.gov/profiles/susan-e-celniker/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jhih-Wei Chu, <i>Biological Faculty Engineer</i>. </strong>Molecular Biophysics and Integrated Bioimaging.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Douglas S. Clark, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biochemical engineering and biocatalysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/douglas-clark"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer A. Doudna, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>RNA machines, hepatitis C virus, RNA interference, ribosomes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14290"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kenneth Downing, <i>Biophysicist Senior Scientist</i>. </strong>Development and application of electron methodology for determination of macromolecular and subcellular structures .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter H. Duesberg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetic structure of retroviruses, carcinogenesis, aneuploidy, virology, HIV-AIDS.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13885"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lin He, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Comparative genomics, developmental biology, cell biology.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/lin-he"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sona Kang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Epigenetics, chromatin remodeling, gene expression, diabetes, metabolic diseases .<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sona-kang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gary H. Karpen, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Gene expression, cell biology, chromosome structure and function, drosophila melanogaster, centromere identity and function.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13892"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jay Keasling, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microorganism metabolic engineering for environmentally friendly product   .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jay-d-keasling"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sung-Hou Kim, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational genomics, Structural Biology, drug discovery, disease genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14921"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Judith P. Klinman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Catalytic and regulatory mechanisms in enzyme-catalyzed reactions, kinetic, spectroscopic, stereochemical biological techniques, peptide- derived cofactors, Nuclear tunneling and role of protein dynamics in catalysis, enzymatic activation of molecular oxygen.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13893"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Isao Kubo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Agriculture, insect biology, pest management.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14938"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Kuriyan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Structural and functional studies of signal transduction, DNA replication, cancer therapies, phosphorylation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13895"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stuart M. Linn, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biology, enzymology of DNA metabolism, DNA repair and replication in mammalian cells, mechanisms of DNA damage by reactive oxygen species, structure of iron: DNA complexes, DNA damage and repair, DNA polymerases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15063"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fenyong Liu, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15029"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sangwei Lu, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Pathogenesis and Transmission of Salmonella, Foodborne Pathogens, Foodborne Diseases-Detection and Prevention.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sangwei-lu"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jian-Hua Mao, <i>Geneticist Senior Staff Scientist</i>. </strong>A systems biology approach to identification of genetic networks controlling susceptibility to genomic instability and carcinogenesis induced by radiation.<br/><a href="http://biosciences.lbl.gov/profiles/jian-hua-mao-2/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gerard Marriott, <i>Biochemist Faculty Scientist</i>. </strong>Molecular Biophysics and Integrated Bioimaging, Cellular and Tissue Imaging.<br/><a href="http://biosciences.lbl.gov/profiles/gerard-marriott/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anastasios Melis, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Photosynthesis, Metabolic Engineering, bioenergy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15342"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anders Naar, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Gene expression, microRNAs, Mammalian Cell Metabolism, Metabolic Diseases, obesity, Type 2 diabetes, NAFLD/NASH, cancer therapies .<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/people/faculty"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joseph L. Napoli, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Metabolism, nutritional biochemistry, fat-soluble vitamins, retinoids, retinoic acid, retinol, vitamin A, vitamin D, analytical biochemistry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15165"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Olzmann, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Cell biology, organelle biogenesis, lipid droplet regulation, lipotoxicity, lipid storage, cell death, protein quality control, systems biology, metabolic disease, cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16268"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Randy W. Schekman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Saccharomyces cerevisiae, organelle assembly, intracellular protein transport, assembly of cellular organelles, Alzheimer's Disease.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13908"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martyn T. Smith, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, genomics, toxicology, molecular epidemiology, exposome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15044"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hei Sook Sul, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15684"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nir Yosef, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Computational biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/nir-yosef"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Bruce N. Ames, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, cancer, aging, mitochondrial decay, oxidants and antioxidants, micronutrient deficiencies and DNA damage, chronic inflammation and cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14339"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nancy Amy, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Nutritional science and toxicology, nutrition, cell metabolism, trace elements.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14374"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George W. Chang, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Microbial biology, health and nutrition, food safety.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14489"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ben De Lumen, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Cancer prevention, academic enterpreneurship.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14535"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barry Shane, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Montgomery Slatkin, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Evolutionary theory, genetic evolution, natural populations of plants and animals populations, human populations, natural selection structure genomes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15458"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

