<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Jurisprudence and Social Policy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>UC Berkeley Law School’s Jurisprudence and Social Policy (JSP) Program offers a unique interdisciplinary graduate program leading to PhD degrees for students interested in:</p>
<ul>
	<li>The scholarly study of legal ideas and institutions from the standpoint of one or more of the basic disciplines, such as history, economics, philosophy, sociology, or political science.</li>
	<li>Policy analysis and applied research on law-related issues in such fields as criminal justice, poverty and discrimination, human rights, urban planning, and environmental protection.</li>
	<li>Preparation for teaching legal studies in graduate and undergraduate curriculums.</li>
	<li>Interdisciplinary preparation for teaching law.</li>
</ul>
<p>Admission to the JSP Program does not require a juris doctor (JD) degree and does not lead to a JD degree. Students may apply to both the law school’s JD and JSP Programs; however, admission to one does not guarantee admission to the other.</p>
<p>Applicants have two options:</p>
<ul>
	<li>To seek admission to the JSP Program alone, leading to the PhD degree without a JD degree.</li>
	<li>To seek admission to both programs, leading, if admitted to both, to the JD and PhD degrees. Completion of the first option normally takes about five years and completion of the second option includes an additional year or more.</li>
</ul>
<p>A fundamental objective of the JSP Program is to focus the knowledge and perspectives of the social sciences and humanities on the analysis of law, legal discourses, legal institutions, and law-related policies. To this end, JSP’s faculty includes scholars from economics, history, philosophy, political science, psychology, and sociology.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/jurisprudence-social-policy/">Jurisprudence and Social Policy</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Catherine R. Albiston, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Social movements, gender, employment law, legal profession, public interest law.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/catherine-albiston/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lauren Edelman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Organizations and employment, civil rights, social inequality, disability, research methods.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/lauren-edelman/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rebecca Goldstein, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Racial and ethnic politics, bureaucratic politics, and the politics of criminal justice policy.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/rebecca-goldstein/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Grewal, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Legal theory, political theory, intellectual history, global economic governance, international trade law, intellectual property law and biotechnology, law and economics.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/david-singh-grewal/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kinch Hoekstra, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Political theory, history of philosophy  .<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/kinch-hoekstra/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher Kutz, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Moral/political philosophy, ethics and laws of war .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14184"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Calvin Morrill, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Organizations, culture, social movements, education, youth, research methods.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/calvin-morrill/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Osagie Obasogie, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Bioethics, policing and police use of force, race in law and medicine, constitutional law.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/osagie-k-obasogie/#tab_profile"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dylan Penningroth, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>African American and U.S. socio-legal history.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/dylan-penningroth/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Victoria Plaut, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Diversity/Inclusion, culture, research methods.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/victoria-plaut/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jonathan Simon, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Criminal justice, punishment and society, mass incarceration.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/jonathan-simon/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sarah Song, <i>Professor</i>. </strong> Citizenship, migration, race, feminist theory.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/sarah-song/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rachel Stern, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Courts, authoritarian states, globalization, China.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/rachel-stern/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher Tomlins, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Labor, slavery, colonization, history of contemporary legal thought.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/christopher-tomlins/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Robert D. Cooter, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Business law, contracts, torts.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/robert-cooter/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Malcolm M. Feeley, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Criminal law, punishment, social policy.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/malcolm-feeley/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Robert Kagan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Law and political science.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/robert-kagan/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Lieberman, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>History of legal ideas, legal theory  .<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/david-lieberman/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kristin Luker, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Sociology of law.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/kristin-luker/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Rubinfield, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Law and economics.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/daniel-rubinfeld/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Harry Scheiber, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Law and History.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/harry-scheiber/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martin Shapiro, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Law and political science.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/martin-shapiro/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Franklin E. Zimring, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Legal policy, criminal sanctions, policing.<br/><a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/our-faculty/faculty-profiles/franklin-zimring/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

