<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Architecture</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">The department offers an accredited professional Master of Architecture (MArch), a post-professional Master of Advanced Architectural Design (MAAD), Master of Science (MS) and Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) degrees.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Master of Architecture (MArch)</h3>
<p class="Normal1">The Master of Architecture program is designed to provide students seeking their first accredited professional degree with a comprehensive and challenging education leading to the practice of architecture. Graduate students have the flexibility to choose a variety of paths within a two-to-three-year rigorous program, depending upon previous education and experience. The department makes no restriction as to the field of undergraduate preparation. However, the length of the required residence period, the number of required semester course units, and the specific list of required courses may vary depending upon undergraduate major, professional and other work experience, and previous graduate study, if any. The placement into the program will be decided by the Master of Architecture Committee upon reviewing the application.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Master of Advanced Architectural Design (MAAD) </h3>
<p class="Normal1">STUDIO ONE is a one-year post-professional design studio intended for those who have a professional (Bachelor or Master of Architecture) degree, and who wish to continue to explore current design issues in a stimulating, rigorous, and experimental studio setting. Students who complete the program will receive a non-accredited Master of Advanced Architectural Design degree. The two-semester studio course is at the core of the program and is integrated with required seminars, lectures, and workshops in design theory, history, urbanism, digital applications, and building technology.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Master of Science (MS)</h3>
<p class="Normal1">This researched-based, non-professional degree program offers the opportunity for advanced research in specialized areas within the increasingly complex subfields within architecture, preparing students for a range of careers. The degree emphasizes coursework and supervised independent research in one of the following areas of study: <em>Building Science, Technology and Sustainability</em> or <em>History, Theory and Society</em>. The undergraduate degrees of our entering M.S. students are diverse, including architecture, history, engineering, environmental sciences, or a range of other disciplines related to the built environment.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Doctor of Philosophy (PhD)</h3>
<p class="Normal1">This advanced research-based degree prepares students with outstanding academic records for careers in teaching and scholarship in architecture and its related areas, or in roles in government or private companies and organizations that require specialization and experience in research. The program emphasizes an interdisciplinary approach of both depth and breadth as part of the student’s formal coursework and original research. The student defines their specialty (the basis for the dissertation), in one of the following areas of study: <em>Building Science, Technology and Sustainability</em> or <em>History, Theory and Society</em>.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Admission to the Department</h3>
<p class="tglhead">For specific admission requirements and deadlines for Architecture programs MArch, MAAD, MS and PhD, please go to the department website: <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/admissions/graduate/programs-deadlines/">http://ced.berkeley.edu/admissions/graduate/programs-deadlines/</a></p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext name="Doctoral Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p class="p1">The Ph.D. in Architecture is a research degree appropriate for those seeking careers in teaching and scholarship in architecture and its related areas, or in roles in government or professional consultation that require depth in specialization and experience in research. Berkeley’s Ph.D. program in architecture is interdisciplinary in outlook, reaching into the various disciplines related to architecture and incorporating substantial knowledge from outside fields. Students admitted to this program carry out a program of advanced study and research, both on the basis of formal class work and of individual investigation. Work centers on related fields of study, the major field (the basis for the dissertation), and one-to-two minor fields, at least one of which must be from a discipline outside architecture, a minimum of 48 units, two-year academic residency, passing the qualifying exam and submission of a dissertation.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Curriculum: 48 Units</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Methods Course, depending on concentration:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Building Science, Technology &amp; Sustainability - Arch 241, 3 units</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">History, Theory &amp; Society - Arch 281, 4 units</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Inside Field (Speciality):</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Minimum of 3 courses per approved individualized study in one of the concentrations (3-4 unit graduate classes for a letter grade)</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Outside Field(s) Two Options:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">One outside field (not in department), minimum four courses (3-4 unit graduate classes for a letter grade)</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Two outside fields, minimum two courses each (for students without a degree in Architecture, one must be within the Department. Considered Architectural Breadth.) BSTS: the courses must be taken outside their speciality and may come from other Architecture program areas such as History, Theory or Society. HTS: the courses must be offered by instructors other than those with whom the student has taken coursework for the Inside Field. (3-4 unit graduate classes for a letter grade) </span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Language (applies only to students in History, Theory &amp; Society): one language, high proficiency or two languages, low proficiency</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Written qualifying examination, followed by an oral qualifying examination</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Dissertation submission with approval of the dissertation committee</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"/><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<mastersdegreerequirementsmstext name="Master's Degree Requirements (MS)">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Curriculum: 36 Units</h3>
<p>The last two decades have seen rapid growth in the complexity of buildings and the development of specialized knowledge for their design and operation. The building profession now requires a wider range of expertise in design, operation, and management than was required in the past, and new types of professional specialists have emerged to provide this expertise. Often these experts are educated outside of traditional architectural programs, frequently through studies in other disciplines.</p>
<p>The Master of Science (M.S.) in Architecture is an academic, nonprofessional degree program that offers the opportunity for advanced research in the ever-broadening and increasingly complex subfields within architecture. Some students enter with a degree in architecture, or occasionally while here, will get an additional Master of Architecture degree (the professional degree accredited for the practice of architecture).  But neither is required, and the undergraduate degrees of our entering M.S. students are diverse.</p>
<p>The following list applies to both concentrations.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Methods Course, depending on concentration:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Building Science, Technology &amp; Sustainability - Arch 241, 3 units</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">History, Theory &amp; Society - Arch 281, 4 units</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Inside Field (Speciality) </span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Minimum of three courses per approved individualized study in one of the concentrations (3-4 unit graduate classes for a letter grade)</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Architecture Breadth Area: for those without an architecture degree</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Minimum two courses within the department but from faculty members different than those with whom the student had taken courses for the Inside Field (3-4 unit graduate classes for a letter grade)</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Thesis submission</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Arch 299 (independent study) course sponsored by your thesis chair</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"/><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementsmstext>
<mastersdegreerequirementsmarchtext name="Master's Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Curriculum</h3>
<h4>Requirements for One-Year Master of Advanced Architectural Design: 24 Units </h4>
<p>Post-professional degree students with a professional undergraduate Architecture degree.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 205A">ARCH 205A</span></td><td>Studio One, Fall</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 205B">ARCH 205B</span></td><td>Studio One, Spring</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Required Seminar in Humanities - 3 units</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Required Seminar in Technology - 3 units</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h4>Requirements for the Two-Year Master of Architecture: 48 Units</h4>
<p>Students with a pre-professional BA or BS in Architecture. Placement will be determined by the Master of Architecture Committee.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 201">ARCH 201</span></td><td>Architecture &amp; Urbanism Design Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 202">ARCH 202</span></td><td>Graduate Option Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 203">ARCH 203</span></td><td>Integrated Design Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 204A">ARCH 204A</span></td><td>Thesis Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 204B">ARCH 204B</span></td><td>Thesis Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 207B">ARCH 207B</span></td><td>Architecture Research Colloquium</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 207C">ARCH 207C</span></td><td>Professional Practice Colloquium</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 207D">ARCH 207D</span></td><td>The Cultures of Practice <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 230">ARCH 230</span></td><td>Advanced Architectural Design Theory and Criticism <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 240">ARCH 240</span></td><td>Advanced Study of Energy and Environment <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 250">ARCH 250</span></td><td>Introduction to Structures <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 260">ARCH 260</span></td><td>Introduction to Construction, Graduate Level <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 270">ARCH 270</span></td><td>History of Modern Architecture <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Courses marked * may possibly be waived based on previous coursework. To be considered for a waiver, submit waiver form, equivalent undergraduate course description and syllabus, and transcript before the first semester. If a required course is waived, an advanced course in the same area will need to be taken.</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h4>Requirements for the Three-Year Master of Architecture: 72 Units</h4>
<p>Students without a pre-professional BA or BS in Architecture. Placement will be determined by the Master of Architecture Committee.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 200A">ARCH 200A</span></td><td>Introduction to Architecture Studio 1</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 200B">ARCH 200B</span></td><td>Introduction to Architecture Studio 2</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 200C">ARCH 200C</span></td><td>Representational Practice in Architectural Design</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 207A">ARCH 207A</span></td><td>Architecture Lectures Colloquium</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 207B">ARCH 207B</span></td><td>Architecture Research Colloquium</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 207C">ARCH 207C</span></td><td>Professional Practice Colloquium</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 207D">ARCH 207D</span></td><td>The Cultures of Practice <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 201">ARCH 201</span></td><td>Architecture &amp; Urbanism Design Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 202">ARCH 202</span></td><td>Graduate Option Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 203">ARCH 203</span></td><td>Integrated Design Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 204A">ARCH 204A</span></td><td>Thesis Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 204B">ARCH 204B</span></td><td>Thesis Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 230">ARCH 230</span></td><td>Advanced Architectural Design Theory and Criticism <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 240">ARCH 240</span></td><td>Advanced Study of Energy and Environment <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 250">ARCH 250</span></td><td>Introduction to Structures <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 260">ARCH 260</span></td><td>Introduction to Construction, Graduate Level <sup>*</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 270">ARCH 270</span></td><td>History of Modern Architecture</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Courses marked * may possibly be waived based on previous coursework. To be considered for a waiver, submit a waiver form, equivalent undergraduate course description and syllabus, and transcript before the first semester. If the required course is waived, an advanced course in the same area will need to be taken.</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementsmarchtext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Architecture</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch200a" data-toggle="#cb_arch200a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 200A</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Architecture Studio 1</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch200a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Introductory course in architectural design and theories for graduate students. Problems emphasize the major format, spatial, material, tectonic, social, technological, and environmental determinants of building form. Studio work is supplemented by lectures, discussions, readings, and field trips.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Architecture Studio 1:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="33" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four hours of lecture/seminar, eight hours of studio, and four hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Architecture Studio 1:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch200b" data-toggle="#cb_arch200b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 200B</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Architecture Studio 2</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch200b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Introductory course in architectural design and theories for graduate students. Problems emphasize the major format, spatial, material, tectonic, social, technological, and environmental determinants of building form. Studio work is supplemented by lectures, discussions, readings, and field trips.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Architecture Studio 2:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="571" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four hours of lecture/seminar, eight hours of studio, and four hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Architecture Studio 2:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch200c" data-toggle="#cb_arch200c">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 200C</span> 
<span class="title">Representational Practice in Architectural Design</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch200c">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course will address three distinct levels of representational practice in architectural design: 1) cultivate an understanding of the foundational discourse and diversity of approaches to architectural representation; 2) develop a fluency in the canonical methods found in architectural practice; 3) encourage the development of a personal relationship to forms of modeling and formats of drawing.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Representational Practice in Architectural Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="374" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> 200C must be taken in conjunction with 200A.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4 hours of seminar and 1 hour of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of laboratory and four hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Steinfeld</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Representational Practice in Architectural Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch200d" data-toggle="#cb_arch200d">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 200D</span> 
<span class="title">Representational Practice in Architectural Design II</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch200d">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022<br/>
<span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 200D">ARCH 200D</span> is the second part in a two-part sequence of classes that introduces students to techniques of architectural representation as well as the concepts and precedents that surround them. Building on the concepts and techniques introduced in <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 200C">ARCH 200C</span>, this class will expand students’ technical knowledge to include rendering, notation, and graphic design. Each topic will be broken into a separate module and be supported with lectures, discussions</span><span class="deschide">, tutorials, workshops and presentations. Additionally, the class is closely linked with <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 200B">ARCH 200B</span>, Introduction to Architecture Studio 2 and will provide much of the technical skill-building for that class.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Representational Practice in Architectural Design II:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="418" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Representational Practice in Architectural Design II:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch201" data-toggle="#cb_arch201">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 201</span> 
<span class="title">Architecture &amp; Urbanism Design Studio</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch201">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
The design of buildings or communities of advanced complexity. Each section deals with a specific topic such as housing, public and institutional buildings, and local or international community development. Studio work is supplemented by lectures, discussions, readings, and field trips.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Architecture &amp; Urbanism Design Studio:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="663" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A-100B or 200A-200B</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 6 hours of studio per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture and 13 hours of studio per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 5.5 hours of lecture and 9.5 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Six hours of studio and two hours of lecture per week. Nine hours of studio and five hours of lecture per week for 8 weeks. Thirteen hours of studio and seven hours of lecture per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Architecture &amp; Urbanism Design Studio:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch202" data-toggle="#cb_arch202">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 202</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Option Studio</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch202">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2020<br/>
Focused design and research for graduate students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Option Studio:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="32" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of studio per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Option Studio:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch203" data-toggle="#cb_arch203">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 203</span> 
<span class="title">Integrated Design Studio</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch203">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2021, Fall 2020<br/>
The Integrated Design Studio is the penultimate studio where students incorporate their accumulated knowledge into architectural solutions. The students demonstrate the<br/>
integrative thinking that shapes complex architectural design and technical solutions. Students will possess an understanding to classify, compare, summarize, explain and/or interpret information. The students will also become proficient in using specific information to accomplish</span><span class="deschide"> a task, correctly selecting the appropriate information and accurately applying it to the solution of a specific problem while also distinguishing the effects of its implementation.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Integrated Design Studio:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="131" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of studio per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Integrated Design Studio:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch204" data-toggle="#cb_arch204">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 204</span> 
<span class="title">Final Project Studio: Studio Thesis Option</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch204">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2011, Spring 2010<br/>
Focused design research as the capstone project for graduate students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Final Project Studio: Studio Thesis Option:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="926" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of Studio per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 202A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Final Project Studio: Studio Thesis Option:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch204a" data-toggle="#cb_arch204a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 204A</span> 
<span class="title">Thesis Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch204a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Focused design research as the capstone project for graduate students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Thesis Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="587" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Thesis Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch204b" data-toggle="#cb_arch204b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 204B</span> 
<span class="title">Thesis Studio</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch204b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Focused design research as the capstone project for graduate students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Thesis Studio:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="832" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of Studio per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 204</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Thesis Studio:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch205a" data-toggle="#cb_arch205a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 205A</span> 
<span class="title">Studio One, Fall</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch205a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
The first semester of a one-year, post-professional design studio intended for those students who have a professional architecture degree and wish to explore current design issues in a stimulating, rigorous, and highly experimental studio setting.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Studio One, Fall:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="394" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of Chair or graduate advisors during fall semester</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of studio per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Studio One, Fall:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch205b" data-toggle="#cb_arch205b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 205B</span> 
<span class="title">Studio One, Spring</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch205b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This course is the second semester of a one-year, post-professional studio intended for those students who have a professional architecture degree and wish to explore current design issues in a stimulating, rigorous, and highly experimental studio setting.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Studio One, Spring:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="642" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of chair or graduate advisors</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of Studio per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 205</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Studio One, Spring:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch207a" data-toggle="#cb_arch207a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 207A</span> 
<span class="title">Architecture Lectures Colloquium</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch207a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course accompanies the required introductory design studio in the three-year option of the Master of Architecture program. It is the first in a series of three one-unit colloquia, scheduled consecutively for the first three semesters of the program. Students will attend all Wednesday evening lectures of the College of Environmental Design lecture series. Every third week, they will meet with the instructor for a one-hour discussion.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Architecture Lectures Colloquium:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="237" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Architecture Lectures Colloquium:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch207b" data-toggle="#cb_arch207b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 207B</span> 
<span class="title">Architecture Research Colloquium</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch207b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course accompanies the second year of the required architecture and urbanism design studio in the three-year option of the Master of Architecture program. It is the second in a series of three one-unit colloquia, scheduled consecutively in the fall for the first three years of the program. For a one-hour session each week, faculty in the department of architecture, other departments of the College of Environmental Design, and global guest</span><span class="deschide"> speakers will present lectures on their research and design practices in urbanism.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Architecture Research Colloquium:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="149" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Co-requisite with Architecture 201</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Chow</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Architecture Research Colloquium:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch207c" data-toggle="#cb_arch207c">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 207C</span> 
<span class="title">Professional Practice Colloquium</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch207c">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course accompanies the required comprehensive design studio in the three-year option of the Master of Architecture program. It is the third in a series of three one-unit colloquia, scheduled consecutively for the first three semesters of the program.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Professional Practice Colloquium:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="973" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Concurrent enrollment in Arch 203 Integrated Design Studio</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Professional Practice Colloquium:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch207d" data-toggle="#cb_arch207d">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 207D</span> 
<span class="title">The Cultures of Practice</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch207d">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
The nature of architectural practice, how it has evolved and how it is changing in today's world is the theme of the class. The course considers how diverse cultures--both anthropological and professional--contribute to practice, and how the culture of practice evolves. The class has three five-week modules, devoted to the following themes: traditions of practice, research in the culture of the profession, and innovations in practice.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Cultures of Practice:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="160" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 201</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Comerio, Cranz</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Cultures of Practice:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch209" data-toggle="#cb_arch209">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 209</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Architectural Design</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch209">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2022, Fall 2021, Spring 2021<br/>
Topics deal with major problems and current issues in architectural design. For current offerings, see departmental website.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Architectural Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="850" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Second- or third-year graduate standing</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 2.5-10 hours of lecture per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 2-8 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to four hours of lecture per week. Two to eight hours of lecture per week for 8 weeks. Two and one-half to ten hours of lecture per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 209X</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Architectural Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch211" data-toggle="#cb_arch211">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 211</span> 
<span class="title">Theory and Methods in the Social and Cultural Basis of Design</span> 
<span class="hours">3 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch211">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2017, Spring 2013, Spring 2011<br/>
Explores a variety of theories which explain and document the relationship between humans and the environment they build; outlines the research methods appropriate to each theory.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Theory and Methods in the Social and Cultural Basis of Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="817" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 110 or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week plus individual advising.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Cranz</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Theory and Methods in the Social and Cultural Basis of Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch212" data-toggle="#cb_arch212">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 212</span> 
<span class="title">Body-Conscious Design: Shoes, Chairs, Rooms, and Beyond</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch212">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 2023 8 Week Session, Spring 2018, Spring 2017<br/>
This seminar prepares students to evaluate and design environments from the point of view of how they interact with the human body. Tools and clothing modify that interaction. Semi-fixed features of the near environment, especially furniture, may have greater impact on physical well being and social-psychological comfort than fixed features like walls, openings, and volume. Today, designers can help redefine and legitimize</span><span class="deschide"> new attitudes toward supporting the human body by, for example, designing for a wide range of postural alternatives and possibly designing new kinds of furniture.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Body-Conscious Design: Shoes, Chairs, Rooms, and Beyond:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="602" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 5 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week. Five hours of seminar per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Cranz</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Body-Conscious Design: Shoes, Chairs, Rooms, and Beyond:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch215" data-toggle="#cb_arch215">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 215</span> 
<span class="title">Landscape, Architecture, Infrastructure, and Urbanism</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch215">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2014, Spring 2013, Spring 2012<br/>
This seminar aims to explore how the physical and conceptual understanding of landscape can enrich current forms of architectural and urban design practice. At the junction of landform, infrastructure, urban design, and architecture lies a rich field of possibilities that is increasingly superseding the narrower field of each of the disciplines by themselves. In the past century, contemporary culture and technology-automobiles, televisions</span><span class="deschide">, cell phones, and the internet have socially, culturally, environmentally, and physically reshaped the urban fabric, calling into question the very definition of urbanity. The course will explore the implications for public space in an era of increased security and risk mitigation and how designers may direct the various invisible forces which give form to the world around us.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Landscape, Architecture, Infrastructure, and Urbanism:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="885" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Davids</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Landscape, Architecture, Infrastructure, and Urbanism:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch216" data-toggle="#cb_arch216">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 216</span> 
<span class="title">The Sociology of Taste in Environmental Design</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch216">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2012, Fall 2011<br/>
Taste is at work in the way we display our things as much as in the qualities of things themselves. A performance-oriented model of taste observes that objects fall into two broad categories: pragmatic (that support behavior) and symbolic (that identify a person). People visually organize these two categories of objects using both explicit and subconscious aesthetic rules to produce visually unified displays. Depending on how it is used, how it</span><span class="deschide"> is placed in relation to other things, an object's meaning can vary. The display of taste is where objects take on--and shed--meanings, depending on how they are combined with one another. This seminar reviews the extensive body of 20th-century theory and empirical research on taste and considers the implications of theories about taste for design creation, design education, and for client-professional relations.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Sociology of Taste in Environmental Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="586" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 110, or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Cranz</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Sociology of Taste in Environmental Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch217" data-toggle="#cb_arch217">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 217</span> 
<span class="title">Social Aspects of Housing Design: Mid-Rise Urbanism</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch217">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2012, Fall 2011<br/>
The course explores strategies to bring coherence and continuity back to the city focusing on mid-rise, higher density urbanism and the potential and difficulties of this scale of urban fabric to contribute to the form of cities, without losing the potential of choice and diversity. The seminars are organized in case studies revolving around four cities: Amsterdam, Barcelona, Beijing, and New York. Design exercises parallel the case studies as a way to test</span><span class="deschide"> and challenge the potentials of mid-rise urbanism.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Social Aspects of Housing Design: Mid-Rise Urbanism:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="467" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Chow</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Social Aspects of Housing Design: Mid-Rise Urbanism:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch218" data-toggle="#cb_arch218">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 218</span> 
<span class="title">Housing, Urbanization, and Urbanism: Design, Planning, and Policy Issues in Developing Countries</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch218">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This seminar is concerned with the study of housing, urbanization, and urbanism in developing countries, studying not only the physical landscapes of settlements, but also the social, economic, political, and cultural dimensions. This course's focus will be on housing, its lens will be their processes of urbanization, and its intent will be to investigate the space for action by the professionals of the &quot;urban&quot; in the arena of housing. While the emphasis</span><span class="deschide"> of the course will be on the diverse trajectories of developing countries, &quot;First World&quot; experiences will also be used to illuminate the specific transnational connections and their use in the making of housing theory and policy. The seminar complements the series of lectures offered in 111 and City Planning 111.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Housing, Urbanization, and Urbanism: Design, Planning, and Policy Issues in Developing Countries:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="657" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of lecture and 1.5 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One and one-half hours of Lecture and One and one-half hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> AlSayyad</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Housing, Urbanization, and Urbanism: Design, Planning, and Policy Issues in Developing Countries:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch219" data-toggle="#cb_arch219">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 219</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in the Social and Cultural Basis of Design</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch219">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2019, Fall 2017, Spring 2017<br/>
Topics include the sociology of taste, personal and societal values in design, participatory design, semantic ethnography, environments for special popultions such as the elderly, and building types such as housing, hospitals, schools, offices, and urban parks. For current offerings, see departmental website.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in the Social and Cultural Basis of Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="966" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture/seminar per unit per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in the Social and Cultural Basis of Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch221" data-toggle="#cb_arch221">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 221</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Seminar in Digital Design Theories and Methods</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch221">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2013, Spring 2010, Fall 2009<br/>
This seminar is intended to help graduate students develop a coherent research agenda in the area of digital design theories and methods. In addition, it is intended to serve as a forum for the exchange of ideas (e.g., work in progress, potential directions for research, etc.) in the area of shared interest. The course provides students with a set of questions as guides, readings, and guest lectures.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Seminar in Digital Design Theories and Methods:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="495" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 235</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Seminar in Digital Design Theories and Methods:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch222" data-toggle="#cb_arch222">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 222</span> 
<span class="title">Principles of Computer Aided Architectural Design</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch222">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2009<br/>
This course introduces students to Architecture's New Media; why and how computers are being used in architecture and what are their current and expected impacts on the discipline and practice of architecture. Topics include presentation and re-presentation (including sketching, drafting, modeling, animating, and rendering); generating design solutions (generative systems, expert systems,genetic algorithms, and neural networks); evaluation and prediction (using examples</span><span class="deschide"> from structures, energy, acoustics, and human factors); and the future uses of computers in architectural design (including such topics as construction automation, smart buildings, and virtual environments). The laboratories introduce students to a REVIT, a state-of-the-art architectural software, including drafting, modeling, rendering, and building information modeling. This course is co-listed with 122. Graduate students will have a discussion section instead of the laboratory that 122 students undertake.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Principles of Computer Aided Architectural Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="882" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 6 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Six hours of lecture and two hours of supervised laboratory session per week for eight weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Principles of Computer Aided Architectural Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch226" data-toggle="#cb_arch226">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 226</span> 
<span class="title">Collaboration by Digital Design</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch226">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This project-based seminar studies the problem of multi-disciplinary and cross-cultural collaboration in the building industry. It employs two complementary approaches: 1) a theoretical approach, which examines the nature of collaboration in general and in architecture in particular, looks at the methods that have been used to foster and support it, and interrogates their advantages and shortcomings; and 2) a practical approach, which use a web-based multi-person</span><span class="deschide"> design 'game' that allow students to play different roles (architect, clients, engineer, builder, etc.) while collaborating in the design of a building.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Collaboration by Digital Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="855" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Collaboration by Digital Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch227" data-toggle="#cb_arch227">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 227</span> 
<span class="title">Workshop in Designing Virtual Places</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch227">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2010<br/>
This course introduces students to designing web-accessible, Multi User, Virtual Environments (MUVEs), inhabited through avatars. Such worlds are used in video games and web-based applications, and are assuming their role as alternative 'places' to physical spaces, where people shop, learn, are entertained, and socialize. Virtual worlds are designed according to the same principles that guide the design of physical spaces, with allowances made for the absence of gravity</span><span class="deschide"> and other laws of nature. The course combines concepts from architecture, film studies, and video game design. It uses a game engine software and a modeling software to build, test, and deploy virtual worlds.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Workshop in Designing Virtual Places:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="329" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar and 1.5 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar and one and one half hours of supervised laboratory sessions per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Workshop in Designing Virtual Places:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch229" data-toggle="#cb_arch229">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 229</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Digital Design Theories and Methods</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch229">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Selected topics in digital design theories and methods. For current offerings, see departmental website.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Digital Design Theories and Methods:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="867" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 210 or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture/seminar per unit per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Digital Design Theories and Methods:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch229a" data-toggle="#cb_arch229a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 229A</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Construction Law</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch229a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2009, Spring 2008, Spring 2007<br/></span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Construction Law:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="312" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Four hour of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 229F</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Construction Law:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch230" data-toggle="#cb_arch230">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 230</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Architectural Design Theory and Criticism</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch230">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Seminar in the analysis and discussion of contemporary and historical issues in architectural design theory and criticism.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Architectural Design Theory and Criticism:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="96" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 130A or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Forty-five hours of lecture/seminar per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Architectural Design Theory and Criticism:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch231" data-toggle="#cb_arch231">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 231</span> 
<span class="title">Research Methods in Architectural Design Theory and Criticism</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch231">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2004, Spring 2003, Spring 2002<br/>
Seminar in methods and use of research in contemporary and historical architectural design theory and criticism. Required for doctoral students in this study area.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research Methods in Architectural Design Theory and Criticism:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="112" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Thirty hours of lecture/seminar per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research Methods in Architectural Design Theory and Criticism:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch233" data-toggle="#cb_arch233">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 233</span> 
<span class="title">Architectures of Globalization: Contested Spaces of Global Culture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch233">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2010, Fall 2009<br/>
This seminar examines the relationship between architecture and the processes associated with globalization. The social and spatial changes connected to the global economic restructuring of the last four decades are explored in relation to distinctive national conditions and their connection to historical forces such as colonization and imperialism. Theoretical arguments about international urban political economy, uneven development, deindustrialization</span><span class="deschide"> and the growth of tourism and service industries, are grounded in specific urban and architectural contexts. Case studies explore issues such as urban entrepreneurialism and the branding of cities and nation-states; heritage practices and the postcolonial politics of place; border cities, and the urbanism of transnational production; cities, terrorism and the global architecture of security; critical regionalism, localism and other responses to debates on place and placelessness. Readings and class discussions examine course themes in a comparative framework and consider their implications for architectural design, education and professional practice.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Architectures of Globalization: Contested Spaces of Global Culture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="236" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> This course is open to all graduate students and upper division undergraduates</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Crysler</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Architectures of Globalization: Contested Spaces of Global Culture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch236" data-toggle="#cb_arch236">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 236</span> 
<span class="title">The Literature of Space</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch236">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2012, Spring 2011, Spring 2010<br/>
The concept of space as it is applied to the fields of architecture, geography, and urbanism can be understood as a barometer of the condition that we call &quot;modernity.&quot; This course explores connections between the larger cultural frameworks of the past century, and the idea of space as it has been perceived, conceived, and lived during this period. Readings include key essays from the disciplines of philosophy, geography, architecture</span><span class="deschide">, landscape, and urbanism, and short works of fiction that illustrate and elucidate the spatial concepts. The readings are grouped according to themes that form the foundation for weekly seminar discussions. Chronological and thematic readings reveal the force of history upon the conceptualization of space, and its contradictions.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Literature of Space:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="635" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Stoner</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Literature of Space:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch237" data-toggle="#cb_arch237">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 237</span> 
<span class="title">Ulterior Speculation: Monographs and Manifestos</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch237">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2013, Spring 2012, Spring 2011<br/>
An examination and analysis of architectural manifestos and monographs from the first half of the 20th century to today. The class analyzes the possibilities and limits of grounding a discourse in practice as well as theory. The seminar complements thesis preparation or can serve as an introduction to critical thinking in architecture.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Ulterior Speculation: Monographs and Manifestos:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="940" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Fernau</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Ulterior Speculation: Monographs and Manifestos:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch238" data-toggle="#cb_arch238">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 238</span> 
<span class="title">The Dialectic of Poetics and Technology</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch238">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2020, Spring 2019, Spring 2017<br/>
This seminar examines the relationship between technology and design philosophy in the work of architects through analysis of individual buildings within the context of the complete oeuvre and an examination of the architect's writings and lectures. The seminar poses questions such as: What is the role of technology in the design philosophy of the architect and how is this theoretical position established in the architect's writings, lectures</span><span class="deschide">, and interviews? A series of lectures explores these questions in relation to the architect and a set of required readings introduces the work of the architect and explores the relationship between technology and design philosophy.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Dialectic of Poetics and Technology:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="623" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Ubbelohde</p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 209A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Dialectic of Poetics and Technology:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch239" data-toggle="#cb_arch239">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 239</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Architecture Design Theory and Criticism</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch239">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2021<br/>
Selected topics in contemporary and historical architectural design theory and criticsm. For current offerings, see departmental website.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Architecture Design Theory and Criticism:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="475" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to four hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Architecture Design Theory and Criticism:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch240" data-toggle="#cb_arch240">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 240</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Study of Energy and Environment</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch240">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Minimizing energy use is a cornerstone of designing and operating sustainable buildings, and attention to energy issues can often lead to greatly improved indoor environmental quality. For designers, using computer-based energy analysis tools are important not only to qualify for sustainability ratings and meet energy codes, but also to develop intuition about what makes buildings perform well. This course will present quantitative and qualitative</span><span class="deschide"> methods for assessing energy performance during design of both residential and commercial buildings. Students will get hands-on experience with state-of-the-art software -- ranging from simple to complex -- to assess the performance of building components and whole-building designs.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Study of Energy and Environment:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="12" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for Architecture 240 after taking Architecture 240A.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of lecture and 3 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One and one-half hours of lecture and three hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Study of Energy and Environment:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch241" data-toggle="#cb_arch241">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 241</span> 
<span class="title">Research Methods in Building Sciences</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch241">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2022, Fall 2020, Fall 2018<br/>
This class provides training in research skills and critical thinking in the field of Architecture, Building Science, Engineering with a focus on energy use, indoor environmental quality, and human well-being. Readings will cover both building science and technology theory and research methods, and classes will be organized around a series of individual and group homework. Topics will include literature review, design of experiments/simulations</span><span class="deschide">, physical measurements, post-occupancy evaluation, statistical analysis, data visualization, and spreading of scientific results.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research Methods in Building Sciences:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="422" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> The class is targeted towards Building Science MS/PhD, MArch, BA in Architecture, and MS/PhD in Engineering students or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Schiavon</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research Methods in Building Sciences:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch242" data-toggle="#cb_arch242">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 242</span> 
<span class="title">Sustainability Colloquium</span> 
<span class="hours">1 or 2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch242">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Presentations on a variety of topics related to sustainability, offering perspectives from leading practitioners: architectural designers, city planners, consultants, engineers, and researchers. Students can enroll for one unit (required attendance plus reading) or two units (with additional assignments.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Sustainability Colloquium:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="921" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours lecture/seminar per unit per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Brager</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Sustainability Colloquium:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch243" data-toggle="#cb_arch243">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 243</span> 
<span class="title">Natural Cooling: Sustainable Design for a Warming Planet</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch243">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Climate-responsive, person-centered design can reduce energy use, create experiential delight and connection to nature, and be more sustainable. This course covers design and operational strategies, low-and high-tech solutions, material choices, dynamic high-performance facades, natural ventilation, and a range of other integrated climate-control strategies most relevant to warm climates. Students will use interactive and experiential exercises</span><span class="deschide">, simulation tools, case studies, design exercises. Depending on the semester offered, students may also use the Building Science Wind Tunnel to test design solutions for natural ventilation.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Natural Cooling: Sustainable Design for a Warming Planet:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="943" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 140">ARCH 140</span> or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 240">240</span> or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Brager, Betti</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Natural Cooling: Sustainable Design for a Warming Planet:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch244" data-toggle="#cb_arch244">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 244</span> 
<span class="title">Mechanical Systems Design for Sustainable Buildings</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch244">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2011, Fall 2010, Fall 2009<br/>
This class will focus on how to design integrated mechanical systems for sustainable buildings. The building sector plays an important role in global warming, and it is critically important to reduce building energy use in order to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Roughly one-third of the primary energy consumed in buildings is used for controlling the indoor environment through Heating, Ventilating and Air Conditioning (HVAC) and lighting systems.</span><span class="deschide"> Achieving net-zero or positive energy or carbon buildings demands the integration of architecture, structure, and building systems to optimize both passive and active systems.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Mechanical Systems Design for Sustainable Buildings:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="128" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Arch 140 or Arch 240 or consent of the instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Schiavon</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Mechanical Systems Design for Sustainable Buildings:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch245" data-toggle="#cb_arch245">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 245</span> 
<span class="title">Daylighting in Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch245">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2017, Spring 2014<br/>
Daylighting is a cornerstone of architecture design, a fundamental aspect of space making. The course focuses on design approaches to natural light, resorting to the study of precedents in modern and contemporary architecture, daylighting vocabularies and grammars, rules of thumb, field measurements, quantitative studies and computer simulations. Other topics include health and comfort, energy conservation, metrics and standards. Weekly sessions</span><span class="deschide"> comprise both lectures and labs. Final projects are developed in groups and use both qualitative and quantitative methods to assess design solutions.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Daylighting in Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="61" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Caldas</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Daylighting in Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch246" data-toggle="#cb_arch246">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 246</span> 
<span class="title">Building Energy Simulations</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch246">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2021<br/>
Energy saving in buildings is among the most cost-effective and environmentally sustainable measures to reduce greenhouse gasses emissions and energy consumption. 40% of the primary energy use and 75% of total U.S. electricity consumption is used in buildings. Computer-based energy analysis tools are important for architects, building designers, engineers, and sustainability consultants to use for evidence-based design, sustainability ratings, energy code</span><span class="deschide"> compliance, building control and optimization, policy development, and assessment.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Building Energy Simulations:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="271" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> Develop a fundamental and practical knowledge about building performance and energy simulations. <br/>Specify, design, run, analyze, compare and assess building energy simulations.</p><p><strong>Student Learning Outcomes:</strong> Energy modeling by performing guided energy simulations and apply them to a project.<br/>
Flexibility to select a building that you like, for example, it could be a school, a house, a commercial building.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Arch 140 or Arch 240 or consent of the instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Schiavon</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Building Energy Simulations:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch249" data-toggle="#cb_arch249">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 249</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in the Physical Environment in Buildings</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch249">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/></span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in the Physical Environment in Buildings:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="620" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 140</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours lecture/seminar per unit per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in the Physical Environment in Buildings:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch250" data-toggle="#cb_arch250">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 250</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Structures</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch250">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This class focuses on the fundamental principles that affect the structural behavior of buildings. Through digital and hands-on exercises, students will learn analytical techniques for measuring and evaluating the flow of forces through structural systems. Students will also learn to consider the structural behavior of buildings as a fundamental factor in the design of architectural proposals. The goal of the class is to gain a fundamental</span><span class="deschide"> understanding of the forces, moments, and stresses in typical building elements such as columns, beams,<br/>
frames and walls and to make better informed decisions when designing resource- and environmentally-friendly buildings with lightweight and material-efficient structural systems.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Structures:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="199" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 250">ARCH 250</span> after completing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 250">ARCH 250</span>. A deficient grade in <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 250">ARCH 250</span> may be removed by taking <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 250">ARCH 250</span>.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of lecture and 1.5 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One and one-half hours of lecture and one and one-half hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Structures:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch252" data-toggle="#cb_arch252">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 252</span> 
<span class="title">Form and Structure</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch252">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
The class investigates the interplay between geometry and structural behavior of different structural systems categorized with respect to their load-bearing mechanism. Special focus is placed on form-active and surface-active structures like cable nets, membranes, gridshells, and continuous shells. The class will begin by providing a holistic overview of ancient and cutting-edge form-finding approaches and analysis methods. Using playful physical</span><span class="deschide"> experiments, students will gain a hands-on understanding of how different structural states can affect the shape of a structure and how this interrelation could be used creatively to drive the design process.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Form and Structure:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="911" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor required</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Form and Structure:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch253" data-toggle="#cb_arch253">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 253</span> 
<span class="title">Seismic Design and Construction</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch253">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2012, Summer 2012 10 Week Session, Fall 2011<br/>
Contemporary design and construction techniques for improving the performance of new and existing buildings in earthquakes. Topics will include 1) basic principles of seismic design and building performance, 2) retrofit of existing buildings and evaluation techniques, 3) design and planning for disaster recovery and rebuilding. The course will use Bay Area and campus buildings as case studies.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Seismic Design and Construction:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="993" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 150</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture/seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Comerio</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Seismic Design and Construction:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch255" data-toggle="#cb_arch255">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 255</span> 
<span class="title">Structure, Construction, and Space</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch255">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
In profound buildings, the structural system, construction materials, and architectural form work together to create an integrated work of art. Current practice segregates these three areas by assigning separate and rigid roles to 1) an engineer, 2) a contractor, and 3) an architect. The goal of this class is to blur these traditional boundaries and erase the intellectual cleft through hands-on experience. Students are given weekly assignments which focus on one</span><span class="deschide"> or more of the three areas. They may be asked to analyze a structure, to construct something from actual materials or research a case study and present it to the class. Each assignment is geared to help students integrate construction and structural issues into their architectural design so that they can maintain control of the entire design process.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Structure, Construction, and Space:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="536" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 150</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture/seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Black</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Structure, Construction, and Space:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch256" data-toggle="#cb_arch256">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 256</span> 
<span class="title">Structural Design in the Studio</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch256">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2016, Fall 2015, Fall 2013<br/>
Teaching structures to architecture students on their own turf: in a design studio. The course is organized around weekly desk reviews and assignments for students enrolled in a 201 design studio or thesis. The reviews and assignments focus on the structural issues of the students' projects. A central goal of the course is to help students understand structural issues as they relate to design and to help them become comfortable with structural</span><span class="deschide"> concepts so that they can begin to integrate the structure and architecture. The course can be taken for 1 unit, 2 units, or 3 units depending on the amount of time a student wishes to commit to it. A final report showing the evolution of each student's project with clear reference to how structural understanding influenced design decisions is required of all students regardless of units taken. Enrollment strictly limited to 10 students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Structural Design in the Studio:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="681" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 150 or equivalent</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Black</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Structural Design in the Studio:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch258" data-toggle="#cb_arch258">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 258</span> 
<span class="title">Robotic Fabrication and Construction</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch258">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022<br/>
The emergence of robotics in creative sectors such as architecture and design has sparked an entirely new movement of collective making that is inextricably open and future-oriented. Challenged by increasingly complex technological and environmental problems, architects, designers, and engineers are seeking novel practices of collaboration that go far beyond traditional disciplinary boundaries.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Robotic Fabrication and Construction:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="509" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of the instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 1 hour of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of lecture and one hour of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Schleicher</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Robotic Fabrication and Construction:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch259" data-toggle="#cb_arch259">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 259</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Building Structures</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch259">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Selected topics in building structures such as experimental structures and architectural preservation. For current offerings, see departmental website.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Building Structures:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="700" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture per unit per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Building Structures:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch259x" data-toggle="#cb_arch259x">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 259X</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics: Building Structures</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch259x">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2009, Fall 2008, Spring 2008<br/>
Special topics such as experimental structures and architectural preservation.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics: Building Structures:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="546" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Four hour of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics: Building Structures:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch260" data-toggle="#cb_arch260">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 260</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Construction, Graduate Level</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch260">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course addresses the methods and materials of construction. While students will not be experts at the end of the semester, the course should give students the confidence to feel comfortable on a construction site or when designing a small building for a studio. The course will focus on four major territories: structural materials, building envelope, built elements such as stairs and cabinets, and costs, labor conditions, conventional practices</span><span class="deschide">, and the regulatory environments that control design.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Construction, Graduate Level:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="995" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Buntrock</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Construction, Graduate Level:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch262" data-toggle="#cb_arch262">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 262</span> 
<span class="title">Architecture in Detail</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch262">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2019, Fall 2018, Fall 2017<br/>
This seminar will reevaluate the material nature of buildings by studying and understanding construction details and the new technologies that are revolutionizing design construction and labor relations in architecture.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Architecture in Detail:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="354" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Davids</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Architecture in Detail:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch264" data-toggle="#cb_arch264">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 264</span> 
<span class="title">Off-Site Fabrication: Opportunities and Evils</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch264">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2021, Spring 2020, Fall 2017<br/>
This seminar looks at the implications of off-site fabrication in architecture: consistent, protected environments; worker efficiency and safety; coordination of trades; cheaper, semi-skilled labor; construction periods shortened; and completion dates more predictable. Off-site fabrication can allow for increased refinement and trial assemblies. However, it may also create monotonous sameness when the processes and results are not considered</span><span class="deschide"> with care.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Off-Site Fabrication: Opportunities and Evils:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="516" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 160, 260 or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Buntrock</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Off-Site Fabrication: Opportunities and Evils:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch265" data-toggle="#cb_arch265">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 265</span> 
<span class="title">Japanese Craft and Construction</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch265">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2011, Spring 2009, Spring 2005<br/>
The class addresses the role craft and construction play in Japanese architecture and applies these lessons to the evaluation of an exemplary recent building having unusual technical features. Buildings are expressions of theoretic and technical intent and a response to cultural and economic forces; Japanese architecture is regarded as particularly innovative. In studying a system where there is an emphasis on collaboration, students also</span><span class="deschide"> see the values of North American systems of architectural production.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Japanese Craft and Construction:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="708" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 150, 160, or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Buntrock</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Japanese Craft and Construction:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch269" data-toggle="#cb_arch269">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 269</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Construction and Materials</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch269">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Selected topics in construction and materials. For current offerings, see departmental website.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Construction and Materials:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="682" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture/seminar per unit per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Construction and Materials:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch270" data-toggle="#cb_arch270">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 270</span> 
<span class="title">History of Modern Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch270">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course examines developments in design, theory, graphic representation, construction technology, and interior programming through case studies of individual buildings. Each lecture will delve deeply into one or sometimes two buildings to examine program, spatial organization, critical building details, and the relationship of the case study building with regard to other parallel works and the architect's overall body of work.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>History of Modern Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="363" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Castillo</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>History of Modern Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch271" data-toggle="#cb_arch271">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 271</span> 
<span class="title">Methods in Historical Research and Criticism in Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch271">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2021, Spring 2019, Fall 2014<br/></span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Methods in Historical Research and Criticism in Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="625" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Doctoral candidate or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Sixty hours of lecture/seminar per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Methods in Historical Research and Criticism in Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch273" data-toggle="#cb_arch273">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 273</span> 
<span class="title">Case Studies in Modern Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch273">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2010<br/>
This course examines developments in design, theory, graphic representation, construction technology, and interior programming through case studies of individual buildings. Our survey technique will be highly focused rather than panoptic. Each lecture will delve deeply into one or two buildings to examine program, spatial organization, graphic representation, critical building details, construction technology, and the relationship of the case study building with regard</span><span class="deschide"> to other contemporary structures and the &quot;architect's overall body of work&quot;. From this nucleus, we will spiral outward to consider how the case study is embedded within a constellation of social and economic factors crucial to its design and physical realization. This survey of &quot;modernism's built discourses&quot; provides multiple perspectives on the variety of architectural propositions advanced to express the nature of modernity as a way of life.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Case Studies in Modern Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="84" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 170A-170B and consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Case Studies in Modern Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch275" data-toggle="#cb_arch275">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 275</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Architectural Theory 1945 - Present</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch275">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This seminar provides an introduction to architectural theory since 1945, with emphasis on developments over the last three decades. Class readings, and discussions explore the post-World War II crisis within modernism, postmodernism within and beyond architectural culture, and more recent developments around issues such as rapid urbanization, sustainability, the politics of cultural identity and globalization. Transformations in architectural theory are examined</span><span class="deschide"> in relation to historical forces such as the economy, the growth and transformation of cities, and the changing relationship between design professions and disciplines. The influences of digital media, new materials and production techniques on architectural education and practice are explored and the implications for architectural theory assessed. Key issues are anchored in case studies of buildings, urban spaces, and the institutions and agents or architectural culture.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Architectural Theory 1945 - Present:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="69" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> The course is open to upper division undergraduates and graduate students</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Crysler</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Architectural Theory 1945 - Present:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch276" data-toggle="#cb_arch276">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 276</span> 
<span class="title">Spaces of Recreation and Leisure, 1850-2000</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch276">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2014, Spring 2012, Spring 2010<br/>
A reading and research seminar surveying the building types, social relations, and cultural ideas of recreation in the American city, including the tensions between home, public, and commerical leisure settings.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Spaces of Recreation and Leisure, 1850-2000:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="370" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Groth</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Spaces of Recreation and Leisure, 1850-2000:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch277" data-toggle="#cb_arch277">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 277</span> 
<span class="title">California Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch277">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2021, Fall 2019<br/>
Many California architects came from other places: Maybeck from New York via the Ecole des Beaux Arts; Schindler and Neutra from Vienna; Frank Gehry from Chicago. But, once they arrived, their encounters with the Golden State produced new and original forms of architecture. This seminar will examine the qualities of the state’s environment, culture, economy, and population that have produced unique buildings and landscapes during the 20th century. It will</span><span class="deschide"> look at both Northern and Southern California architecture, starting with canonical designers then moving beyond them to consider lesser-known regional architects whose work embodies local characteristics.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>California Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="425" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> A previous architectural history class</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> There will be periodic in-class field trips.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Crawford</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>California Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch278" data-toggle="#cb_arch278">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 278</span> 
<span class="title">Visionary Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch278">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This course explores architectural visions as historical windows, examining them from a number of angles. Using a variety of cases studies drawn from different media (architectural theory, film, advertisements, architectural projects, and so on) and periods (turn of the century, the Modern Movement, Depression, World War II, 1860's, etc.) It provides a sampling of possibilities and models for the final student project, an in-depth, original research paper. Several</span><span class="deschide"> themes thread their way through the course, including the role of the &quot;unbuilt&quot; in architectural history and architectural practice; the uses of the future in the construction of national and personal identities, cultural narratives, and modern mythologies; the importance of the future as cliche, and the role of play in cultural production.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Visionary Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="781" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 170A-170B and cosent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Shanken</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Visionary Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch279" data-toggle="#cb_arch279">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 279</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in the History of Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch279">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Selected topics in the history of architecture. For current offerings, see department website.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in the History of Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="944" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture/seminar per unit per semester.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in the History of Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch281" data-toggle="#cb_arch281">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 281</span> 
<span class="title">Methods of Inquiry in Architectural Research</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch281">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2021, Fall 2019<br/>
This is the introductory course in methods of inquiry in architecture research to be required of all entering Ph.D. students in all areas of the program. The purpose is to train students in predissertation and prethesis research strategies, expose them to variety of inquiry methods including the value of scholarly research, the nature of evidence, critical reading as content analysis and writing, presenting and illustrating scholarship in the various</span><span class="deschide"> disciplines of architecture.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Methods of Inquiry in Architectural Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="340" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> M.S. or Ph.D. standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four hours of lecture/discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Methods of Inquiry in Architectural Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch290" data-toggle="#cb_arch290">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 290</span> 
<span class="title">Dissertation Writing Seminar in Architectural History, Theory, and Society</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch290">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
Post-candidacy research and writing seminar focused on dissertation completion.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Dissertation Writing Seminar in Architectural History, Theory, and Society:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="635" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advancement to candidacy or instructor permission</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with advisor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Dissertation Writing Seminar in Architectural History, Theory, and Society:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch298" data-toggle="#cb_arch298">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 298</span> 
<span class="title">Special Group Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch298">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Spring 2018, Fall 2016<br/>
Special group studies on topics to be introduced by instructor or students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Group Study:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="450" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> May be repeated for credit up to unit limitation.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit up to a total of 4 units.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 8-32 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of work per week per unit for eight weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> The grading option will be decided by the instructor when the class is offered. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Group Study:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch299" data-toggle="#cb_arch299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study and Research for Master's and Doctoral Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2021 8 Week Session, Summer 2018 8 Week Session, Fall 2015<br/>
Individual studies including reading and individual research under the supervision of a faculty adviser and designed to reinforce the student's background in areas related to the proposed degree.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study and Research for Master's and Doctoral Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="743" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of work per week per unit for eight weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study and Research for Master's and Doctoral Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch375" data-toggle="#cb_arch375">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 375</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in the Teaching of Architecture</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch375">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This class is intended for first-time graduate student instructors, especially those working in studio and lab settings. The class covers a range of issues that normally come up when teaching, offers suggestions regarding how to work well with other graduate student instructors and faculty, and how to manage a graduate student instructor's role as both student and teacher. The greatest benefit of this class comes from the opportunity to explore</span><span class="deschide"> important topics together. Using a relatively light, but provocative set of readings, the seminar will explore the issues raised each week. There will be one assignment intended to help students explore their own expectations as educators.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Seminar in the Teaching of Architecture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="392" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Architecture 300</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Seminar in the Teaching of Architecture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_arch602" data-toggle="#cb_arch602">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ARCH 602</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_arch602">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2015, Fall 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required of candidates for the Ph.D. This course may not be used for units or residence requirements for the doctoral degree.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study for Doctoral Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="939" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2-8 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of work per unit per week for eight weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Architecture/Graduate examination preparation</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study for Doctoral Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Mark S. Anderson, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture, building design, BIM, integrated project delivery, building construction, school design, housing design, net zero energy desig, nurban design, building integrated modeling, IPD, design-build, prefabricated, modular, architecture in China, architecture in Japan, urban water.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14381"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>William Andrew Atwood, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Techniques of representation as historical and conceptual instruments.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/andrew-atwood"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Giovanni Betti, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture, architectural design, performance-based design, next-generation building systems; self-regulated facades; biologically inspired technologies; multifunctional materials, sustainable built environments, design-based research.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/giovanni-betti"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gail S. Brager, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture, comfort and adaptation in buildings, design and performance of offices.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14463"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dana Buntrock, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture, construction industry, East Asian studies, architectural practice in Japan.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14602"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Luisa Caldas, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Virtual and augmented reality for building design and simulation, net zero energy and sustainable design, parametric and generative design systems for sustainable architecture, daylighting, daylighting in buildings, housing solutions for the developing world and refugee camps.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/luisa-caldas"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher L. Calott, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Urban Design, Infill Housing, Mixed-use Infill Development, Urban Landscape Infrastructure, Participatory Design and Community Planning, Affordable and Informal Housing, US-Mexico Border Urbanism, Native American Planning and Development, Latin American Urban Development, International Development .<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/chris-calott"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Greg Castillo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architectural history, design discourses and practices, aesthetic theory, counterculture, modernism, interwar and postwar America and Europe, Cold War, Germany, America.<br/><a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/faculty-staff/greg-castillo"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>VISHAAN CHAKRABARTI, <i>WILLIAM W. WURSTER DEAN</i>. </strong>Architecture, urbanism.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/vishaan-chakrabarti"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Raveevarn Choksombatchai, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture, landscape design, space design, media and its effect upon design through filmic techniques and video investigations.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/raveevarn-choksombatchai"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Renee Y. Chow, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Urban design, architectural design.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14517"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Margaret L. Crawford, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>History of architecture, architecture and urban design, urban history and theory, US built environment studies, urbanism in China.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/margaret-crawford"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>C. Greig Crysler, <i>Professor and Associate Dean for Undergraduate Studies, CED</i>. </strong>Architecture, geopolitics of architectural discourse, globalization and social production of the built environment, architecture and identity.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14493"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rene Davids, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture and urban design and theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14142"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maria Paz Gutierrez, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Next-generation building systems, self-regulated facades, biologically inspired technologies, multifunctional materials.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14763"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lisa M. Iwamoto, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture, design, materials research and fabrication.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14882"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>MARCEL SANCHEZ PRIETO, <i>ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR</i>. </strong><br/><a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/faculty-staff/visitor-temp-1580242668"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ronald L. Rael, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>3D printed buildings, additive manufacturing, earth architecture, mud, dirt, dust, U S -Mexico border wall, arid landscapes, ranching, acequias, alipne deserts, ceramics, rural architecture, ruralism, animation, digital modeling, furry buildings, unnatural materials, rasquachetecture.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15255"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stefano Schiavon, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Energy, architecture, thermal comfort, indoor air quality, building energy efficiency, indoor environment quality, productivity, wellbeing, sustainable building design, simulation and verification, personal environmental control system, energy simulation, underfloor air distribution, radiant, post-occupancy evaluation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15420"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Simon Schleicher, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biomimetics, structural engineering, architectural design, 3D printing, 3D scanning, digital fabrication, fabrication, composite structures, finite element analysis, parametric design, bio-inspired structures, robotics manufacturing.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/simon-schleicher"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andrew Shanken, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Memory, visionary architecture, the unbuilt, paper architecture, heritage conservation, architectural representation, urban representation, diagrams, history of professions, historiography, world's fairs, expositions, California architecture, themed environments.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15666"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kyle Steinfeld, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Digital design, design computation, data visualization, architectural representation, design methods.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16281"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Roddy Creedon, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>William W. Di Napoli, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Darell W. Fields, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rudabeh Pakravan, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Keith Plymale, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong>Architectural Design, Construction and Material Technology, Earthwork Art as Architecture, Native American Architecture, Concrete Structures, Italian Modernism and Brutalism.<br/><a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/faculty-staff/keith-plymale"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles Salter, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher W. J. Alexander, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Nezar Alsayyad, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Virtual reality, urban history, Architectural history, Middle Eastern Studies, cross-cultural design, cities and cinema, cultural studies of the built environment, environmental design in developing countries, housing and urban development, Islamic architecture and urbanism, traditional dwelling and settlements, urban design and physical planning.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14244"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Edward A. Arens, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Indoor environment, thermal comfort, occupant surveys, building environmental control, ventilation, wind, architectural aerodynamics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15003"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard Bender, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles C. Benton, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, thermal comfort, sunlight and shadow patterns, measurement of physical building performance.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14429"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>R. Gary Black, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, finite element modeling, finite element analysis, structure and space, experimental testing, timber connections, teaching structures, integrating structure and architecture.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14446"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter C. Bosselmann, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Urban design, architecture, city and regional planning, landscape architecture.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14460"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jean-Paul Bourdier, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gary R. Brown, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Tom Buresh, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong><br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/tom-j-buresh"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary C. Comerio, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Disaster recovery, housing impacts in disasters, loss modeling, performance based design.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14506"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Clare Cooper Marcus, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, landscape architecture, environmental planning, medium-density housing, public housing modernization, public open-space design, children's environments, housing for the elderly.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15331"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Galen Cranz, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, sociology of space, urban parks, Alexander Technique, chairs, ergonomics, somatics, body conscious design, social research methods for architecture and urban design, ethnography, programming, post occupancy evaluation and assessment, sociology of taste, housing for the elderly.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14496"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Sam Davis, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Margaret Or Penny Dhaemers, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, electronic imaging, 2D and 3D.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14543"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anthony Dubovsky, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>William R. Ellis, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Sociology, social issues in architecture and urban design.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15023"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Norma D. Evenson, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard E. Fernau, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Harrison Fraker, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Urban design, architecture, environmental design, passive solar, daylighting, sustainable design, sustainable systems, urban design principles, transit oriented neighborhoods.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14681"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sara Ishikawa, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Yehuda E. Kalay, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Virtual reality, new media, computer-aided design, design methods, colaborative design.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14906"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lars G. Lerup, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Raymond Lifchez, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Donlyn Lyndon, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, structure of place, ethical dimensions of design.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14135"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>W. Mike Martin, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stanley Saitowitz, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, architecture and cooking, urbanism and computers.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15302"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maryly A. Snow, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Solomon, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Claude Stoller, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jill H. Stoner, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, architecture as fiction, derivation of spatial words, Jewish ghettos in Italy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15503"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stephen Tobriner, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* E. Marc Treib, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Architecture, East Asian studies, Japanese architecture and gardens.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15691"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>M. Susan Ubbelohde, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>India, architecture, climate and architecture, Le Corbusier, Kahn, Correa, Doshi, culture and practice, daylighting design tools, software evaluation, sky simulator design, low-energy design, California residential industry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15561"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sim H. Van Der Ryn, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

