<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Biophysics</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Biophysics Graduate Group is an interdisciplinary PhD program hosted by the California Institute for the Biosciences (QB3). Our program trains graduate students for careers at the interface of the biological and physical sciences. This interdisciplinary group provides an opportunity for interested students to receive training leading to the PhD in Biophysics. Approximately 60 faculty members are affiliated with the Biophysics Group, spanning over a dozen departments and groups at UC Berkeley. Students may work under the supervision of any faculty member belonging to the group.</p>
<p>Students interested in pursuing graduate work in biophysics typically acquire undergraduate training in one of the basic physical or biological sciences and during the first two years at UC Berkeley take self-selected courses in topics such as biology, physics, and chemistry to fill in any gaps in foundational knowledge.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the Program</h3>
<p>Applicants should have sufficient undergraduate training to undertake graduate work in the chosen field. This includes such undergraduate majors as: biological sciences, structural biology, physics, math, and/or chemistry. Laboratory experience is expected.</p>
<p>Typical students admitted to the program have demonstrated outstanding potential as a research scientist and have clear academic aptitude in multiple disciplines, as well as excellent communication skills. This is assessed based on research experience, grades, standardized exams, course selection, essays, personal background, and letters of recommendation.</p>
<p>GRE general and subject tests are not required, and will not be seen by the review committee even if submitted.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext name="Doctoral Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Normative Time Requirements</h3>
<h4 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Normative Time to Advancement</h4>
<p>Normative time to advancement is two years.</p>
<h6><strong>Year 1</strong></h6>
<p>Students perform three laboratory rotations with the chief aim of identifying a research area and selecting a thesis laboratory. In their first year, all students must pass two graded STEM courses. Passing is a grade of “B” or higher for graduate students. This requirement can be met by: a) completing a total of 5 units of graduate level coursework (200* and above), or b) completing 6 units of combined graduate and upper-division (100 and above) undergraduate courses.<span> Any exceptions to this policy (ie, completing coursework in 2nd year, using non-STEM course to fulfill requirement) must be approved by the Head Graduate Advisor</span></p>
<h6 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle"><strong>Year 2</strong></h6>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Students attend seminars, prepare a dissertation prospectus, and prepare for their PhD oral qualifying examination (QE). With the successful passing of the QE, students select their thesis committee and advance to candidacy for the PhD degree.</p>
<h4 class="Normal1CxSpLast">Normative Time in Candidacy</h4>
<h6><strong>Years 3 to 5</strong></h6>
<p>Students undertake research for the PhD dissertation under a self-selected four-person committee in charge of their research and dissertation. Students conduct original laboratory research and then write the dissertation based on the results of this research. On completion of the research and approval of the dissertation by the committee, the students are awarded the doctorate.</p>
<h4 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Total Normative Time</h4>
<p>Total normative time is 5-5.5/6 years.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Time to Advancement</h3>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Curriculum</h5>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Courses Required</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="BIOPHY 293A">BIOPHY 293A</span></td><td>Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS)</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="BIOPHY 293B">BIOPHY 293B</span></td><td>Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS)</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MCELLBI 293C">MCELLBI 293C</span></td><td>Responsible Conduct in Research</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h5 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Lab Rotations</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Students conduct three 10-week laboratory rotations in the first year. The thesis lab, where dissertation research will take place, is chosen at the end of the third rotation in late April/early May.</p>
<h5>Qualifying Examination</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">The qualifying examination will evaluate a student’s depth of knowledge in his or her research area, breadth of knowledge in fundamentals of biophysics, ability to formulate a research plan, and critical thinking. The QE prospectus/proposal will include a description of the specific research problem but will serve as a framework for the QE committee members to probe the student’s foundational knowledge in the field and area of research. Proposals will be written in the manner of a NIH-style grant proposal. The prospectus must be completed and submitted to the QE chair no fewer than four weeks prior to the oral qualifying examination.</p>
<p>Students are expected to pass the qualifying examination by the end of the fourth semester in the program.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Time in Candidacy</h3>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Advancement</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">After passing the qualifying exam by the end of the second year, students have until the fifth semester to select a thesis committee and submit the online advancement to candidacy form to the Graduate Division.</p>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Dissertation</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Primary dissertation research is conducted in years 3-5/5.5. Requirements for the dissertation are decided in consultation with the thesis advisor and thesis committee members. To this end, students are required to have yearly thesis committee meetings with the committee after advancing to candidacy.</p>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Dissertation Presentation/Finishing Talk</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">There is no formal defense of the completed dissertation; however, students are expected to publicly present a talk about their dissertation research in their final year.</p>
<hr/>
<h3 class="Normal1">Required Professional Development</h3>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Presentations</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">All biophysics students are expected to attend the annual retreat and present research talks there. They are also encouraged to attend national and international conferences to present research from the second year onwards.</p>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Teaching</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Biophysics students are required to teach one semester and may teach more. The teaching requirement may be waived, in consultation with the Head Grad advisor and Chair, for service to the program (such as creating and teaching a 5-week module, active participation on the DEI Committee).</p>
]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Biophysics</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_biophy292" data-toggle="#cb_biophy292">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">BIOPHY 292</span> 
<span class="title">Research</span> 
<span class="hours">3 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_biophy292">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Summer 2023 10 Week Session, Spring 2023<br/>
Individual research under the supervision of a faculty member.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="464" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 10 weeks - 3-12 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to twelve hours of independent study per week. Three to twelve hours of independent study per week for 10 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Biophysics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_biophy293a" data-toggle="#cb_biophy293a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">BIOPHY 293A</span> 
<span class="title">Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS)</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_biophy293a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Seminar on presentation and evaluation of results in area of student's individual research interests.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS):</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="580" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 292</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Biophysics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. This is part one of a year long series course. A provisional grade of IP (in progress) will be applied and later replaced with the final grade after completing part two of the series. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS):</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_biophy293b" data-toggle="#cb_biophy293b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">BIOPHY 293B</span> 
<span class="title">Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS)</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_biophy293b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Seminar on presentation and evaluation of results in area of student's individual research interests.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS):</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="828" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 293A, and 292</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Biophysics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. This is part two of a year long series course. Upon completion, the final grade will be applied to both parts of the series. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research Seminar: Faculty Evening Research Presentations (FERPS) and Student Evening Research Presentations (SERPS):</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Hillel Adesnik, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Neural basis of perception, neuroscience, neurobiology .<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/NEU/adesnikh.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Adam Arkin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Systems modeling.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/adam-arkin"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Georjana Barnes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biochemistry, genetics, cancer, biology, microtubule cytoskeleton, cell cycle controls, cellular imaging.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14409"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eric Betzig, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Physics, molecular and cell biology.<br/><a href="http://compbio.berkeley.edu/people/brenner/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven Brenner, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational Biology, Genomics, Protein Function Prediction.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14469"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steve Brohawn, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular and cell biology.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/NEU/brohawns"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Carlos J. Bustamante, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Nanoscience, structural characterization of nucleo-protein assemblies, single molecule fluorescence microscopy, DNA-binding molecular motors, the scanning force microscope, prokaryotes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15099"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jamie Cate, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular basis for protein synthesis by the ribosome, RNA, antibiotics, a thermophilic bacterium, escherichia coli.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14485"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kathy Collins, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Telomerase, non-coding RNAs, RNA silencing.<br/><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/kcollinslab/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Xavier Darzacq, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Transcription regulation during cellular differentiation  Linking the biophysical rules of nuclear organization and gene expression control mechanism  .<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/ggd/darzacqx.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Karen Davies, <i>Assistant Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Protein structure, bioenergentic membranes, cellualr organisation, electron cryo tomography.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/BBS/daviesk"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Abby Dernburg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genomics, chromosome remodeling and reorganization during meiosis, Down syndrome, DNA.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/abby-dernburg"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Deweese, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Machine learning, computation, systems neuroscience, auditory cortex, neural coding.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14649"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer A. Doudna, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>RNA machines, hepatitis C virus, RNA interference, ribosomes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14290"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David G. Drubin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cellular morphogenesis, plasma membrane dynamics, microtubule cytoskeletons, cytoskeletal proteins, morphological development.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13884"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael B. Eisen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genomics, genome sequencing, bioinformatics, animal development.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13886"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Dan Feldman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Neurobiology, learning, neurophysiology, sensory biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14661"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Marla B. Feller, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Neurophysiology, developmental neuroscience.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Graham R. Fleming, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Chemistry, proteins, chemical and biological dynamics in the condensed phase, ultrafast spectroscopy, body dynamics, liquids, solutions, glasses, photosynthetic proteins, role of solvents in chemical reactions, complex electric fields, electron transfer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14675"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Fletcher, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Bioengineering, optical and force microscopy, microfabrication, biophysics, mechanical properties of cells.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/daniel-alden-fletcher"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Robert J. Full, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Energetics, comparative biomechanics, arthropod, adhesion, comparative physiology, locomotion, neuromechanics, biomimicry, biological inspiration, reptile, gecko, amphibian, robots, artificial muscles.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/robert-j-full"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jack L. Gallant, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Vision science, form vision, attention, fMRI, computational neuroscience, natural scene perception, brain encoding, brain decoding.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14700"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hernan G. Garcia, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Biophysics.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/GEN/garciah.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Phillip Lewis Geissler, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical mechanics, theoretical chemistry, microscopic behavior of complex biological and material systems, biomolecular structure and dynamics, nonlinear vibrational spectroscopy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14707"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jay T. Groves, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Chemistry, physical chemistry of cell membranes, molecular organization in cell membranes, receptor-ligand binding, spatial rearrangement of receptors, ligands.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14751"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Oskar Hallatschek, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Biophysics, random mutational events, genetic diversity, genome architecture, statistical physics, stochoastic reaction-diffusion systems, .<br/><a href="http://hallatscheklab.berkeley.edu/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Teresa Head-Gordon, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational chemistry, biophysics, bioengineering, biomolecules, materials, computational science.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14816"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Hurley, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Structural biology and biophysics of membrane remodeling in autophagy, membrane traffic, and HIV biogenesis.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/BMB/hurleyj.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nicholas Ingolia, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Ribosome Profiling, translation, genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16282"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ehud Y. Isacoff, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ion channel function, synaptic plasticity, neural excitability, synaptic transmission, the synapse.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13890"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Na Ji, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Physics, molecular and cell biology.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/na-ji"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sung-Hou Kim, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational genomics, Structural Biology, drug discovery, disease genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14921"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mimi A. R. Koehl, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biomechanics, insects, invertebrate functional morphology, fluid dynamics, aerodynamics, marine animals, filtration, gliding vertebrates.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13868"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard H. Kramer, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cells, synaptic transmission, chemical signaling between neurons, ion channels, electrical signals, chemical reagents, synapses.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13894"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sanjay Kumar, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biomaterials, molecular and cellular bioengineering, stem cells, cancer biology, translational medicine.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sanjay-kumar"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Kuriyan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Structural and functional studies of signal transduction, DNA replication, cancer therapies, phosphorylation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13895"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Markita Landry, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Nanomaterials, single-molecule fluorescence microscopy, biophysics.<br/><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/landry"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Polina Lishko, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Reproductive and Developmental Biology, ion channels, Physiology of Fertilization and Early Embryo Development.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16272"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kranthi K. Mandadapu, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical Mechanics, Continuum Mechanics â€” Polycrystalline Materials, Biological Membranes, Bacterial Motility.<br/><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/mandadapu"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael A. Marletta, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical biology, molecular biology, structure/function relationships in proteins, catalytic and biological properties of enzymes, cellular signaling, nitric oxide synthase, soluble guanylate cyclase, gas sensing, cellulose degradation, polysaccharide monooxygenases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15087"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Susan Marqusee, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Amino acids, determinants of protein structure and folding, biophysical, structural and computational techniques, translocation, protein synthesis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13900"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andreas Martin, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Proteasome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16781"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard Mathies, <i>Professor of the Graduate School</i>. </strong>Genomics, biophysical, bioanalytical, physical chemistry, laser spectroscopy, resonance Raman, excited-state reaction dynamics photoactive proteins, rhodopsins, microfabricated chemical biochemical analysis devices, forensics, infectious disease detection.<br/><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/themathieslab/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barbara J. Meyer, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Developmental biology, gene expression, genetic determination of sex, regulatory genes, chromosome dynamics, X-chromosome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15112"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Evan W. Miller, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Biophysical, bioanalytical and physical chemistry.<br/><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/chem/evan-miller"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mohammad Mofrad, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Nuclear pore complex and nucleocytoplasmic transport, mechanobiology of disease, cellular mechanotransduction, integrin-mediated focal adhesions.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15133"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Priya Moorjani, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Human population genetics and evolutionary biology.<br/><a href="https://moorjanilab.org/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eva Nogales, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biochemistry, complex biological assemblies, structure and regulation of the cytoskeleton, microtubule dynamics, human transcriptional initiation machinery, biophysics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13903"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eunyong Park, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Structure and mechanism of membrane transport proteins, cryo-EM, biochemistry, biophysics.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/eunyong-park"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel S. Rokhsar, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biology, collective phenomena and ordering in condensed matter and biological systems, theoretical modeling, computational modeling, behavior of quantum fluids, cold atomic gases, high temperature superconductors, Fermi and Bose systems.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/bbs/parke"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Savage, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Synthetic biology and metabolism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15309"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Karthik Shekhar, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Computational Biology and Genomics, Systems Neuroscience.<br/><a href="http://www.shekharlab.com/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Aaron Streets, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Genomics and evolution of aging and cellular and organismal diversity.<br/><a href="http://bioeng.berkeley.edu/faculty/aaron-streets"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter Sudmant, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Genomics, genetics, computational biology, structural variation, RNA, diversity, aging, population genetics.<br/><a href="https://www.sudmantlab.org/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Frederic Theunissen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Behavior, cognition, brain, psychology, birdsong, vocal learning, audition, neurophysiology, speech perception, computational neuroscience, theoretical neuroscience.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15689"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Denis Titov, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular basis of inactivation of cellular machinery during aging, biochemistry, physiology, mathematical modeling, custom instrumentation, novel tool development.<br/><a href="https://denistitovlab.org/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Evan Williams, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Spectroscopy, molecular structure and dynamics, analytical chemistry, biophysical chemistry, structure and reactivity of biomolecules and biomolecule/water interactions, mass spectrometry, separations, protein conformation, protein and DNA sequencing.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15622"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ke Xu, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Biophysical chemistry, cell biology at the nanoscale, super-resolution microscopy, single-molecule spectroscopy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16316"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Yartsev, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Neurobiology.<br/><a href="https://bioegrad.berkeley.edu/people/michael-yartsev"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ahmet Yildiz, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Single molecule biophysics, molecular motors, telomeres.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16366"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Roberto Zoncu, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong> Biophysics and Structural Biology, MCB.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/bbs/zoncur.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

