<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Film &amp; Media</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">PhD in Film and Media</h3>
<p class="Normal1">Students in the Film and Media PhD are encouraged to situate moving images within the larger theoretical and analytical frameworks of a range of other disciplines. They integrate the traditions of history, law, literature, cultural studies, gender studies, and political theory to the newer disciplines of film studies and digital media, applying the tools of post-structuralism, psychoanalysis, new historicism, media archaeology, Frankfurt School, feminist theory, queer theory, post-colonialism, and critical race theory. Many combine their degree study with a campus designated emphasis (graduate “minor”) in New Media, in Critical Theory, or in Women, Gender and Sexuality.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Designated Emphasis in Film Studies</h3>
<p class="Normal1">PhD students at Berkeley outside the Department of Film &amp; Media may add a Designated Emphasis in Film Studies to their major fields. The designated emphasis provides curricular and research resources for students who want to concentrate on film and media research within their respective disciplines and have their work formally recognized. Designed to bring together faculty and students from different departments, the program provides a unique contliext for rigorous cross-disciplinary thinking and promotes innovative research in the theory and history of cinema and media studies.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the Designated Emphasis Program</h3>
<p class="Normal1">Applicants must be enrolled in a doctoral program at Berkeley and must have completed either FILM 201, offered each fall semester, or <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 200">FILM 200</span></span>, taught every spring.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext name="Doctoral Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h4 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Curriculum</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 200">FILM 200</span></td><td>Graduate Film Theory Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 201">FILM 201</span></td><td>Graduate Film Historiography</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 203">FILM 203</span></td><td>Film Studies Proseminar</td><td class="hourscol">2-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Film Electives: Graduate seminars (4 courses)</span></td><td class="hourscol">16</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Outside Field Electives (2 courses)  </span></td><td class="hourscol">8</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<designatedemphasisrequirementstext name="Designated Emphasis Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Coursework/Curriculum</h3>
<p>A minimum of three graduate seminars in Film Studies must be taken at Berkeley. Independent study courses are not acceptable to fulfill this requirement.</p>
<h6>Required courses</h6>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 200">FILM 200</span></td><td>Graduate Film Theory Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 201">FILM 201</span></td><td>Graduate Film Historiography</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 240">FILM 240</span></td><td>Graduate Topics in Film (or a graduate seminar cross-listed with Film and Media)</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3 class="Normal1">Qualifying Examination (QE)</h3>
<p class="Normal1">A member of the Graduate Group in Film Studies must be a formal member of the PhD qualifying examination committee. If applicable, the Film Studies Graduate Group member in the student’s home department will serve in this function. A member of the Graduate Group may also serve as the outside member of the qualifying exam committee. A Film Studies topic must be included as a subject on the qualifying examination.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Dissertation</h3>
<p>A member of the Graduate Group in Film Studies must be a formal member of the dissertation committee. The dissertation must contribute to the study of film and moving-image media.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Degree Conferral</h3>
<p class="Normal1">Upon completion of these requirements and the dissertation, the student will receive a designation on their transcript to state that they have completed a “PhD in [major] with an Emphasis in Film Studies.”</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Film and Media</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film200" data-toggle="#cb_film200">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 200</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Film Theory Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film200">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This seminar will examine both traditional and recent critical approaches to a systematic and historical study of film. Although we will emphasize contemporary structuralist-semiotic, psychoanalytical, and socio-critical methods, we will also study the classical debates in film theory about representation, filmic vs. literary signification, sexual difference, and the social function of images in modernism and postmodernism. Illustrations</span><span class="deschide"> will be taken from film history from 1910 to 1980.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Film Theory Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="858" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Film Theory Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film201" data-toggle="#cb_film201">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 201</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Film Historiography</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film201">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
The theoretical and methodological issues raised by the recent practice of film history are the focus of this seminar. Intended primarily for first-year film studies graduate students and other students interested in starting work on film history, the seminar provides both a theoretical overview of film historiography and an introduction to the practice of historically oriented film research. The first part of the course uses both overtly historiographic</span><span class="deschide"> readings and film history examples to raise historical questions of technology, institution-formation, exhibition, cultural history, and spectatorship.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Film Historiography:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="933" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Film Historiography:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film203" data-toggle="#cb_film203">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 203</span> 
<span class="title">Film Studies Proseminar</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film203">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
A seminar introducing Film Studies graduate students to the field, the profession, and the faculty practicing film studies. Envisioned as a way for new students to learn what is expected of them and for more advanced students to pass through the all-important last years of their training in an atmosphere of helpful camaraderie. Introduces students to the intellectual and physical resources of the Berkeley campus as well as the Bay Area. By the</span><span class="deschide"> end of the semester students should gain an understanding of the expectations of their performance in graduate school, have identified the major goals on the way towards getting a Ph.D., and, depending on where they are in their studies, have begun to achieve those goals.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Film Studies Proseminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="3" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Film Studies Proseminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film204" data-toggle="#cb_film204">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 204</span> 
<span class="title">Compact Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film204">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2010<br/>
A compact seminar features a distinguished, short-term visitor with expertise in Film and Media. During the stay, the visitor meets intensively with graduate students, who then continue to work on research topics for the remainder of the semester. The seminar meets eight times one hundred and twenty minutes, not including screening time, and a substantial (twenty-five page) research paper is required at the end of the semester.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Compact Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="996" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 4 weeks - 4 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four hours of seminar (meeting two times per week).</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Compact Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film220" data-toggle="#cb_film220">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 220</span> 
<span class="title">Film Curating</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film220">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2021, Spring 2011, Fall 2006<br/>
An introduction to the theory, history, and practice of film curating taught by Pacific Film Archive curators. What do curators do? How do they decide what to show? What is the role of film archives and film exhibition in the field of film and moving image study? Using the Pacific Film Archive and its programmers as a laboratory, students will go behind-the-scenes of the Archive's curatorial, print traffic, publicity, and editorial departments</span><span class="deschide"> and learn how to program by doing. The course will culminate in a proposal for a comprehensive film series.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Film Curating:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="693" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar and 1-4 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar and One to Four hour of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Film Curating:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film221" data-toggle="#cb_film221">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 221</span> 
<span class="title">Film Curating Part 2</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film221">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2007<br/>
Students will develop and present a film series for presentation at the Pacific Film Archive. Possibly refining a series proposed in 220. PFA curators will have final approval of the series topic and the film/video selection. Students will locate and book all films, write program notes, do outreach, and introduce programs. Guest speakers will include local press, writers, and artists. Local film and videomakers will trace the history of a work from production through</span><span class="deschide"> exhibition.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Film Curating Part 2:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="352" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 220</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Film Curating Part 2:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film230" data-toggle="#cb_film230">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 230</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Production Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film230">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2013, Spring 2013, Spring 2012<br/>
Intensive study of the basic elements of film and digital video production and post-production. Graduate students will develop a working knowledge of film and video making through hands-on production experience that will enable them to film and edit their own productions. They will also acquire training to teach basic video and film production classes. The uses of specific technologies and formats will be discussed in relation to aesthetic</span><span class="deschide"> and theoretical questions. Training includes pre-production-scripting and storyboarding, production elements including image capture, and post-production strategies and aesthetics for non-linear digital editing programs. The course will also introduce problems of how to format video/films for exhibition and approaches to distribution, exhibition, and funding. Classes will consist of technical lectures and hands-on workshops, creative exercises, seminar-style discussion and critique, film screenings, assigned readings, and visiting artists and speakers.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Production Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="663" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 3-5 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Lecture and Three to Five hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Production Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film240" data-toggle="#cb_film240">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 240</span> 
<span class="title">Graduate Topics in Film</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film240">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Selected topics in the study of film.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Graduate Topics in Film:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="635" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Graduate Topics in Film:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film297" data-toggle="#cb_film297">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 297</span> 
<span class="title">Dissertation Writing Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film297">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Students having completed doctoral qualifying examinations and now working on a dissertation or prospectus will undertake a structured process leading to the completion of a finished piece of work, in most cases a dissertation chapter. Each week, students will discuss one or more works in progress, and will have an opportunity both to learn from other students’ process and research, and to receive feedback from a diverse group on your own writing. Alongside the</span><span class="deschide"> work of participants, students will read relevant theoretical texts and discuss research methods, questions of genre, tools for moving through blocks, and avenues for publication.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Dissertation Writing Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="364" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Students must have successfully completed their doctoral qualifying examinations and advanced to candidacy</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Dissertation Writing Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film298" data-toggle="#cb_film298">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 298</span> 
<span class="title">Special Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film298">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2022 First 6 Week Session, Fall 2021, Fall 2017<br/>
Designed to allow students to do research in areas not covered by other courses. Requires regular discussions with the instructor and a final written report.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Study:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="600" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor. Graduate standing</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>3 weeks - 5-20 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 2.5-10 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 2-7.5 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>10 weeks - 1.5-6 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Individual conferences. Individual conferences.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Study:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film299" data-toggle="#cb_film299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 299</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2021, Summer 2021, Fall 2020<br/>
Open to graduate students who have passed their Ph.D. qualifying examinations.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Directed Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="645" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Twelve hour of Independent study per week for 15 weeks. One and one-half to Twenty-two and one-half hours of Independent study per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Directed Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film375" data-toggle="#cb_film375">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 375</span> 
<span class="title">Teaching Reading and Composition through Film &amp; Media</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film375">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course serves as introductory training for first-time R&amp;C GSIs who are interested in incorporating moving-image materials and instructional strategies into their teaching repertoire.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Teaching Reading and Composition through Film &amp; Media:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="983" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> This course exposes students to current research on teaching student writing, encourages discussion of strategies and practices for R&amp;C courses using both readings and moving-image media in the instructional content, and creates a structured space for current GSIs to workshop and troubleshoot issues from teaching in progress during the semester’s instruction.</p><p><strong>Student Learning Outcomes:</strong> 2. be able to create and evaluate the effectiveness of lesson plans and assignments that employ active learning strategies (e.g., discussion, collaborative problem solving, applied practice) in the study of moving-image media materials;<br/>
3. know the standards of ethical conduct by which they and their students must abide and how to provide a welcoming and respectful learning environment for a diverse student body;<br/>
4. know general and field-specific University policies and resources for teaching film and media composition courses on the Berkeley campus, such as those pertaining to students with disabilities, students in distress, student athletes, sexual harassment, academic integrity, and instructional technology;<br/>
5. know how to assess student learning and grade student work fairly, consistently, and efficiently, with special attention to the structural and cultural differences in preparation that present barriers to learning effective writing;<br/>
6. be able to use feedback and assessment tools such as mid-semester evaluations to improve teaching;<br/>
7. be able to reflect upon teaching and learning and explain why they make the choices they do as teachers in their field;<br/>
8. know how to effectively communicate and collaborate with members of a teaching team (e.g., faculty instructor, head GSI, co-instructors, fellow GSIs, Readers, course support staff).<br/>
Upon completion of the course, GSIs should:<br/>
1. know effective practices, current directions, and resources for engaging students in writing about film and media;</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Current or upcoming first-time appointment as GSI</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Teaching Reading and Composition through Film &amp; Media:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_film602" data-toggle="#cb_film602">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">FILM 602</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 6 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_film602">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2019, Spring 2019, Fall 2018<br/>
Individual study in consultation with faculty director as preparation for degree examinations.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study for Doctoral Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="452" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-6 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-11 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Six hour of Independent study per week for 15 weeks. One and one-half to Eleven hours of Independent study per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Film and Media/Graduate examination preparation</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study for Doctoral Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Weihong Bao, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Film theory and history, media archaeology, critical theory, visual and performance culture, Chinese language cinema, transnational genre cinema, comparative media history and theory.<br/><a href="http://ealc.berkeley.edu/people/bao-weihong"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rizvana Bradley, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Film theory, critical theory, aesthetics of postcoloniality and the black diaspora, gender and sexuality studies, contemporary art, art history and visual culture.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Natalia Brizuela, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Photography, film, contemporary art, critical theory and aesthetics of Spanish America and Brazil .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14471"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary Ann Doane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, semiotics, cinema, media, cultural theory, archaeology of media technology, poststructuralism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14326"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jacob Gaboury, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Digital media, visual culture, media archaeology, queer theory,  20th century histories of technology and computation, computer graphics, and the intersection of contemporary art and technology .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anton Kaes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Film studies, modern literature, literary and cultural theory, cinema, interdisciplinary and comparative aspects of Weimar culture, contemporary literature and film, literary theory, theory of cultural studies, film history, film theory, history of cinema.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14903"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anne Nesbet, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Culture, film studies, Slavic languages, early Soviet culture, Sergei Eisenstein, silent film, Soviet film, GDR history, children's literature and Stalinism, the Soviet Union, American minority movements.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15172"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>NicolÃ¡s Pereda, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Film production, hybrid cinema, alternative fictions, slow cinema.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mark Sandberg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Silent film, late nineteenth-century visual culture, theater history, comedy, Scandinavian design, serial television, film historiography, Scandinavian film history, Henrik Ibsen, Norwegian literature, Nordic literary history.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14283"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Miryam Sas, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Comparative literature, 20th century avant-gardes, Japanese literature, film, theater and dance, contemporary art, critical theory, gender theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15410"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jeffrey A. Skoller, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Film history, theory and practice of documentary, avant-garde film, film as art, activist media, Third Cinema , film/video production.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15455"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kristen Whissel, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cinema and technological change, computer-generated images and contemporary cinema, digital visual effects, the history and theory of special effects, cinema in transition, American film history, silent American cinema, modernity and early cinema .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14322"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Damon R. Young, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Digital media, global art cinema (with a focus on French and francophone), gender and sexuality studies, critical theory.</p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Emily Carpenter, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>J. Mira Kopell, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

