<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Film &amp; Media</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Bachelor of Arts (BA)</h3>
<p>Berkeley offers an interdisciplinary undergraduate program leading to a Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Film &amp; Media. The program offers rigorous engagement with the entire culture of moving-images, teaching students to think historically, theoretically, and analytically about a wide range of cinematic forms. At the same time, it encourages students to look at moving images from the vantage point of other disciplines. To this end, the Department of Film &amp; Media cooperates with a number of other departments and programs on campus. Students earning their BA in Film &amp; Media may also choose to complement their study of the history and theory of moving images with the hands-on experience provided by production and screenwriting classes.</p>
<h3>Declaring the Major</h3>
<p>To declare a major in Film &amp; Media, students must have completed a minimum of 30 units, and have satisfactorily completed <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 10">FILM 10</span></span> or <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 20">FILM 20</span></span>. For further information regarding prerequisites, please see the Major Requirements tab on this page.</p>
<h3>Honors Program</h3>
<p>To be eligible for admission to the honors program in Film &amp; Media, a student must have attained senior standing with a grade point average (GPA) of 3.3 or higher on all University work and a 3.5 GPA or higher in courses in the major.  Students in the honors program are to take <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM H195">FILM H195</span></span> for a letter grade to complete a senior honors thesis. Although the production of a film may be part of the preparation of the thesis — and the film may be submitted as a documentation, or example — it is expected that the thesis will be a substantial piece of writing on film and media theory, criticism, or history.</p>
<h3>Minor Program</h3>
<p>There is no minor program in Film &amp; Media.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<majorrequirementstext name="Major Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p><strong>*Beginning Fall 2020, the Film &amp; Media program will be rolling out a new curriculum. The new curriculum expands the department's production-based course offerings, gives more consideration to emerging and alternative media, expands the scope of required courses into related media fields, and provides more flexibility in pathways through the major. </strong></p>
<p><strong>The major structural changes include removing the foreign language requirement and replacing it with an elective requirement that creates a total of five elective requirements instead of the previous four.</strong></p>
<p><strong>While many courses under the new curriculum have been adapted from existing courses, the course numbering system has been completely revamped as well, making course numbering more rational and predictable (such as numbering all electives in the 170 series and all production courses in the 180 series).</strong></p>
<p><strong>All the following requirements and policies are based on this new curriculum. </strong></p>
<p>In addition to the University, campus, and college requirements listed on the College Requirements tab, students must fulfill the requirements below specific to their major program.</p>
<h3>General Guidelines</h3>
<ol>
	<li>All courses taken to fulfill the major requirements below must be taken for graded credit, with the exception of one upper-division elective, which can be taken on a P/NP grading basis. There are a few other exceptions; see Major Advisor for details.</li>
	<li>No more than one upper division course may be used to simultaneously fulfill requirements for a student's major and minor programs, with the exception of minors offered outside of the College of Letters &amp; Science.</li>
	<li>A minimum grade point average (GPA) of 2.0 must be maintained across all upper- and lower-division courses used to fulfill the major requirements. In addition, each specific upper- and lower-division course used to fulfill major requirements needs to be passed with a C- or better.</li>
</ol>
<p>For information regarding residence requirements and unit requirements, please see the College Requirements tab.</p>
<h3>Lower Division Requirements</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 10">FILM 10</span></td><td>Film History &amp; Form</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 20">FILM 20</span></td><td>Film and Media Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">ONE of THREE:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 30">FILM 30</span></td><td>Film Aesthetics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 35">FILM 35</span></td><td>Digital Media Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 45">FILM 45</span></td><td>Television Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3>Upper Division Requirements </h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">THREE of FOUR:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 125">FILM 125</span></td><td>Documentary Forms</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 135">FILM 135</span></td><td>Experimental and Alternative Media Art</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 145">FILM 145</span></td><td>Global Media</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 155">FILM 155</span></td><td>Media Technologies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">ELECTIVES x5:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select 20 units, from upper-division Film &amp; Media course offerings, or from the list of approved extra-departmental electives available every semester. It is acceptable to take one 4-unit elective course as Pass/Not Passed</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">*Note that a maximum of two (2) extra-departmental courses can be counted towards elective credit; all other courses must be Film &amp; Media department courses</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</majorrequirementstext>
<summercertificaterequirementstext name="Summer Certificate Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p>The 3-course Summer Sessions certificate in Film &amp; Media Industries and Professions is designed for students interested in pursuing careers in film and media. The curriculum exposes students to industry structures that govern a broad range of media professions, fields, and practices. Individual courses introduce students to the various processes entailed in developing, pitching and producing media content; provide understanding of the roles played by various artists and professionals in the production, distribution, and exhibition of content; provide critical understanding of the key business and legal concepts relevant to intellectual property in our changing media landscape; and provide opportunities to learn about film and media practices from award-winning artists.</p>
<p>This certificate is not an official program offered by Undergraduate Education and will not be noted on a student’s transcript, but upon completion of the third required course, the student will receive a certificate from the Department of Film &amp; Media noting completion of the summer program. <span>Students are welcome to enroll in individual courses offered as part of the certificate program even if they do not intend to pursue the full certificate. </span><span>Non-UC Berkeley students are also welcome to enroll in our summer courses.</span></p>
<h3>Required Courses</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 176">FILM 176</span></td><td>Pitch to Production</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 177">FILM 177</span></td><td>Entertainment Law <sup>1</sup></td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 178">FILM 178</span></td><td>Film &amp; Media Professions</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<dl class="sc_footnotes" aria-label="Footnotes"><dt> <sup> 1 </sup> </dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent">Film &amp; Media majors may count <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 177">FILM 177</span></span> toward the upper division elective requirements for the major. This course satisfies the Philosophy &amp; Values L&amp;S breadth requirement.</p></dd></dl>
<h3>Forms</h3>
<p><a class="external" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSePeATwJul_azScpqHw8RJYDZ9RbV4CVKBoGeZJAra3fwO4Ag/viewform?usp=sf_link" target="_blank">Declaration of Intent to Complete Form</a> – Please submit this form by the end of Week 3 of your second certificate course.</p>
<p><a class="external" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScf56a1H3AQhJmvw6sNIwMB9zO4cDZWNkr_pnmX7ZAQyUWCLg/viewform?usp=sf_link" target="_blank">Certificate Completion Form</a> – Please submit this form by the end of Week 3 of your third certificate course. </p>
]]>
</summercertificaterequirementstext>
<studentlearninggoalstext name="Student Learning Goals">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Learning Goals for the Major</h3>
<p>After completing the Film &amp; Media major, a student will have a working knowledge of the film-making process from concept to exhibition and will be able to interpret films through a variety of aesthetic, cultural, historical, and theoretical frameworks. The critical thinking skills promoted in the film major involve seeing beyond one’s immediate reactions to a film by developing a repertoire of productive interpretive questions and approaches that lead to more complex understanding and appreciation of the filmic experience. Analytic reasoning is encouraged in both oral and written assignments that require students to perform systematic analysis of film sequences, to construct careful, step-by-step arguments in larger research projects, or to create a coherently constructed film or script. Communication skills are developed through participation in classroom discussions, in the effective writing of critical essays and research papers, and in the articulation of creative ideas through film-making and scriptwriting.</p>
<p>More specifically, the successful graduate from the Film &amp; Media major must be able to:</p>
<ol>
	<li><!--class="Mso"--><!--class="Mso"--><span lang="EN">produce formal and aesthetic analyses of different media forms drawing on both medium-specific and comparative approaches;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">think beyond the surface impressions of popular film and media texts by developing a repertoire of critical questions and approaches that facilitate deeper understanding, including concepts of concepts of race, ethnicity, nation, empire, colonialism, class, gender, and sexual orientation;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">engage in the critical study of film and media in an expanded framework, focusing on experimental (social and political), documentary, and global perspectives as part of a comparative approach to a range of media forms including film, television, new media, sound, photography, and more;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">learn basic principles of film analysis through the early emergence of film form;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">develop the skills of shot- and sequence-analyses, both orally in class and in written form;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">talk and write about how individual films or media texts fit within a historical context and the mode of production from which they emerge;</span></li>
	<li>
	<p class="MsoListParagraph"><span>identify and understand the place of film and media as visual and fine art, as well as its influence on major art movements and discourses in modern and contemporary art;</span></p>
	</li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">demonstrate the ability to understand and apply key concepts from film and media theory when analyzing or producing a media text, making a film, or writing a screenplay;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">for those students with special interests in film and media production, develop the technical production skills necessary to express original and critically-informed creative ideas in an accomplished form of visual expression;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">write essays and papers that are clear, well-researched and organized, and that mount an original argument;</span></li>
	<li class="MsoNormal"><span lang="EN">organize ideas in oral presentations and general classroom discussions.</span></li>
</ol>
]]>
</studentlearninggoalstext>
<majormaptext name="Major Map">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>Major Maps help undergraduate students discover academic, co-curricular, and discovery opportunities at UC Berkeley based on intended major or field of interest. Developed by the Division of Undergraduate Education in collaboration with academic departments, these experience maps will help you:</span></p>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-5ef7b472-7fff-6cd0-248d-aaa2f43a2929">Explore</span></strong> your major and gain a better understanding of your field of study</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-5ef7b472-7fff-6cd0-248d-aaa2f43a2929">Connect</span></strong> with people and programs that inspire and sustain your creativity, drive, curiosity and success</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-5ef7b472-7fff-6cd0-248d-aaa2f43a2929">Discover</span></strong> opportunities for independent inquiry, enterprise, and creative expression</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-5ef7b472-7fff-6cd0-248d-aaa2f43a2929">Engage</span></strong> locally and globally to broaden your perspectives and change the world</p>
	</li>
	<li><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-5ef7b472-7fff-6cd0-248d-aaa2f43a2929">Reflect</span></strong> on your academic career and prepare for life after Berkeley</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-d71893c3-7fff-0026-643a-dcc4d58f355a">Use the major map below as a guide to planning your undergraduate journey and designing your own unique Berkeley experience.</span></p>
<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-d71893c3-7fff-0026-643a-dcc4d58f355a"><a href="https://ue.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/film_and_media.pdf">View the Film &amp; Media Major Map PDF.</a></span></strong></p>
]]>
</majormaptext>
<advisingtext name="Advising">
<![CDATA[
<p><strong>Undergraduate Major Advisor:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Grayson Johnston</strong></p>
<div>7406 Dwinelle Hall </div>
<div>gjohnston@berkeley.edu</div>
<div>510-642-3522</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Advising appointments with Grayson can be booked with the following link: <a href="https://graysonjohnston.youcanbook.me/" target="_blank">https://graysonjohnston.youcanbook.me/</a></div>
<div> </div>
<div><span style="font-size:1em">He is generally available for meetings Tuesday-Thursday, 9AM-12PM and 1PM-4PM</span></div>
]]>
</advisingtext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h1><strong>Film &amp; Media</strong></h1>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM R1A">FILM R1A</span></td><td>The Craft of Writing - Film Focus</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM R1B">FILM R1B</span></td><td>The Craft of Writing - Film Focus</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 10">FILM 10</span></td><td>Film History &amp; Form</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 20">FILM 20</span></td><td>Film and Media Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 30">FILM 30</span></td><td>Film Aesthetics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 35">FILM 35</span></td><td>Digital Media Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 39">FILM 39</span></td><td>Freshman/Sophomore Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 45">FILM 45</span></td><td>Television Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 50">FILM 50</span></td><td>Introduction to Film for Nonmajors</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 84">FILM 84</span></td><td>Sophomore Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">1,2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 85">FILM 85</span></td><td>Introduction to Moving Image Production</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 98">FILM 98</span></td><td>Directed Group Study</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 125">FILM 125</span></td><td>Documentary Forms</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 135">FILM 135</span></td><td>Experimental and Alternative Media Art</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 140AC">FILM 140AC</span></td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 145">FILM 145</span></td><td>Global Media</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 155">FILM 155</span></td><td>Media Technologies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 170">FILM 170</span></td><td>Special Topics in Film</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 171">FILM 171</span></td><td>Special Topics in Film Genre</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 172">FILM 172</span></td><td>Auteur Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 176">FILM 176</span></td><td>Pitch to Production</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 177">FILM 177</span></td><td>Entertainment Law</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 178">FILM 178</span></td><td>Film &amp; Media Professions</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 179">FILM 179</span></td><td>Understanding Film Sound</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 180">FILM 180</span></td><td>Introduction to Screenwriting</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 181">FILM 181</span></td><td>Screenwriting</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 182">FILM 182</span></td><td>TV Writing</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 185">FILM 185</span></td><td>Intermediate Moving Image Production</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 186">FILM 186</span></td><td>Advanced Moving Image Production</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 187">FILM 187</span></td><td>Special Topics in Media Production</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 188">FILM 188</span></td><td>Documentary and Non-fiction Media Production</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 190">FILM 190</span></td><td>Capstone Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 193">FILM 193</span></td><td>Intermediate Film Writing</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 194">FILM 194</span></td><td>Advanced Film Writing</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM H195">FILM H195</span></td><td>Film Honors Thesis</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 197A">FILM 197A</span></td><td>Field Study at the Pacific Film Archive</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 197B">FILM 197B</span></td><td>Field Studies for Majors</td><td class="hourscol">1-3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 197C">FILM 197C</span></td><td>Film Curating Internship</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 198">FILM 198</span></td><td>Directed Group Study</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FILM 199">FILM 199</span></td><td>Supervised Independent Study for Advanced Undergraduates</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Weihong Bao, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Film theory and history, media archaeology, critical theory, visual and performance culture, Chinese language cinema, transnational genre cinema, comparative media history and theory.<br/><a href="http://ealc.berkeley.edu/people/bao-weihong"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rizvana Bradley, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Film theory, critical theory, aesthetics of postcoloniality and the black diaspora, gender and sexuality studies, contemporary art, art history and visual culture.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Natalia Brizuela, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Photography, film, contemporary art, critical theory and aesthetics of Spanish America and Brazil .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14471"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary Ann Doane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, semiotics, cinema, media, cultural theory, archaeology of media technology, poststructuralism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14326"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jacob Gaboury, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Digital media, visual culture, media archaeology, queer theory,  20th century histories of technology and computation, computer graphics, and the intersection of contemporary art and technology .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anton Kaes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Film studies, modern literature, literary and cultural theory, cinema, interdisciplinary and comparative aspects of Weimar culture, contemporary literature and film, literary theory, theory of cultural studies, film history, film theory, history of cinema.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14903"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anne Nesbet, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Culture, film studies, Slavic languages, early Soviet culture, Sergei Eisenstein, silent film, Soviet film, GDR history, children's literature and Stalinism, the Soviet Union, American minority movements.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15172"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>NicolÃ¡s Pereda, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Film production, hybrid cinema, alternative fictions, slow cinema.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mark Sandberg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Silent film, late nineteenth-century visual culture, theater history, comedy, Scandinavian design, serial television, film historiography, Scandinavian film history, Henrik Ibsen, Norwegian literature, Nordic literary history.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14283"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Miryam Sas, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Comparative literature, 20th century avant-gardes, Japanese literature, film, theater and dance, contemporary art, critical theory, gender theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15410"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jeffrey A. Skoller, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Film history, theory and practice of documentary, avant-garde film, film as art, activist media, Third Cinema , film/video production.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15455"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kristen Whissel, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cinema and technological change, computer-generated images and contemporary cinema, digital visual effects, the history and theory of special effects, cinema in transition, American film history, silent American cinema, modernity and early cinema .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14322"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Damon R. Young, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Digital media, global art cinema (with a focus on French and francophone), gender and sexuality studies, critical theory.</p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Emily Carpenter, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>J. Mira Kopell, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

