<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Health and Medical Sciences</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The JMP is a five-year graduate/medical degree program. The pre-clerkship years are spent at UC Berkeley, engaging in a leading-edge integrated Problem-Based Learning medical curriculum while simultaneously earning a master’s degree (MS) in the Health and Medical Sciences at UC Berkeley’s School of Public Health. After two and a half years, our students move across the bay to UCSF to finish their medical education and receive their medical doctorate (MD).</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Health and Medical Sciences. However, <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/premed/">Pre-Med/Pre-Health</a> is a pre-professional path that students choose when preparing for a career in graduate-level health professions. </p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/health-medical-sciences-program/">Health and Medical Sciences</a>: UC Berkeley–UCSF Joint Medical Program (JMP).</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Amin Azzam, <i>Clinical Professor</i>. </strong>Medical education scholarship.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/amin-azzam"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Katherine Brooks MD, <i>Assistant Professor, Medicine</i>. </strong>Clinical Skills Faculty.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Odinakachukwu (Odi) Ehie MD, <i>Associate Clinical Professor</i>. </strong>Anesthesia Head, Clinical Skills.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Monica Hahn, <i>Associate Clinical Professor</i>. </strong> Family & Community Medicine. Family physician, HIV specialist, and Clinical Director/Co-Principal Investigator of the Pacific AIDS Education and Training Center (PAETC). JMP PRIME-US faculty.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jodi Halpern, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, bioethics, patient autonomy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jodi-halpern"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Seth Holmes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Medical anthropology, transnational im/migration, race and racism, gender and queer studies.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Susan Ivey, <i>Associate Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, health disparities, interventions, community-based participatory research.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/susan-l-ivey"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Claudia Landau, <i>Associate Clinical Professor</i>. </strong>Neuroendocrinology of Stress, Cognitive Assessment in Diverse Cultures, Community Bases, Fall prevention.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leanna W. Lewis, LCSW, <i>Associate Director, UC Berkeley-UCSF Joint Medical Program Administrative Program Director, UCSF Program in Medical Education for the Urban Underserved (PRIME-US) at the JMP</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jyothi Marbin MD, <i>HS Clinical Professor, Pediatrics Director, UC Berkeley-UCSF Joint Medical Program</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Osagie Obasogie, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Law, bioethics, reproductive and genetic technologies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/osagie-obasogie"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gaspar Rivera, MD, <i>Assistant Clinical Professor, Pediatrics</i>. </strong>Clinical Skills Faculty.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ashkon Shaahinfar, MD, <i>Assistant Professor, Emergency Medicine</i>. </strong>Clinical Skills Faculty.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Karen Sokal-Gutierrez, <i>Clinical Professor</i>. </strong>Nutrition, maternal-child health, early childhood health, oral health, child health in developing countries.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/karen-sokal-gutierrez"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Gustavo Valbuena, <i>Associate Clinical Professor, Head, Foundational Sciences Head, Master's of Health and Medical Sciences</i>. </strong>Conceptualization and operationalization of inquiry in medical education, the relationship between inquiry and the process of integration between basic sciences and clinical sciences, integration-supportive instructional design.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/gustavo-valbuena-md-phd"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>* Jennifer Breckler, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>Research on student learning styles and career choice Projects include creating new hands-on kinesthetic ways for students to engage in and learn about science.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/jennifer-breckler"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Shelene Stine, <i>Head of Assessment and Clinical Partnerships/Clinical Skills and Foundational Medical Sciences Faculty</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Woolridge, MD, MS, MPH, <i>Lecturer, Pediatrics</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Hana Dan-Cohen, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>Integration of the basic sciences with a clinical curriculum in medical education.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/hana-dan-cohen"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sara Hartley, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>The interpersonal domain of doctor-patient interaction, The interview, Mind/brain models.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/sara-hartley"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Guy Micco, <i>Clinical Professor, Emeritus, Co-director, UC Berkeley Program for Health and Medical Sciences</i>. </strong>Aging/old age, suffering, and death, the medical humanities.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/guy-micco"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Kent Olson, <i>Clinical Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Diagnosis and management of acute poisoning, Cost-effectiveness of poison control centers, Case development in the JMP case-based curriculum, General Emergency Medicine, Medical Toxicology.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/kent-olson"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard Quint, <i>Clinical Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Ann Stevens, <i>Clinical Professor Emerita</i>. </strong>Women's health issues, Medical education, Physician/patient relationshi.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/ann-stevens"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* John Swartzberg, <i>Clinical Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Social epidemiology, community interventions.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/s-leonard-syme"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

