<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Health and Wellness</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The goal of the interdisciplinary minor in health and wellness is for students to have concentrated study in the area that can complement their major with a series of courses from outside their discipline. The minor centers on a three-course core, covering the cultural, psychological, and physiological aspects of health and wellness, respectively, and two upper-division electives, selected from a list of chosen courses from various disciplines across campus for students to tailor a focused course of study in human well-being. After completing the minor, students shall be able to:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Analyze health and wellness via a cultural lens with sociocultural factors such as race, class, sex, and gender.</li>
	<li>Apply different research methods for examining health and wellness issues.</li>
	<li>Identify the strengths and weaknesses of quantitative and qualitative methods in health and wellness research. Develop sound research skills to be able to read, to interpret, and to implement research in health and wellness.</li>
	<li>Evaluate cultural systems that give rise to inequities in health and wellness and assess how health and wellness can be constructed culturally and may be potentially biased.</li>
	<li>Gain knowledge in the dimensions of wellness — physical, occupational, social, spiritual, intellectual, and emotional — and develop strategies within each dimension of wellness to modify lifestyle and to learn, to implement, and to adopt healthy behaviors.</li>
	<li>Make behavior changes that promote health and well-being, and identify and implement healthy behaviors that enhance the quality of life throughout the lifespan.</li>
	<li>Promote health and wellness through the implementation of behavioral change and lifestyle medicine.</li>
	<li>Explore career options in health and wellness, including allied areas such as fitness- and sports-related endeavors.</li>
</ul>
<p>Declaration to Pursue the Health and Wellness Minor: <a href="https://pe.berkeley.edu/declaration-pursue-health-and-wellness-minor">https://pe.berkeley.edu/declaration-pursue-health-and-wellness-minor</a></p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<minorrequirementstext name="Minor Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>General Requirements</h3>
<p style="margin-left:40px">1. All upper-division courses taken to fulfill the minor requirements below must be taken for a letter grade.</p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">2. A minimum of three of the upper-division courses taken to fulfill the minor requirements must be completed at UC Berkeley.</p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">3. A minimum grade point average (GPA) of 2.0 is required for courses used to fulfill the minor requirements. Courses used to fulfill the minor requirements may be applied toward the Seven-Course Breadth requirement, for Letters &amp; Science students.</p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">4. No more than one upper-division course may be used to simultaneously fulfill requirements for a student’s major and minor programs.</p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">5. All minor requirements must be completed prior to the last day of finals during the semester in which the student plans to be graduated. If the student cannot finish all courses required for the minor by that time, the student must see a College of Letters &amp; Science advisor.</p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">6. All minor requirements must be completed within the unit ceiling.</p>
<h3>Lower Division Required Courses</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUSCTX 10">NUSCTX 10</span></td><td>Introduction to Human Nutrition</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 32">PHYS ED 32</span></td><td>Fitness for Life: Physical Adaptations to Exercise</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Choose two of the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 1">PHYS ED 1</span></div></td><td>Physical Education Activities [0.5]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 2">PHYS ED 2</span></div></td><td>Physical Education Activities [0.5]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 3">PHYS ED 3</span></div></td><td>Physical Education Activities [0.5]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 4">PHYS ED 4</span></div></td><td>Physical Education Activities [0.5]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 5">PHYS ED 5</span></div></td><td>Physical Education Activities [0.5]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Choose one of the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PSYCH 1">PSYCH 1</span></div></td><td>General Psychology [3]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PSYCH W1">PSYCH W1</span></div></td><td>General Psychology [3]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PSYCH 2">PSYCH 2</span></div></td><td>Principles of Psychology [3]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3>Upper Division Required Core Courses</h3>
<p>Three core courses are required; two courses are electives.</p>
<p>A minimum of five, upper-division courses must be completed that total at least 15 units. Three of the courses must be taken from UC Berkeley. Some courses may have additional prerequisites or require the permission of the instructor.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 121">PHYS ED 121</span></td><td>Health, Wellness, and Culture: A Critical Perspective</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYS ED 177">PHYS ED 177</span></td><td>Wellness for Life</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PSYCH 162">PSYCH 162</span></td><td>Human Happiness</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass even lastrow"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PSYCH C162">PSYCH C162</span></td><td colspan="2"> Human Happiness</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3>Upper Division Elective Courses</h3>
<p>Select two elective courses, for a minimum of six units. The courses may be counted in any semester they are offered. One course may be replaced by completing a minimum of three units of thesis, internship (field study), group study, or independent study and research (i.e., 196 Thesis, 197 Field Study, 198 Directed Group Study, or 199 Supervised Independent Study and Research; these courses normally would have a prefix of PHYS ED or PSYCH, but prefixes from other departments are allowed with written approval from the program’s director).</p>
<p>For a full list of elective courses, visit the program web page: <a href="https://pe.berkeley.edu/health-and-wellness-minor">https://pe.berkeley.edu/health-and-wellness-minor</a></p>
]]>
</minorrequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

