<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Development Engineering</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<div>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p><span>The Designated Emphasis in Development Engineering (DE in Dev Eng) is an interdisciplinary training program for UC Berkeley doctoral students whose dissertation research includes topics related to the application of technology to address the needs of people living in poverty. Through course work, research, mentoring, and professional development, the program prepares students to develop, pilot, and evaluate technological interventions designed to improve human and economic development within complex, low-resource settings. The DE in Dev Eng serves students across engineering disciplines, quantitative social science disciplines (including public health), business programs, information sciences, and natural sciences.</span></p>
<p>The program builds upon ongoing research in technological innovations, human-centered design, development economics, remote sensing and monitoring, data science, and impact analysis at UC Berkeley. The program is overseen by the Graduate Group in Development Engineering, administered through the Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, and affiliated with: </p>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://blumcenter.berkeley.edu/">Blum Center for Developing Economies</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://cega.berkeley.edu/">Center for Effective Global Action (CEGA)</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://dil.berkeley.edu/data-analytics-toolkits/mezuri-platform/tier/">Technology and Infrastructure for Emerging Regions (TIER)</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://dil.berkeley.edu/">Development Impact Lab (DIL)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This constellation of affiliates, through DIL, is a cornerstone partner in USAID's <a href="http://www.usaid.gov/GlobalDevLab">Global Development Lab</a>. As such, Development Engineering students are connected to a network of researchers and practitioners at Berkeley and also have access to a dynamic global network. To review the development engineering research projects sponsored by DIL, students are encouraged to explore the <a href="http://dil.berkeley.edu/technology-portfolio/">DIL Technology Portfolio</a>. </p>
</div>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Development Engineering.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Charisma Acey, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Water, sanitation, basic services delivery, poverty alleviation, environmental sustainability, environmental justice, urban governance, participatory planning, community-based development, international development, development planning, sustainable development, African studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16861"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rediet Abebe, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Artificial intelligence, algorithms, computational social science, economics and computation, discrimination, inequality.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/rediet-abebe"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alice M. Agogino, <i>Chair of Development Engineering</i>. </strong>New product development, computer-aided design and databases, theory and methods, intelligent learning systems, information retrieval and data mining, digital libraries, multiobjective and strategic product, nonlinear optimization, probabilistic modeling, supervisory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14365"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joshua Blumenstock, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Development Economics, Data Science, Econometrics, Machine Learning, ICTD.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/joshua-blumenstock"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jenna Burrell, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>School of Information.<br/><a href="https://www.ischool.berkeley.edu/people/jenna-burrell"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Canny, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computer science, activity-based computing, livenotes, mechatronic devices, flexonics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14606"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jack Colford, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, epidemiology, infectious diseases, biostatistics, meta-analysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14621"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Paolo D'Odorico, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Hydrology,  Ecohydrology,  water resources,  Water and Society,  environmental sciences,  Drylands, Desertification.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/paolo-dodorico"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hany Farid, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Digital forensics, forensic science, misinformation, image analysis, and human perception.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/hany-farid"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Fletcher, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Bioengineering, optical and force microscopy, microfabrication, biophysics, mechanical properties of cells.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/daniel-alden-fletcher"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ashok Gadgil, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Fuel-efficient stoves, indoor air quality, energy efficiency, developing countries, drinking water, buildings energy efficiency .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/ashok-gadgil"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Paul Gertler, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Impact evaluation, health economics.<br/><a href="http://facultybio.haas.berkeley.edu/faculty-list/gertler-paul/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maria Paz Gutierrez, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Next-generation building systems, self-regulated facades, biologically inspired technologies, multifunctional materials.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14763"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Elizabeth Hoover, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Native American food systems, food sovereignty, Native American environmental health movements, heirloom seeds, Indigenous use of fire, Native American museum curation, community based participatory research, environmental justice, food justice.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/elizabeth-hoover"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Kammen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Climate Change, Engineering, Environment, Energy, Renewable and Clean Energy, Energy Forecasting, Health and Environment, International R&D Policy, Race and Gender, Rural Resource Management.<br/><a href="https://gspp.berkeley.edu/directories/faculty/daniel-kammen"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>G. Mathias Kondolf, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Landscape Architecture & Environmental Planning, Hydrology, environmental planning, river restoration, urban river management, river-basin scale sustainable sediment management, strategic planning for hydroelectric dams.<br/><a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/faculty-staff/g-mathias-kondolf"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Laura (Layla) H. Kwong, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Environmental health sciences.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/laura-kwong"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Levine, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Organizational learning, economic development, management, workplace, health and education in poor nations.<br/><a href="http://facultybio.haas.berkeley.edu/faculty-list/levine-david/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Baoxia Mi, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Membrane separation, desalination, water purification, wastewater reuse, environmental applications of nanomaterials.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/baoxia-mi"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kara L. Nelson, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Water and wastewater treatment, water reuse, detection and inactivation of pathogens in water and sludge, appropriate technologies .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/kara-l-nelson"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Grace O Connell, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Biomechanics of cartilage and intervertebral disc; tissue engineering; continuum modeling of soft tissues; intervertebral disc function, degeneration, and regeneration.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/grace-d-oconnell"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Amy Pickering , <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Disease transmission.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/amy-pickering"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Kameshwar Poolla, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cybersecurity, modeling, control, renewable energy, estimation, integrated circuit design and manufacturing, smart grids.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14273"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Matthew D. Potts, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Forest management, biofuels, plantation agriculture, land use planning, land use policy, biodiversity conservation, ecosystem services, tropical ecology, environmental economics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/matthew-potts"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Ranney, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Problem solving, knowledge representation and reorganization, explanatory coherence and inference, conceptual change, societal implications, science instruction, global climate change psychology, numeracy in journalism, naive/informal physics, computational models of cognition, perceptual-cognitive interactions, intelligent tutoring systems, understandings of biological evolution, Reasoning, qualitative and quantitative thinking.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15390"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Benjamin Recht, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Machine learning, data science, artificial intelligence.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/benjamin-recht"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Elisabeth Sadoulet, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Economics, agriculture, labor management and policy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15297"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>S. Shankar Sastry, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computer science, robotics, arial robots, cybersecurity, cyber defense, homeland defense, nonholonomic systems, control of hybrid systems, sensor networks, interactive visualization, robotic telesurgery, rapid prototyping.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13862"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Zuo-Jun (Max) Shen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Industrial Engineering and Operations, Civil and Environmental Engineering, Integrated Supply Chain Design and Management, Data Driven Logistics and Supply Chain Optimization, Design and Analysis of Optimization Algorithms, Energy Systems Optimization, Transportation System Planning .<br/><a href="https://shen.ieor.berkeley.edu/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Laura D'Andrea Tyson, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>High-technology competition, US industrial and technology policies, international economy, US trade policy, US competitiveness, emerging market economies, multinational companies in the US economy, gender gap (economic participation, educational attainment, political empowerment and health), research and development tax credit.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14334"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sarah Vaughn, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Cultural anthropology, post-colonial science, environment, climate change, vulnerability, theories of liberalism, Caribbean, Latin America.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sarah-e-vaughn"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Catherine D. Wolfram, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Climate change, energy efficiency, regulation of business, energy and environmental markets.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15629"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Zilberman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Marketing, biotechnology, water, risk management, biofuels, natural resources, agricultural and environmental policy, the economics of innovation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15655"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>* Sara Beckman, <i>Senior Lecturer SOE</i>. </strong>Business, innovation, management, product development, operations strategy, environmental supply chain management.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13849"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Clair Brown, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Innovation, management, economics, labor, employment, labor market institutions, semi-conductor industry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14424"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>S. Leonard Syme, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Social epidemiology, community interventions.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15518"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anil Aswani, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Data-driven decision making, with particular emphasis on addressing inefficiencies and inequities in health systems and physical infrastructure.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/anil-aswani"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maya Carrasquillo, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Urban water infrastructure, green infrastructure, food-energy-water nexus, sustainable urban systems, environmental justice, social justice, critical race theory, community engagement, equitable decision-making, interdisciplinary engineering, workforce development, K-12 math and science education.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/maya-carrasquillo"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Solene Delecourt, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Business performance, entrepreneurship, discrimination, field experiments, management.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/solene-delecourt"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Brad Delong, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Economic history, macroeconomics, economic growth, finance.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/j-bradford-delong"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Oscar Dubon, <i>Professor of Material Science</i>. </strong>Magnetic, optical materials, processing, properties in electronic.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/oscar-dubon"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marco Gonzalez-Navarro, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Development economics, urban economics.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/marco-gonzalez-navarro"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kosa Goucher-Lambert, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Design theory and methods, automation, decision-making applied to engineering teams and individuals, ideation and creativity, analogical reasoning in design, preference modeling and design attribute optimization, design cognition, neuroimaging methods applied to design, sustainable design, new product development, crowdsourcing and collaboration.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/kosa-goucher-lambert"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jay Graham, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Community-acquired antimicrobial resistance, Zoonotic infectious diseases, Environmental determinants of infectious diseases, Exposure assessment.<br/><a href="https://publichealth.berkeley.edu/people/jay-graham/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Supreet Kaur, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Development economics, behavioral economics, labor economics.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/supreet-kaur"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

