<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Epidemiology</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2><span>Overview</span></h2>
<p>The PhD group in Epidemiology is interdisciplinary and includes faculty from a number of departments at UC Berkeley as well as the University of California, San Francisco (UCSF). Students receive either an MS or PhD degree from the Graduate Division of the Berkeley campus. The group is within the academic jurisdiction of the Graduate Council and is administratively located in the Division of Epidemiology.</p>
<p>The group brings together faculty with disciplinary knowledge in epidemiology, biostatistics, economics, demography, sociology, anthropology, behavioral science, molecular biology, genetics, vector biology, and other fields relevant to the study of human health and disease at a population level. MS and PhD students receive a strong background in epidemiologic and biostatistical methods and theory; additionally, students choose a third disciplinary area in which to develop competence. Doctoral dissertation research is generally focused on developing new knowledge about the factors that influence the distribution of health or given disease outcomes within human populations.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Epidemiology.</p>
<h3>Graduate Programs</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/epidemiology/">Epidemiology</a>: MS, MPH, PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Barbara Abrams, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Weight and weight gain in women during pregnancy, postpartum and menopause Maternal weight, nutrition, social factors and perinatal health outcomes Could expressed and heat-treated breast milk prevent perinatal hiv transmission.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/barbara-abrams"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer Ahern, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Mental health, epidemiology, social epidemiology, population health, neighborhood characteristics and health, methodological issues and novel methodological applications in social, traumatic events, substance use, behavioral health, birth outcomes and maternal health.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14580"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lisa F. Barcellos, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, genetic epidemiology, human genetics, autoimmune diseases, multiple schlerosis, lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, epigenetics, genomics, computational biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14591"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Patrick Bradshaw, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer Epidemiology, Epidemiologic Methods, Nutritional Epidemiology, Obesity Epidemiology.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/patrick-bradshaw"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jack Colford, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, epidemiology, infectious diseases, biostatistics, meta-analysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14621"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Brenda Eskenazi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, epidemiology, biostatistics, maternal and child health.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14640"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mahasin S. Mujahid, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Multi-level determinants of racial/ethnic health disparities, Neighborhood environments and cardiovascular health  Breast cancer treatment and survivorship, Methods in social epidemiology, Population health.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/mahasin-mujahid"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Arthur L. Reingold, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Opportunistic infections in AIDS patients, Interrelationship between tuberculosis and AIDS in developing countries, Emerging and re-emerging infections in the United States and in developing countries, Vaccine preventable diseases in the United States and in developing countries.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/arthur-reingold"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

