<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Entry Level Writing Requirement</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
 <h4>Entry Level Writing Requirement</h4> <p>All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by satisfying the Entry Level Writing Requirement (ELWR).</p> <p>The <a href="https://admission.universityofcalifornia.edu/elwr/" target="_blank">UC Entry Level Writing Requirement website</a> provides information on how to satisfy the requirement by one of three options:</p> <p><strong>Standardized Exam option</strong></p> <p style="margin-left:36pt">See the link above for acceptable minimum scores on standardized exams.</p> <p><strong>Advanced Writing Placement Examination (AWPE) option</strong></p> <p style="margin-left:36pt"><strong>High school students</strong> planning to attend a UC campus may take the <a href="https://writing.berkeley.edu/entry-level-writing-assessment-formerly-awpe" target="_blank">Analytical Writing Placement Examination</a> in May of their senior year. (Students selected for the May exam are sent the test notification letter in April.)</p> <p style="margin-left:36pt"><strong>Admitted students</strong> who have not yet satisfied the requirement may take the AWPE their <a href="https://writing.berkeley.edu/students/awp-exam">first semester at Berkeley</a>.</p> <p><strong>English Composition Course option</strong></p> <p style="margin-left:36pt"><strong>Admitted student</strong>s may opt to complete a course articulated to the ENGLISH R1A course, as published in <a href="http://www.assist.org/web-assist/welcome.html">ASSIST</a>, provided the course is completed by the start of the term of admission to Berkeley. A grade of C or higher will satisfy both Entry Level Writing and Part A of the Reading and Composition requirement.</p> <p style="margin-left:36pt">Once an Admitted student begins courses at Berkeley, and the requirement has not otherwise been met, students must complete COLWRIT R1A. A grade of C or higher is will satisfy both Entry Level Writing and Part A of the Reading and Composition requirement.</p> <table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"> <caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption> <colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COLWRIT R1A">COLWRIT R1A</span></td><td>Accelerated Reading and Composition</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr> <tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="XCOLWRI R1A">XCOLWRI R1A</span></td><td>Accelerated Reading and Composition</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr> </tbody></table> 
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

