<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Design</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<div>The Master of Design (MDes) degree program is a three-semester, professional graduate degree in design that<span> integrates human-centered design with a sophisticated understanding of technology to prepare students to excel in creative practices today and design the thoughtful technologies of tomorrow. </span>Jointly offered by the College of Engineering and the College of Environmental Design, the program's interdisciplinary curriculum connects technical rigor, design theory, and social practice and prepares students for a broad range of creative and technical roles for designing innovative products, services, and environments.</div>
<div><br/>
Housed at the Jacobs Institute for Design Innovation, the MDes provides a dynamic, hands-on curriculum that uniquely equips students to develop a critical perspective and navigate a range of technical languages and design methodologies. Studio-based coursework integrates programming, human-centered design process, and communication with hardware and software development. Exploratory project briefs encourage students to use design process to identify new problem spaces and to explore ideas through co-creative processes, iteration, and prototyping. A set of debate-focused seminars help shape students' critical lens on design through analysis and discussion of the ethical, ecological, and societal implications of practice within an evolving environmental and socio-technology landscape. Students further deepen their knowledge through technical electives and offerings in social practice or entrepreneurship relevant to their interests and career goals. Their studies culminate in a Design Studio where they work in teams and bring their distinct perspectives to bear on applied projects. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>With support from MDes Career Services, students enhance their academic preparation through Design@Large — an opportunity outside of an MDes course or studio where they apply what they have learned in a professional context, typically in the summer between their second and third semesters (see Professional Development Activities). </div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<newitemtext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Master of Design (MDes) is designed for early to mid-career professionals with an interest in pursuing graduate work at the intersection of design and technology, with applications that might include artistic production, technological innovations, product or communication design, and design experiences or interventions, etc. Competitive applicants have some prior technical preparation and an interest in design as a creative, goal-oriented activity that can contribute to the emergence of innovative new technologies and environments.</p>
<h3><strong>Application Criteria</strong></h3>
<p>The following are required for admission to the Berkeley MDes program. The following includes the University’s general graduate admission requirements:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Online Application</li>
	<li>Application Fee</li>
	<li>University Transcripts</li>
	<li>Curriculum Vitae (CV) or Resume, showing relevant work and/or research experience</li>
	<li>Two Essays (personal statement and statement of purpose)</li>
	<li>Three Letters of Recommendation</li>
	<li>Project portfolio, showing previous design work</li>
	<li>English Language Proficiency Requirement (if required)</li>
	<li>The GRE Exam is not required.</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, students may be invited for an interview, either in-person or remote, and should be prepared to explain their qualifications, motivations to apply to the program, and goals for the program.</p>
<h3><strong>Portfolio Requirements</strong></h3>
<p>All applicants are required to submit a portfolio that demonstrates their creative and technical proficiency. Depending on your individual practice, this may include examples of visual design work, software systems, interactive electronics, videos, paintings, 3D models, ceramics, performances, musical compositions, social practices, or many other types of creative or technical pursuits.<br/>
Your portfolio should be legible to a general audience of designers, and should not only present representations of final outcomes/designs in their intended contexts, but also accounts of your design process, and samples of early design iterations. Portfolios are expected to include both images and supporting text and should convey the context from which the project arose and the lens through which to understand and critique the work. Collaborative work is encouraged, but please credit all authors and highlight your specific contribution. Similarly, academic, professional, and personal work are all welcome, but please differentiate these distinct types of work.</p>
<p>In our experience, strong portfolios often opt to describe a limited selection of projects in depth, rather than account for a large breadth of projects superficially. We suggest highlighting between 3–5 of your most compelling exemplars of creative work. The most important role of a portfolio is to clearly communicate your skills, experience, and perspective. Your portfolio must include your name and contact information and be submitted as a stand-alone PDF formatted document. You may submit your portfolio of up to 20 pages maximum and 20MB total PDF file size. Portfolios that are submitted in excess of this page and size restriction will not be reviewed by the admissions committee. Any URLs or links to outside materials within your portfolio or elsewhere in your application will not be reviewed. You may optionally include up to two minutes of additional time-based media (audio/video). </p>
<div class="yj6qo ajU"> </div>
<h3><span>Graduate Division Admissions</span></h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
]]>
</newitemtext>
<mastersdegreerequirementstext name="Master's Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Master of Design (MDes) program requires nine core courses and three electives (see below) for a minimum of 38 credits for the degree. </p>
<h3>Required Courses</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 200">DES INV 200</span></td><td>Design Frameworks: History &amp; Methods</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 201">DES INV 201</span></td><td>Debates in Design (Students are required to take this course twice; once during the fall semester in year one, and again during the fall semester of year two.)</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 202">DES INV 202</span></td><td>Technology Design Foundations</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 211">DES INV 211</span></td><td>Designing Emerging Technologies I</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 212">DES INV 212</span></td><td>Designing Emerging Technologies II</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 213">DES INV 213</span></td><td>Design Studio</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 219">DES INV 219</span></td><td>Capstone Portfolio</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 290">DES INV 290</span></td><td>Advanced Special Topics in Design Innovation</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 183">ENGIN 183</span></td><td>Special Topics in Technology Innovation and Entrepreneurship</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3><span>Elective Courses</span></h3>
<p>The MDes requires three electives: one technical elective, and at least one entrepreneurship or social practice elective from the approved lists of courses, shown below. The third elective may be either an additional elective from the approved list (technical, social practice, or entrepreneurship) or any 3 or 4 unit upper division or graduate level course offered at UC Berkeley, subject to enrollment availability. Students may submit petitions for alternate courses to the Executive Director. </p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Approved Technical Electives</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 249">ARCH 249</span></td><td>Special Topics in the Physical Environment in Buildings</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 252">ARCH 252</span></td><td>Form and Structure</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 259">ARCH 259</span></td><td>Special Topics in Building Structures</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 269">ARCH 269</span></td><td>Special Topics in Construction and Materials (Indoor Microbiome, Detoxification, and Artificial Intelligence and Matter; Plant Fibers and Design: Origins and Future; Timber Frame and Mass Timber Construction )</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 172">ART 172</span></td><td>Advanced Digital Media: Computer Graphics Studio</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CIV ENG 190">CIV ENG 190</span></td><td>Special Topics in Civil and Environmental Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 161">COMPSCI 161</span></td><td>Computer Security</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 169A">COMPSCI 169A</span></td><td>Introduction to Software Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 188">COMPSCI 188</span></td><td>Introduction to Artificial Intelligence</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 194">COMPSCI 194</span></td><td>Special Topics (Data Engineering)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 260B">COMPSCI 260B</span></td><td>Human-Computer Interaction Research</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 184">COMPSCI 184</span></td><td>Foundations of Computer Graphics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass even"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 284A">COMPSCI 284A</span></td><td colspan="2"> Foundations of Computer Graphics</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 188">COMPSCI 188</span></td><td>Introduction to Artificial Intelligence</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI C200A">COMPSCI C200A</span></td><td>Principles and Techniques of Data Science</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI C249A">COMPSCI C249A</span></td><td>Introduction to Embedded Systems</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 260A">COMPSCI 260A</span></td><td>User Interface Design and Development</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 284A">COMPSCI 284A</span></td><td>Foundations of Computer Graphics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 287H">COMPSCI 287H</span></td><td>Algorithmic Human-Robot Interaction</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 289A">COMPSCI 289A</span></td><td>Introduction to Machine Learning</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 294">COMPSCI 294</span></td><td>Special Topics (Intro to Computer Vision and Computational Photography)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 297">COMPSCI 297</span></td><td>Field Studies in Computer Science ( Immersive Computing and Virtual Reality)</td><td class="hourscol">12.0</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN 257">CY PLAN 257</span></td><td>Data Science for Human Mobility and Socio-technical Systems</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DATASCI 207">DATASCI 207</span></td><td>Applied Machine Learning</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 150">ENGIN 150</span></td><td>Basic Modeling and Simulation Tools for Industrial Research Applications</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="IND ENG 290">IND ENG 290</span></td><td>Special Topics in Industrial Engineering and Operation Research (Entrepreneurship &amp; Innovation: Data-X (Applied Data Science with Venture Application))</td><td class="hourscol">2-3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="INFO 253A">INFO 253A</span></td><td>Front-End Web Architecture</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="INTEGBI C217">INTEGBI/BIO ENG/MEC ENG C217</span></td><td>Biomimetic Engineering -- Engineering from Biology</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MAT SCI 200A">MAT SCI 200A</span></td><td>Survey of Materials Science</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 122">MEC ENG 122</span></td><td>Processing of Materials in Manufacturing</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG C201">MEC ENG C201</span></td><td>Modeling and Simulation of Advanced Manufacturing Processes</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 236U">MEC ENG 236U</span></td><td>Control and Dynamics of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 270">MEC ENG 270</span></td><td>Advanced Augmentation of Human Dexterity</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 280A">MEC ENG 280A</span></td><td>Introduction to the Finite Element Method</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MUSIC 158A">MUSIC 158A</span></td><td>Sound and Music Computing with CNMAT Technologies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MUSIC 159">MUSIC 159</span></td><td>Computer Programming for Music Applications</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NWMEDIA 190">NWMEDIA 190</span></td><td>Special Topics in New Media (Advanced Digital Animation)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NWMEDIA C203">NWMEDIA C203</span></td><td>Critical Making</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NWMEDIA C262">NWMEDIA/INFO C262</span></td><td>Theory and Practice of Tangible User Interfaces</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Approved Entrepreneurship Electives</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 183C">ENGIN 183C</span></td><td>Challenge Lab</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 183D">ENGIN 183D</span></td><td>Product Management</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 183">ENGIN 183</span></td><td>Special Topics in Technology Innovation and Entrepreneurship</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 283">ENGIN 283</span></td><td>Special Topics in Technology Innovation and Entrepreneurship</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Approved Social Practice Electives</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 209">ARCH 209</span></td><td>Special Topics in Architectural Design (Virtual Reality: Theory and Representation; Special Topics in Architectural Design: Housing as Design Generator; Contradictions in Disaster and Resilience)</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 239">ARCH 239</span></td><td>Special Topics in Architecture Design Theory and Criticism (Design Dispossession and Dissent)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 279">ARCH 279</span></td><td>Special Topics in the History of Architecture (Design Radicals)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 160">ART 160</span></td><td>Special Topics in Visual Studies (Social Practices; Making and Exhibiting Art in Pandemic Times)</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN 190">CY PLAN 190</span></td><td>Advanced Topics in Urban Studies (Ghosts and Visions)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN 205">CY PLAN 205</span></td><td>Introduction to Planning and Environmental Law</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN 207">CY PLAN 207</span></td><td>Land and Housing Market Economics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN C213">CY PLAN C213</span></td><td>Transportation and Land Use Planning</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN 216">CY PLAN 216</span></td><td>Active Transportation</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN C217">CY PLAN C217</span></td><td>Transportation Policy and Planning</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN C251">CY PLAN C251</span></td><td>Environmental Planning and Regulation</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN 255">CY PLAN 255</span></td><td>Urban Informatics and Visualization</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN 257">CY PLAN 257</span></td><td>Data Science for Human Mobility and Socio-technical Systems</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NWMEDIA 151AC">NWMEDIA 151AC</span></td><td>Transforming Tech: Issues and Interventions in STEM and Silicon Valley</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NWMEDIA 200">NWMEDIA 200</span></td><td>History and Theory of New Media</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NWMEDIA C265">NWMEDIA C265</span></td><td>Interface Aesthetics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NWMEDIA 290">NWMEDIA 290</span></td><td>Special Topics in New Media (Locative Media)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Approved Design Electives (may be taken as free/open elective)</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 209">ARCH 209</span></td><td>Special Topics in Architectural Design (Architecture and Landscape)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 229">ARCH 229</span></td><td>Special Topics in Digital Design Theories and Methods</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ARCH 269">ARCH 269</span></td><td>Special Topics in Construction and Materials (Constructing Interior Objects)</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<div> </div>
]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementstext>
<programoutcomestext name="Program Outcomes">
<![CDATA[
<p>The goal of the Master of Design (MDes) program is to educate a cohort of designers to have a deep understanding of the foundations of emerging technologies and a rigorous design approach for analyzing ethical, ecological and societal implications of a continuously evolving environmental and socio-technology landscape. To meet this goal, MDes students are expected to:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Master methods of problem-conception and problem-solving at a range of social and ecological scales.</li>
	<li>Hone methods of implementation grounded in the creative practice of design.</li>
	<li>Gain core design skills, in terms of process, materials, craft, and representation.</li>
	<li>Deepen and expand their technical skills in 1-2 emerging technology areas.</li>
	<li>Explicitly consider contexts and impacts of design decisions.</li>
	<li>Use design as a tool for collaboration and team-work.</li>
	<li>Communicate design ideas effectively to diverse collaborators and audiences.</li>
	<li>Weave all of the above together in multiple practice-focused studios.</li>
</ul>
]]>
</programoutcomestext>
<researchresourcestext name="Research Resources">
<![CDATA[
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewNumberedItemContainer">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsItemItem freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextTextItem" data-item-id="1374164640" jsaction="sPvj8e:e4JwSe,Dlbleb;O22p3e:e4JwSe,F0zejc;" jscontroller="rDGJeb" jsname="ibnC6b" role="listitem">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextTextItemContainer">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextLongText freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextDisabledText freebirdThemedInput">As part of enrollment in the program, each MDes student receives a Jacobs Maker Pass for access to Jacobs Hall makerspace and a materials budget each semester to purchase materials from the store at Jacobs Hall. Access to the Fabrication Shop in College for Environmental Design (CED) and to the CITRIS Innovation Lab is also included.</div>
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextLongText freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextDisabledText freebirdThemedInput"> </div>
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextLongText freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextDisabledText freebirdThemedInput">Starting in the second semester of the program, each MDes student is assigned a desk in the MDes studio to support their individual and collaborative work. </div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewNumberedItemContainer">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsItemItem freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextTextItem" data-item-id="131998304" jsaction="sPvj8e:e4JwSe,Dlbleb;O22p3e:e4JwSe,F0zejc;" jscontroller="rDGJeb" jsname="ibnC6b" role="listitem">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsItemItemHeader">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsItemItemTitleDescContainer">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsItemItemTitleContainer"> </div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]>
</researchresourcestext>
<teachingopportunitiestext name="Teaching Opportunities">
<![CDATA[
<p>MDes students may apply for GSI positions, when they are available, for undergraduate design courses offered at The Jacobs Institute for Design Innovation. These teaching opportunities are optional and MDes students are expected to be able to balance GSI responsibilities with their own educational commitments with little difficulty.</p>
]]>
</teachingopportunitiestext>
<professionaldevelopmentactivitiestext name="Professional Development Activities">
<![CDATA[
<p><span style="font-size:1em">MDes students are expected to complete Design@Large, a professional development requirement for the program. Design@Large requires students to engage in an experience outside of an MDes course or studio where they apply what they have learned in a broader context. Design@Large experience typically takes place in the summer between the Spring and Fall semesters and is uniquely defined to align with students’ interests and career goals. </span></p>
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewFormCard exportFormCard">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewFormContent">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemList" role="list">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewNumberedItemContainer">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsItemItem freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextTextItem" data-item-id="1876003589" jsaction="sPvj8e:e4JwSe,Dlbleb;O22p3e:e4JwSe,F0zejc;" jscontroller="rDGJeb" jsname="ibnC6b" role="listitem">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextTextItemContainer">
<div class="freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextLongText freebirdFormviewerViewItemsTextDisabledText freebirdThemedInput">
<p> <br/>
MDes students may satisfy this requirement in the following ways: </p>
<ul>
	<li>Securing an internship</li>
	<li>Having an international experience</li>
	<li>Contributing to a research project</li>
	<li>Launching or contributing to a new start-up or business</li>
	<li>Working in government, service or non-profit organization</li>
</ul>
<p>The MDes Program provides Career Services advising and other resources to aid students in their pursuit of internships or other professional opportunities as part of this requirement. It is each student’s responsibility, however, to define and identify their Design@Large experience.<br/>
 <br/>
MDes students demonstrate the completion of the Design@Large requirement by documenting a project or contribution from their experience in DES INV 219: Capstone Portfolio, a culminating course, required for all MDes students in the last semester of the program.  In this course, students compile a portfolio of work that has been completed during the MDes program, selecting meaningful pieces that demonstrate the achievement of key learning objectives and highlight the underlying themes of their course of study in the program. As part of this documentation, the Capstone Portfolio must also include and reflect on their Design@Large experience. </p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]>
</professionaldevelopmentactivitiestext>
<relatedcoursestext name="Related Courses">
<![CDATA[
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv200" data-toggle="#cb_desinv200">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 200</span> 
<span class="title">Design Frameworks: History &amp; Methods</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv200">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course exposes students to the mindset, skillset and toolset associated with design, and interweaves practical design methods with readings and lectures on the history of design and technology.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Design Frameworks: History &amp; Methods:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="582" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of lecture and 1.5 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One and one-half hours of lecture and one and one-half hours of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Design Frameworks: History &amp; Methods:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv201" data-toggle="#cb_desinv201">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 201</span> 
<span class="title">Debates in Design</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv201">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2022, Fall 2021, Spring 2021<br/>
As today’s most pressing challenges cut across disciplinary boundaries, designers need to articulate new methods for connecting conceptual knowledge with technical skills and develop new ways of integrating ideas from various perspectives and world views. Each year students in this colloquium-style course explore a topic in design. Invited lecturers present a relevant project or challenge from their professional careers at a given intersection</span><span class="deschide"> of critical contemporary issues expressed at a particular scale of design practice. Speakers share background material or readings in advance, allowing students to arrive with thoughtful questions and discussion points. Students compose written reflections throughout and following each speaker.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Debates in Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="176" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit up to a total of 1 time.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 1 hour of colloquium per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of lecture and one hour of colloquium per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Debates in Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv202" data-toggle="#cb_desinv202">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 202</span> 
<span class="title">Technology Design Foundations</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv202">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2022, Fall 2021, Spring 2021<br/>
This course introduces foundational design and technology frameworks and builds skill sets essential to the design of products, services, and experiences enabled by emerging technologies. It follows a human-centered design process that includes research, concept generation, and prototyping, with an emphasis on iteration and refinement. It also develops fluency across a range of core technologies, from fabrication to micro-controllers, and how</span><span class="deschide"> to operationalize them within a design context. These activities are supported by regular practice of design critique. Students engage with a highly technical semester-long project to create a product-service system leveraging both hardware and digital technologies that addresses a well-defined need.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Technology Design Foundations:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="577" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> Students are expected to build fluency in the following skill sets through Technology Design Foundations: <br/>● Iteratively prototyping a range of physical and interactive concepts; <br/>● Validate hypotheses using technical and experiential prototypes, and statistical methods;<br/>● Visually and experientially communicating design concepts to inspire audiences and solicit feedback.<br/>● design ideation; <br/>● establishing empathy for users and stakeholders;<br/>● framing complex problems as actionable design opportunities;</p><p><strong>Student Learning Outcomes:</strong> - Communicate both conceptual and concrete ideas effectively, using a range of visual and verbal presentation techniques<br/>
- Give form to design ideas through prototyping at a range of fidelities, and using a range of materials and tools, including electronics, to convey specific information about a design idea<br/>
- Lead key steps in an iterative and human-centered design process, including conducting research, uncovering insights, generating ideas, and developing and testing prototypes.<br/>
- Work effectively in teams with a toolkit of resources to support productive teamwork<br/>
Upon completing this course, students will be able to:</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with advisor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 2 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of lecture and two hours of studio per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Technology Design Foundations:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv210" data-toggle="#cb_desinv210">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 210</span> 
<span class="title">Studio Foundations</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv210">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Studio Foundations introduces students to the key concepts of a design studio and the foundational principles and methods that inform the ways designers work, collaborate, and practice.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Studio Foundations:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="223" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> This course is only open to students in the first year of the Master of Design (MDes) program. There are no other prerequisites</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of lecture and 1.5-2.5 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two to three hours of lecture and one and one-half to two and one-half hours of studio per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Studio Foundations:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv211" data-toggle="#cb_desinv211">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 211</span> 
<span class="title">Designing Emerging Technologies I</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv211">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course is an intensive, project-based course that focuses on design of interactive artifacts that use emerging technologies. Students are led through a sequence of projects of varying lengths (from one week to three weeks). This serves as the first in a two part sequence of courses (with <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 212">DES INV 212</span>) intended to develop student skills in designing with technology as a material. Projects include both individual and team activities, with</span><span class="deschide"> teams frequently changing in size and composition.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Designing Emerging Technologies I:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="564" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Students must have either completed or be concurrently enrolled in <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 202">DES INV 202</span>: Technology Design Foundations and <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 200">DES INV 200</span>: Design Frameworks</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 3 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and three hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> ERIC PAULOS</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Designing Emerging Technologies I:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv212" data-toggle="#cb_desinv212">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 212</span> 
<span class="title">Designing Emerging Technologies II</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv212">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2022, Spring 2022<br/>
This course is an intensive, project-based course which serves as part of the core required curriculum for students in the Master of Design program. Students are led through a sequence of projects of varying lengths (from one week to one month). The course builds on Designing Emerging Technologies I, and focuses on developing fluency with a different set of technologies. Projects include both individual and team activities, with teams frequently changing</span><span class="deschide"> in size and composition.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Designing Emerging Technologies II:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="695" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 211">DES INV 211</span>: Designing Emerging Technologies I</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of lecture and 1.5 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One and one-half hours of lecture and one and one-half hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Designing Emerging Technologies II:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv213" data-toggle="#cb_desinv213">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 213</span> 
<span class="title">Design Studio</span> 
<span class="hours">5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv213">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022<br/>
In this course you will participate in a hands-on design studio focused on key topics of concern related to design and technology innovation. The primary goal of this course is to orient students to fabrication, building technologies, and fundamental design production skills in a studio environment. A key secondary goal is to provide students the opportunity to address a real world problem and provide an application or solution. Themes and project</span><span class="deschide"> topics, as well as subject matter expertise, are provided by either external partners, including companies, local governmental offices, or nonprofits, or provided by faculty and related to research interests.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Design Studio:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="665" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Students must be concurrently enrolled in <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DES INV 219">DES INV 219</span>: Capstone Portfolio</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 6 hours of studio and 2 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of lecture and six hours of studio per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Design Studio:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv219" data-toggle="#cb_desinv219">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 219</span> 
<span class="title">Capstone Portfolio</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv219">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022<br/>
In this culminating course for the MDes degree, you compile a portfolio of work that has been completed during the MDes program, selecting at least four meaningful pieces that demonstrate the achievement of key learning objectives and highlight the underlying themes of your course of study. Two projects should be deeper investigations of projects done in previous classes. The third project featured should be a deep dive into the project pursued</span><span class="deschide"> in studio. The fourth entry of the portfolio should reflect on Design@Large, an experience you have had outside of an MDes course or studio where you have furthered your design knowledge and expertise within a broader context.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Capstone Portfolio:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="357" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Culminating course taken at the end of the MDes program</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Capstone Portfolio:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_desinv290" data-toggle="#cb_desinv290">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DES INV 290</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Special Topics in Design Innovation</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_desinv290">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Selected advanced topics in design innovation.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Special Topics in Design Innovation:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="441" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Varies by topic. Check syllabus and/or Jacobs Institute website for specific prerequisites</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>7 weeks - 1-8 hours of lecture per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1-8 hours of lecture per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 2-10 hours of lecture per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 2-10 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to four hours of lecture per week or one to eight hours of lecture per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Design Innovation/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Special Topics in Design Innovation:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</relatedcoursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

