<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Critical Theory</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Designated Emphasis (DE) in Critical Theory enables graduate students already enrolled in UC Berkeley PhD programs from across the social sciences, arts, and humanities to obtain certification of a Designated Emphasis specialization in Critical Theory. (The DE is not an independent degree-granting program.) Students admitted to the DE who complete its requirements will receive a parenthetical notation to that effect on their doctoral degrees. The program offers graduate fellowships, hosts international scholars, and presents lectures, seminars, and other events for the wider campus community and local public. Critical Theory also maintains important collaborative relations with other critical theory institutes and programs nationally and internationally.</p>
<p>Critical Theory is often associated with the Frankfurt School, a group of intellectuals who, starting in the 1920s, developed critiques of modern capitalist society, fascism, and the new global dispensations that followed in the aftermath of World War II. In doing so, the Frankfurt School constructed modes of social theory distinct from established forms of philosophy. But key modern concepts of critique had already emerged in various forms in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries in the works of Immanuel Kant, G.W.F. Hegel, Karl Marx, and others. Critique has assumed historically distinct modalities across the twentieth and twenty-first centuries as well.</p>
<p>The Designated Emphasis in Critical Theory offers courses on the nineteenth-century notion of critique; on the Frankfurt School and other twentieth-century currents of critical theory and philosophy; and on contemporary forms and modes of critical theory, including critical race theory, postcolonialist theory, feminist critique, gender studies and queer theory, and the diverse approaches to critique arising with and after structuralism and postructuralism. The program emphasizes the centrality of theoretical critique in the examination of contemporary values, of the power relations that constrain and enable political, social, cultural and economic life, and of the modes of justification that legitimate historical and cultural inquiry and sociopolitical analysis.</p>
<p>The DE student community comprises approximately 100 graduate students enrolled in a wide range of established PhD programs across the humanities and social sciences at UC Berkeley.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>Only students enrolled in PhD programs at Berkeley are eligible to apply for the DE in Critical Theory. Students must apply in the first or second year of graduate study in order to fulfill the requirements of the DE in addition to those of their home departments.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle"><span class="apple-converted-space">Petitions for admission to the DE are accepted each spring for admission to the program. The DE in Critical Theory admits approximately 15 students each year. Petitions and due dates are available on the program’s <a href="http://criticaltheory.berkeley.edu/academics/" target="_blank">website</a>.</span></p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">For further information regarding admission to graduate programs at UC Berkeley, please see the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">Graduate Division's Admissions website</a>.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequirementstext name="Designated Emphasis Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Curriculum/Coursework</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CRIT TH 200">CRIT TH 200</span></td><td>Critique in 19th-Century Thought</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CRIT TH 205">CRIT TH 205</span></td><td>The Classical Frankfurt School: The First Generation of Critical Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CRIT TH 240">CRIT TH 240</span></td><td>Contemporary Critique and Critical Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Two Electives, selected from a list of courses offered by DE faculty, including <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CRIT TH 290">CRIT TH 290</span></span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Qualifying Exam</h3>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">One of the members of the student’s qualifying examination committee must represent the DE in Critical Theory and be a member of the DE’s designated faculty. These faculty members may be outside or inside members of the student’s committees.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Dissertation</h3>
<p>One of the members of the student’s qualifying dissertation committee must represent the DE in Critical Theory and be a member of the DE’s designated faculty. These faculty members may be outside or inside members of the student’s committees.</p>
<h3>Degree Conferral</h3>
<p>Upon successful completion of the dissertation, the student’s transcript will include the designation: “PhD in [major] with a Designated Emphasis in Critical Theory.” This designation certifies that a candidate has participated in, and successfully completed, a Designated Emphasis in Critical Theory in addition to all departmental requirements for the doctorate.</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequirementstext>
<researchresourcestext name="Research Resources">
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">A full annual calendar of lectures, colloquia, and conferences contributes to Critical Theory’s rich research environment. The ongoing participation of international visiting scholars and researchers as well as student-led working and writing groups facilitate dialogue and build community across academic disciplines.</p>
<p>With adequate funding, the Program in Critical Theory awards yearly dissertation fellowships to Critical Theory DE students with records of achievement and promising dissertation projects. The annual fellowships are open to Critical Theory students in UC Berkeley departments including <span style="font-size:1em">African American Studies, Ancient Greek &amp; Roman Studies, Anthropology, Berkeley Law, Comparative Literature, East Asian Languages and Cultures, Energy &amp; Resources Group, English, Ethnic Studies, Film &amp; Media, French, Gender &amp; Women’s Studies, German, Geography, History, History of Art, Italian, Medical Anthropology, Music, Philosophy, Political Science, Rhetoric, School of Education, School of Public Health, Sociology, South &amp; Southeast Asian Studies, Slavic Languages and Literature, Spanish &amp; Portuguese, and Theater, Dance and Performance Studies. </span></p>
<p>The fellowships support students writing their dissertations, providing full fee remission (where required) and a full stipend, usually for a semester. Other research grants of shorter term (including summer) may also be awarded, as resources permit.</p>
]]>
</researchresourcestext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Critical Theory</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_critth200" data-toggle="#cb_critth200">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CRIT TH 200</span> 
<span class="title">Critique in 19th-Century Thought</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_critth200">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Fall 2015<br/>
This course will examine various formulations of critique in 19th-century theory. Thinkers who may be studied include Kant, Hegel, Marx, Nietzsche, and Weber, though the selection will vary by instructor. This is the &quot;foundations&quot; course for the Designated Emphasis in Critical Theory.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Critique in 19th-Century Thought:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="464" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the critical theory designated emphasis or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two to three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Brown</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Critique in 19th-Century Thought:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_critth205" data-toggle="#cb_critth205">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CRIT TH 205</span> 
<span class="title">The Classical Frankfurt School: The First Generation of Critical Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_critth205">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2015, Spring 2015<br/>
This course will explore the founding texts of the Frankfurt School's first generation: Horkheimer, Adorno, Benjamin, Marcuse, Lowenthal, and their circle. It will follow the development of critical theory through its Weimar years, American exile, and return to postwar Germany.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Classical Frankfurt School: The First Generation of Critical Theory:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="106" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the critical theory designated emphasis or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Jay</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Classical Frankfurt School: The First Generation of Critical Theory:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_critth240" data-toggle="#cb_critth240">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CRIT TH 240</span> 
<span class="title">Contemporary Critique and Critical Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_critth240">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2017, Fall 2016, Spring 2016<br/>
This course will explore various contemporary engagements with the foundations of critical theory in relation to other histories and locations. Topics will vary by instructor but may include: post-continental political theory, critique and the problem of political dissent and citizenship, gender and race in relation to critical practices, psychoanalysis, and literary and art theory and criticism.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Contemporary Critique and Critical Theory:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="567" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the critical theory designated emphasis or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Contemporary Critique and Critical Theory:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_critth290" data-toggle="#cb_critth290">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CRIT TH 290</span> 
<span class="title">Critical Theory Elective</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_critth290">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Critical Theory electives are taught by core and affiliated faculty in the Critical Theory program and offer important treatments of theoretical materials significant to the intellectual traditions of the program's course of study in nineteenth-century social theory and philosophy, Frankfurt School and related currents in theory and criticism, and contemporary critical theory. In a typical Critical Theory elective, theoretical materials are presented</span><span class="deschide"> in dialogue with an anthropological, artistic/aesthetic, economic, educational, historical, philosophical, political, rhetorical, sociological, or other disciplinary matrix that constitutes the course's primary materials for study and inquiry.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Critical Theory Elective:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="712" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the Critical Theory Designated Emphasis or consent of the instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two to three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Critical Theory Elective:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_critth298" data-toggle="#cb_critth298">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CRIT TH 298</span> 
<span class="title">Critical Theory Special Study</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_critth298">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Advanced study in interpretive approaches within the field of critical theory, focusing on the question of how critical theory enters into the framing of a long-term research project. We will consider the status and limits of theory, the relation between literary and social theory, reading practices, and archival research.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Critical Theory Special Study:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="470" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the Critical Theory Designated Emphasis or consent of the instructor. This course is intended for graduate students who are working on their prospectus or dissertation</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Butler</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Critical Theory Special Study:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>* Elizabeth Abel, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, psychoanalysis, Virginia Woolf, race and gender.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14359"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rakesh Bhandari, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>Classical Social Theory's Images of Asia, The Juridical Aspects of Unfree Labor Relations, The Role of Luxury Consumption in Economic Growth, The Nature and Limits of Keynesian Intervention, The Discourses of Social Darwinism.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dan Blanton, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Modernism, modern poetry, 19th- and 20th-century British literature, aesthetic and critical theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14448"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Natalia Brizuela, <i>Professor Spanish &amp; Portuguese, Film &amp; Media</i>. </strong>Spanish & Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14472"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Julia Q. Bryan-Wilson, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Contemporary art, feminist theory, queer theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16915"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Michael Burawoy, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Sociology, Russia, capitalism, industrial workplaces, postcolonialism, socialism, global ethnography, Hungary.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14401"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anthony J. Cascardi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English, comparative literature, literature, Spanish, Portuguese, philosophy, aesthetics, early modern literature, French, Spanish Baroque.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14481"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sharad Chari, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Geography as history of the present and as Earth/world-writing, social theory, political economy, development, agrarian studies, labor and work, racial/sexual capitalism, Black radical tradition, biopolitical struggle, oceanic humanities, photography, South Asia, South Africa, Indian Ocean .<br/><a href="http://geography.berkeley.edu/people/regular-faculty/sharad-chari/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lawrence Cohen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Social cultural anthropology, medical and psychiatric anthropology, critical gerontology, lesbian and gay studies, feminist and queer theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14619"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stephen Collier, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Soviet urban planning and post-Soviet urban and social welfare transformation, infrastructure and politics, neoliberalism and governmental rationality, emergency government in the United States, urban vulnerability and resilience, climate change.<br/><a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/faculty-staff/stephen-colllier"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eglantine L. Colon, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>French.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marianne Constable, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Law and language, legal rhetoric and philosophy, social and political thought, Anglo-American legal history, Continental philosophy, law and society.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14502"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Raul Coronado, <i>Associate Professor of Chicano/Latino Studies &amp; Comparative Ethnic Studies</i>. </strong>Ethnic Studies.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Whitney Davis, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ancient art, Modern Art, art theory.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/whitney-davis"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ivonne Del Valle, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Colonial period in Mexico, internal colonialism in Mexico, Jesuits (Loyola, Acosta, Baegert), Baroque and Enlightenment from a colonial perspective, technology and environment, drainage of Mexico City lakes, Christianity and Pre-Hispanic religions .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15015"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary Ann Doane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, semiotics, cinema, media, cultural theory, archaeology of media technology, poststructuralism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14326"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Samera Esmeir, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, Middle Eastern Studies, Legal and political thought, law and society, legal histories, colonialism and post-colonialism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14641"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Karen Feldman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, aesthetics, literary theory, Kant, Nietzsche, Heidegger, Arendt, Benjamin, 18th-20th century German thought, Hegel, Adorno.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14663"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Keith Feldman, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, US cultural studies, Israel-Palestine, theories of race and ethnicity, comparative diaspora studies, public humanities.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14662"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Catherine Flynn, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Modernism, Irish, British, comparative literature, critical theory, Avant-Gardes, James Joyce, Flann O'Brien.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16352"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anne-Lise FranÃ§ois, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Popular culture, English, comparative literature, the modern period, comparative romanticisms, lyric poetry, the psychological novel, novel of manners, gender, critical theory, literature, philosophy, fashion.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14682"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Deniz Gokturk, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>German literature, German cinema, transnational cinemas, German-Turkish-European-American intersections in cinema, performance and spectatorship and reception, intertextuality and intermediality and translation, the politics and poetics of migration and globalization, urban imaginaries and mediations of place, theories of diversity and nationalism, comedy and community, modern rituals of regulating identity and authority and mobility.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14723"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Amanda Goldstein, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Enlightenment and Romantic literature and science, with particular interests in rhetoric and poetics, pre-Darwinian biology, and materialist theories of history, poetry, and nature .<br/><a href="https://english.berkeley.edu/profiles/458"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marcial Gonzalez, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chicano and Chicana literature, twentieth-century American ethnic literatures, theory of the novel, marxism, critical theory, farm worker social movements.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14730"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Singh Grewal, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Legal and political theory, intellectual history, intellectual property law and biotechnology.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/david-singh-grewal"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jocelyne Guilbault, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cultural politics, Caribbean, popular and traditional musics, nation, diaspora, cultural entrepreneurship.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14758"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles Hirschkind, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Islam, anthropology, religious practice, media technologies, political community, Middle East, Europe.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14849"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stefan-Ludwig Hoffmann, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Modern German and European History, Human Rights and Internationalism, global urban history, critical theory.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/stefan-ludwig-hoffmann"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Seth M. Holmes, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Immigration and migration, medical anthropology with foci on social theory and ethnography, social studies of medicine and science, social difference related to race, social difference related to socioeconomic status, social difference related to citizenship, social difference related to gender, social difference related to sexuality, the naturalization and normalization of social hierarchies and health disparities, social suffering and symbolic violence, urban and rural Latin America and North America, population health with focus on global health, population health with focus on health disparities, population health with focus on social determinants of health.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14857"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Shannon Jackson, <i>Professor and Associate Vice Chancellor for Arts + Design</i>. </strong>Rhetoric, performance studies, American studies, 20th century art movements and critical theory, local culture and intercultural citizenship in turn-of-the-century United States, history and theory of theatre and performance art.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14883"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Abdul R. JanMohamed, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, theory of subjection, postcolonial literature, culture, and theory, African American fiction, and minority discourse .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14888"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Donna V. Jones, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, English, modernism, literature and philosophy, literature of the Americas, literature of the African Diaspora, postcolonial literature and theory, narrative and historiography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14901"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Tony Kaes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Film studies, modern literature, literary and cultural theory, cinema, interdisciplinary and comparative aspects of Weimar culture, contemporary literature and film, literary theory, theory of cultural studies, film history, film theory, history of cinema.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14903"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Robert G. Kaufman, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Modern/contemporary poetry and poetics, aesthetics, literary theory, and history of criticism, Frankfurt School Critical Theory and the arts.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16865"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Celeste Langan, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>English, romantic poetry, 19th century literature, Wordsworth, Carlyle, Hardy, Rousseau, the French Revolution, Marxist theory, literature and the social sciences.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14947"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Niklaus Largier, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Religion, literature, German, history of medieval and early modern German literature, theology, mysticism, secularism, senses, sensuality, history of emotions, passions, asceticism, flagellation, sexuality.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14949"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Grace Lavery, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, gender and sexuality studies, Pacific, 19th century British literature, cultural studies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/grace-lavery"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Zeus Leonardo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ideologies and discourses in education, education.<br/><a href="https://gse.berkeley.edu/people/zeus-leonardo"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Lucey, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Pragmatics, the novel, sexuality studies, comparative literature, French, French literature, nineteenth and twentieth centuries, British literature and culture, social and literary theory, cultural studies of music, studies of language in use, theories of practice, twentieth-century American literature .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15326"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Colleen Lye, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Postcolonial theory, critical theory, cultural studies, Asian American literature, 20th and 21st century literature, world literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15079"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Salar Mameni, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Art, aesthetics and visual culture, transnational feminist and queer of color theories, Arab diaspora, Muslim diaspora, militarism, critical race theory, critical postcolonial theory, Anthropocene, extractive economies and petrocultures.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sara-mameni"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Tom McEnaney, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Latin American literature of the 19th and 20th centuries, media studies, radio, 20th century American literature, architecture, linguistic anthropology, digital humanities.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/tom-mcenaney"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ramsey McGlazer, <i>Assistant Professor, Comparative Literature</i>. </strong>European and Latin American literature, film, and critical theory.<br/><a href="https://complit.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/ramsey-mcglazer"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ramona Naddaff, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Rhetoric, aesthetics, theory of the novel, ancient Greek philosophy and literature, history of philosophy, contemporary French thought.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15161"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alva Noe, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cognitive science, phenomenology, consciousness, philosophy, theory of perception, theory of art, Wittgenstein, analytic philosophy origins.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14049"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maura Bridget Nolan, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chaucer, drama, Middle English literature, Gower, Lydgate, medieval, 16th century, literary form, style.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15183"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andreja Novakovic, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>19th and 20th century continental philosophy, G.W.F. Hegel.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fumi Okiji, <i>Assistant Professor </i>. </strong>Black study, Frankfurt School Critical Theory, sound and music studies, black feminist theory.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/fumi-okiji"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stefania Pandolfo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cultural anthropology, Islam, Middle East, theories of subjectivity, postcolonial criticism, anthropology and literature, the Maghreb, mental illness.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15216"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Diego Pirillo, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Renaissance Europe, History of Books and Reading, history of political thought, History of Historiography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16367"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Djordje Popovic, <i>Assistant Professor </i>. </strong>Yugoslav and post-Yugoslav literature, critical theory, comparative literature.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/djordje-popovic"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Porter, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Classical Studies, philosophy, critical theory, aesthetics, Nietzsche, Auerbach.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16925"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Harsha Ram, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Slavic Languages and Literatures and Comparative Literature.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/harsha-ram"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dylan John Riley, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Political sociology, comparative historical sociology, social theory.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/dylan-john-riley"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Juana Maria Rodriguez, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Sexual politics, LGBTQ communities, Latino issues, women of color feminisms, ethnic studies, queer activism, transgender studies, queer kinship.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/juana-maria-rodriguez"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Poulomi Saha, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Asian American, South Asian, critical theory, gender and sexuality, cultural studies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/poulomi-saha"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leslie Salzinger, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Political economy, feminist theory, finance, sociology of gender, Gender and Work, gendering of transnational processes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15303"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Debarati Sanyal, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Violence, poetry, the relationship between literary form, politics in 19th-century France, the connection between performance, performativity, ethics in modernist texts.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15407"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hans Sluga, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Political philosophy, recent European philosophy, history of analytic philosophy, Frege, Wittgenstein, Foucault.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15462"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barbara Spackman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, psychoanalysis, culture, fascism, gender studies, comparative literature, Italian studies, narrative, European decadence, travel writing.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15481"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eric Stanley, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Critical prison studies, queer/trans social movements, anti-colonial feminism.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/eric-stanley"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mario Telo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Greek literature, Roman drama, critical theory.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/mario-telo"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Soraya Tlatli, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Francophone literature, colonial and postcolonial studies, literature and psychoanalysis, twentieth-century continental philosophy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15547"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher Lawrence Tomlins, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Legal history and the history and law of slavery.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/christopher-tomlins"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sarah Vaughn, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Cultural anthropology, post-colonial science, environment, climate change, vulnerability, theories of liberalism, Caribbean, Latin America.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sarah-e-vaughn"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leti Volpp, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Citizenship, law and culture, identity (especially race and gender), immigration and migration, Asian American studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15584"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Loic Wacquant, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Sociology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15588"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nathaniel Wolfson, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Spanish & Portuguese.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/nathaniel-wolfson"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Damon R. Young, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>French and Film/Media.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/damon-young"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nasser Zakariya, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Rhetoric.</p><h4>Emeritus</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Martin Jay, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>History.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles F. Altieri, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Literature and the visual arts, Wittgenstein, Modern American poetry, Contemporary American poetry, history of aesthetic philosophy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14582"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Wendy L. Brown, <i>Professor Emerite</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, critical theory, theories of neoliberalism, public higher education, nineteenth and twentieth century political theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14600"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Judith Butler, <i>Professor Emerite</i>. </strong>Critical theory, gender and sexuality studies, comparative literature, 19th and 20th century continental philosophy, social and political thought, philosophy and literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/judith-butler"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Suzanne Guerlac, <i>Professor Emerita</i>. </strong>Nationalism, literature, philosophy, 19th- and 20th-century literature, myths of literature and theory, contemporary cultural criticism.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gillian P. Hart, <i>Professor Emerita</i>. </strong>Geography.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Francine R. Masiello, <i>Professor Emerita</i>. </strong>Gender theory, culture, globalization, comparative literature, Spanish, Latin American literature of the 19th and 20th centuries, comparative North and South literatures.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15332"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

