<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>College of Environmental Design</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Introduction to the College</h2>
<p>The College of Environmental Design (CED) is UC Berkeley’s home for environmental design theory, research, innovation, and practice. CED stands among the nation’s top environmental design and planning schools. It is one of the world’s most distinguished laboratories for experimentation, research, and intellectual synergy. CED offers undergraduate degrees in architecture, urban studies, landscape architecture, and sustainable environmental design. All departments offer undergraduate minor programs open to students majoring in other fields.</p>
<p>The mission of CED is to educate diverse students to critically analyze the built environment, preparing them to craft buildings, cities, and landscapes that are ecologically sustainable and resilient; prosperous and fair; healthy and beautiful.</p>
<p><span class="m_-1813168428243533000gmail-">The College trains students in </span>rigorous research and analytic methods, as well as the art of designing memorable, well-loved places that both nurture the senses and challenge the imagination. CED helps students acquire technical expertise and develop transcendent ways of seeing and re-figuring the built environment.</p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/?filter_3=true">Explore majors, minors, and certificates</a> available through the College of Environmental Design.</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<ucandcampusrequirementstext name="UC and Campus Requirements">
<![CDATA[
 <h3>University of California Requirements</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">Entry Level Writing</a></p> <p>All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by satisfying the Entry Level Writing Requirement (ELWR). <span style="font-size:1em">The </span><a href="https://admission.universityofcalifornia.edu/elwr/requirements/test-scores-grades.html" style="font-size: 1em;">UC Entry Level Writing Requirement website</a><span style="font-size:1em"> provides information on how to satisfy the requirement</span></p> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American History and American Institutions</a></p> <p>The American History and Institutions (AH&amp;I) requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</p> <h3>Campus Requirement</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American Cultures</a></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c47924ad-7fff-1b30-99f8-3c345cb2b997">The American Cultures requirement is a Berkeley campus requirement, one that all undergraduate students at Berkeley need to pass in order to graduate. You satisfy the requirement by passing, with a grade not lower than C- or P, an American Cultures course. You may take an American Cultures course any time during your undergraduate career at Berkeley. The requirement was instituted in 1991 to introduce students to the diverse cultures of the United States through a comparative framework. Courses are offered in more than fifty departments in many different disciplines at both the lower and upper division level.</span></p> <div> </div>
]]>
</ucandcampusrequirementstext>
<collegerequirementstext name="College Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Summary of College and University Requirements</h3>
<ul>
	<li>Entry Level Writing</li>
	<li>American History and Institutions</li>
	<li>American Cultures</li>
	<li>Reading and Composition</li>
	<li>Seven Course Breadth</li>
	<li>Lower Division Environmental Design (2 courses)</li>
	<li>Upper Division Environmental Design (3 courses)</li>
</ul>
<h3>University of California Requirements<br/>
 </h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/entry-level-writing-requirement/">Entry Level Writing</a></p>
<p>All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by satisfying the Entry Level Writing Requirement. satisfaction of this requirement is also a prerequisite to enrollment in all reading and composition courses at UC Berkeley. </p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/american-history-american-institutions-requirements/">American History and American Institutions</a></p>
<p>The American History and Institutions requirements are based on the principle that a U.S. resident graduated from an American university should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</p>
<h3>Campus Requirement</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/american-cultures-requirement/">American Cultures</a></p>
<p>American Cultures (AC) is the one requirement that all undergraduate students at UC Berkeley need to take and pass in order to graduate. The requirement offers an exciting intellectual environment centered on the study of race, ethnicity and culture of the United States. AC courses offer students opportunities to be part of research-led, highly accomplished teaching environments, grappling with the complexity of American Culture.</p>
<h3>College Requirements</h3>
<h4><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/reading-composition-requirement/">Reading and Composition</a></h4>
<p>In order to provide a solid foundation in reading, writing, and critical thinking, the College requires two semesters of lower division work in composition. Students must complete a first-level reading and composition course by the end of their second semester and a second-level course by the end of their fourth semester. CED students admitted to UCB as freshmen must complete the first half of the R&amp;C requirement at Berkeley.</p>
<h4><span>Seven Course Breadth</span></h4>
<p><span class="s1">Please see <span class="s2"><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/#breadthrequirementstextcontainer" target="_blank">College of Letters &amp; Science Seven-Course Breadth Requirement</a> for detailed instructions on satisfying these requirements</span>. </span><span>Guidelines include the following:</span></p>
<ol>
	<li>Up to two CED courses or courses cross-listed with CED may be used to complete Seven-Course Breadth (students admitted to UCB Fall 2013 and later only).</li>
	<li>Only lower division ENV DES courses (<span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENV DES 1">ENV DES 1</span></span>, <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENV DES 5">ENV DES 5</span></span>) and lower division major requirements may simultaneously satisfy Seven-Course Breadth. A course used to satisfy either an upper division major requirement or the upper division CED outside of architecture requirement may not also satisfy Seven Course Breadth. Upper division CED courses that are not satisfying another upper division requirement may satisfy Seven-Course Breadth.</li>
	<li>No more than two courses from any one academic department may be used to satisfy breadth requirements.</li>
	<li>A Seven-Course Breadth class that is also being used to complete another CED requirement must be completed with a letter grade of C- or better.</li>
	<li>Only one of the remaining Seven-Course Breadth may be taken on a Passed/Not Passed basis.</li>
	<li>The International Studies breadth requirement may be satisfied by participation in the UC Education Abroad Program or a recognized equivalent program.</li>
	<li>CED students may apply high school exam credit (Advanced Placement, International Baccalaureate, A-Level Exam) towards many of the above requirements. See the CED website section on High School Exam Credit for more information: <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/forms-documents/" target="_blank">http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/forms-documents/</a></li>
</ol>
<h4>Lower Division Major Requirements that May be Used to Simultaneously satisfy Seven Course Breadth Requirement</h4>
<h5>Architecture Majors</h5>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Physical Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 7A">PHYSICS 7A</span></div></td><td>Physics for Scientists and Engineers [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 8A">PHYSICS 8A</span></div></td><td>Introductory Physics [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h5>Landscape Architecture Majors</h5>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Biological Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Approved biological science courses (see major handbook) can also be used to satisfy biological science breadth requirements. Consult a CED advisor for more information.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Physical Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Approved physical science courses (see major handbook) can also be used to satisfy physical science breadth requirements. Consult a CED advisor for more information.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h5>Sustainable Environmental Design Majors</h5>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Biological Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LD ARCH 12">LD ARCH 12</span></div></td><td>Environmental Science for Sustainable Development [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Physical Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 7A">PHYSICS 7A</span></div></td><td>Physics for Scientists and Engineers [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 8A">PHYSICS 8A</span></div></td><td>Introductory Physics [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Social &amp; Behavioral Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON C3">ECON C3</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Environmental Economics and Policy [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENVECON C1">ENVECON C1</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Environmental Economics and Policy [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">(<span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 1">ECON 1</span> or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 2">2</span>: permission needed from SED Advisor)</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h5>Urban Studies Majors</h5>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Social &amp; Behavioral Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 1">ECON 1</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Economics [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 2">ECON 2</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Economics--Lecture Format [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON C3">ECON C3</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Environmental Economics and Policy [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENVECON C1">ENVECON C1</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Environmental Economics and Policy [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Urban Studies Lower Division Major Electives</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Lower Divison Major Electives (see major handbook) can also be used to satisfy breadth requirements. Consult a CED advisor for more information. </span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h5><strong>Lower Division Environmental Design (Two Courses Required) *</strong></h5>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENV DES 1">ENV DES 1</span></td><td>Introduction to Environmental Design</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENV DES 5">ENV DES 5</span></td><td>Cities and Sites</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<dl class="sc_footnotes" aria-label="Footnotes"><dt>*</dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent">These requirements apply to all students admitted to Berkeley as freshmen, including students admitted to other colleges at UC Berkeley who enter CED through the Change of College process. Transfer students are exempt from this requirement.</p></dd></dl>
<p>Guidelines for lower division Environmental Design courses:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Must be completed with a letter grade of C- or better.</li>
	<li>Any of the courses used to satisfy this requirement may simultaneously satisfy the Seven Course Breadth Requirement. However, no more than two CED courses (or courses cross-listed with CED courses) may be used to complete Seven Course Breadth.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Upper Division Environmental Design (Three Courses Required)</h4>
<ol>
	<li>Three upper division CED courses from departments outside the major (minimum of 9 units).</li>
	<li>Must be completed with a letter grade of C- or better.</li>
	<li>Each of the three courses must be at least 2 units and must be within the 100-299 course range (excluding 197, 198, and 199).</li>
	<li>Depending on the major, this requirement may be satisfied with courses in Architecture, Environmental Design, Visual Studies, Landscape Architecture, and City and Regional Planning.</li>
	<li>A course used to satisfy this requirement may not also be used to satisfy Seven Course Breadth or major requirements.</li>
</ol>
<h4>High School Exam Credit</h4>
<p>CED students may apply high school exam credit (Advanced Placement, International Baccalaureate, A-Level Exam) towards many College and Major Requirements. Please see the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/forms-documents/" target="_blank">High School Exam Credit section on the CED website</a> for more information.</p>
<h3>Semester Limit</h3>
<p>Students admitted as freshmen must graduate within eight fall/spring semesters at UC Berkeley. Students admitted as transfer students must graduate within four fall/spring semesters at UC Berkeley. EAP and UCDC count towards this semester limit; summer session, UC Extension, and study abroad through non-UC programs do not. Students approved for simultaneous degrees in two colleges may be granted an additional semester. CED does not limit the number of total units a student can accrue.</p>
<h3>Grade Requirements</h3>
<ul>
	<li>A 2.0 UC GPA is required for graduation.</li>
	<li>A 2.0 GPA within the major is required at time of graduation.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Graduating With Honors</h3>
<p>To graduate with distinction, students must meet the grade point average (GPA) requirement and complete at least 50 units in residence at Berkeley (this may include UCB Extension XB units and up to 20 units from UCDC or EAP), of which 43 units must be letter-graded (not including physical education activities courses). <em>Transfer students must make sure they complete 50 units at Berkeley to qualify for honors.</em></p>
<p>Students' GPA in all letter-graded courses taken at Berkeley must be equal to or higher than the GPA established for honors in the year in which they graduate. These GPA cut-offs change slightly each year and are posted on the CED website.</p>
<h3>Unit Requirements</h3>
<p>Students must complete at least 120 semester units of courses subject to certain guidelines:</p>
<ul>
	<li>A maximum of 16 units of Special Studies coursework (courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, or 199) is allowed towards the 120 units; a maximum of four is allowed in a given semester; only upper division students (60 or more units completed) may enroll in 197, 198, or 199 coursework.</li>
	<li>A maximum of 4 units of Physical Education from any school attended will count towards the 120 units.</li>
	<li>Students may receive unit credit for courses graded P (including P/NP units taken through EAP) up to a limit of one-third of the total units taken and passed on the Berkeley campus at the time of graduation.</li>
	<li>No more than 60 units from a single department can be used towards the 120 minimum.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Semester Unit Minimum</h4>
<p>All CED students must enroll in at least 12 units each fall and spring semester. (Students entering UC Berkeley as freshmen with no prior units need to complete 15 units per semester to graduate in four years.)</p>
<h4>Semester Unit Maximum</h4>
<p>To request permission to take more than 20.5 units in a semester, please see the major advisor.</p>
<h4>Senior Residence Requirement</h4>
<p>After reaching senior status (90 semester units earned), students must be registered in the College of Environmental Design and must complete at least 24 of the remaining 30 units in at least two semesters in residence at UC Berkeley as CED students. To count as residence, a semester must consist of at least six passed units.</p>
<p>Students may use Berkeley Summer Sessions to satisfy one semester of the Senior Residence Requirement, provided that six units of coursework are completed. Units completed through UC Berkeley “W” web-based courses do apply towards Senior Residence.</p>
<p><em>Excluded from Senior Residence:</em> Inter-campus Visitor Program, Education Abroad Program (UCEAP), UC Berkeley Washington Program (UCDC), Berkeley Summer Sessions completed abroad, UC Berkeley Extension units (X and XB), and non-UC Berkeley online classes.</p>
<h4>Modified Senior Residence Requirement</h4>
<p>Participants in the UC Berkeley-Washington Program (UCDC); a fall, spring or summer UC Education Abroad Program (UCEAP); Berkeley Summer Abroad; or the Berkeley Global Internship program may meet the Modified Senior Residence Requirement by completing 24 of their final 60 semester units(excluding EAP or UC Extension) in residence. Note that these programs must consist of at least six passed units to meet the requirement. At least 12 of the 24 units must be completed after senior status (90 units) is reached.</p>
<p>Most students automatically satisfy the residence requirement by attending classes here for four years (two years for transfer students). In general, there is no need to be concerned about this requirement, unless students go abroad for a semester or year or want to take courses at another institution or through University Extension during their senior year. In these cases, students should make an appointment to see an advisor to determine how they can meet the Senior Residence Requirement.</p>
<h4>Fulfilling Requirements with Transfer Coursework </h4>
<p>Students may use transfer work, including courses taken via Study Abroad, to fulfill CED requirements, within the following limits (please consult your major advisor for more information):</p>
<ul>
	<li>Upper Division Major Requirements: Up to two courses taken elsewhere may be applied, if deemed transferable by the UC Berkeley <a href="https://ceu.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Central Evaluation Unit</a> and approved by the faculty advisor for your major.</li>
	<li>Upper Division CED Outside the Major: Up to two courses taken elsewhere may be applied, if deemed transferable by the UC Berkeley <a href="https://ceu.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Central Evaluation Unit</a>  and approved by the college.</li>
	<li>Upper Division CED Minor Requirements: Up to two courses taken elsewhere may be applied, if deemed transferable by the UC Berkeley <a href="https://ceu.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Central Evaluation Unit</a>  and approved by the faculty advisor for your minor.</li>
	<li>CED Breadth Requirements: All requirements can be potentially fulfilled by courses taken elsewhere, if deemed transferable by the UC Berkeley <a href="https://ceu.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Central Evaluation Unit</a>  and approved for breadth by the college (courses must be at least three units each).</li>
</ul>
<p>To submit a request, please refer to the CED Forms &amp; Documents page and complete the form located under Transfer Credit Evaluation: &quot;CED Course Substitution Process-Current Students (Including Study Abroad).&quot;</p>
<h4>Concurrent Enrollment </h4>
<p>Concurrent enrollment for enrolled Berkeley students is defined as a student being enrolled in courses at UC Berkeley during a Fall or Spring semester, while also being enrolled in courses at another school such as a California community college. Students who wish to take courses concurrently must seek approval from CED Advising <strong>four weeks prior to the first day of instruction</strong>. Students who do not have approval from CED Advising will not be approved to post transferable units to their UC Berkeley academic transcript. Only summer session enrollment does not require approval from CED Advising.</p>
]]>
</collegerequirementstext>
<choosingamajortext name="Choosing a Major">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>Students must declare one of the CED majors at the time of application to the College. Even if students are certain about which major they wish to pursue, they can still benefit from doing some research about the content of the programs before applying:</span></p>
<ul>
	<li>Come to a prospective student information session. For information regarding these sessions, please see the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/events-media/events/" target="_blank">CED schedule of events on the CED website</a>. </li>
	<li>Talk with a CED advisor to clarify the nature of the major and the types of skills and coursework required.</li>
	<li>If possible, visit the campus, attend some classes, including upper-division courses. Talk to students, faculty, and graduate student instructors (GSI’s).</li>
</ul>
<h3>Admission to Berkeley and the College of Environmental Design</h3>
<p>For more information regarding admission, please see the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/admissions/undergraduate/" target="_blank">College of Environmental Design website</a>.</p>
<h3><span>Admission as a Transfer Applicant</span></h3>
<p>Transfer applicants must complete two years worth of lower division coursework to be considered for admission to CED. See the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/admissions/undergraduate/transfer-applicants/" target="_blank">CED website</a> for detailed information about admission criteria.</p>
<h3><span>CED Admissions Ambassadors</span></h3>
<p>Students are invited to meet with a CED admissions ambassador—a current undergraduate who can talk about what life is like at CED and at UC Berkeley.</p>
<p>To personalize visits to Bauer Wurster Hall, CED offers the following:</p>
<ul>
	<li><span>Tours of Bauer Wurster Hall</span></li>
	<li><span>Student panel discussions about the CED student experience</span></li>
	<li>Presentations about CED</li>
	<li>One-on-one conversations with ambassador(s)</li>
	<li>Webinars, online chats, and email exchanges with ambassador(s)</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information regarding Admissions Ambassadors, please see the <a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/admissions/undergraduate/admissions-ambassadors/" target="_blank">CED website</a>.</p>
<h3>Changing Colleges or Majors</h3>
<p><span>Current UC Berkeley students may apply to change into the College of Environmental Design if they:</span></p>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><span>Apply by the deadline set for their intended CED major. See the Change of College petition for each major on the <a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/students/undergraduate-advising/forms-documents" target="_blank">CED Forms and Documents</a> page.</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span>Have completed at least one semester of coursework at UC Berkeley</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span>Have completed the required lower division courses outlined in the Change of College petition for their desired major</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span>Are able to complete their degree within CED’s semester limit</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span>Have a grade point average (GPA) of 2.0 or above.</span></p>
	</li>
</ul>
<p><span>Download the Change of College application <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/forms-documents" target="_blank">here</a>.</span></p>
]]>
</choosingamajortext>
<advisingtext name="Advising">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>The CED Office of Undergraduate Advising provides a wide array of programmatic and individual advising services to prospective and current students as well as to students in other colleges who are pursuing CED minors or taking CED courses. The professional advising team assists students with a range of issues including course selection, academic decision-making, achieving personal and academic goals, and maximizing the Berkeley experience.</span></p>
<h3>Advising Staff</h3>
<p><strong>Architecture Major Adviser:</strong> Mel Barbers<br/>
250 Bauer Wurster Hall, <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/mailto:mbarbers@berkeley.edu">mbarbers@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<p><span><strong>Landscape Architecture Major Adviser:</strong> Kristian Dawson<br/>
250 </span>Bauer<span> Wurster Hall, </span><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/mailto:kristian.dawson@berkeley.edu">kristian.dawson@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<p><span><strong>Sustainable Environmental Design and College Evaluator:</strong> </span>Heather Grothjan<br/>
<span>250 </span>Bauer<span> Wurster Hall,</span> <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/mailto:heather.grothjan@berkeley.edu">heather.grothjan@berkeley.edu</a><span>,</span></p>
<p><span><strong>Urban Studies Major Adviser:</strong> </span>Kristian Dawson<br/>
250 Bauer Wurster Hall, <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/mailto:kristian.dawson@berkeley.edu">kristian.dawson@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<p><span><strong>Director, Undergraduate Advising:</strong> Omar Ramirez<br/>
250 </span>Bauer<span> Wurster Hall,</span> <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/mailto:oramirez@berkeley.edu">oramirez@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<p><strong>Associate Dean for Undergraduate Studies: </strong>Kyle Steinfeld<br/>
345 Bauer Wurster Hall, <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/mailto:ksteinfe@berkeley.edu">ksteinfe@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<h4>Undergraduate Advising Office Hours</h4>
<p><strong>Fall/Spring:</strong> Monday through Friday, 10 to noon; 1 to 4 p.m. (Office opens at 9 a.m.)<br/>
<strong>Summer: </strong>Monday through Friday, 10 to noon; 1 to 3 p.m.</p>
<h4>Address</h4>
<p>Office of Undergraduate Advising<br/>
College of Environmental Design<br/>
250 Bauer Wurster Hall #1800<br/>
University of California<br/>
Berkeley, CA 94720-1800</p>
<h4>Email Address</h4>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/environmental-design/mailto: cedadvising@berkeley.edu">cedadvising@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<h3>CED Career Services</h3>
<p>The CED Career Services Center (CSC) offers personalized career counseling, a yearly CED Career Fair, and a wide variety of professional-development workshops on topics such as licensure, internships, and applying for graduate school. For further information or to schedule an appointment with the Career Counselor, please see the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/students/career-services/" target="_blank">CED Career Services website</a>.</p>
<h3><span>Program Requirements</span></h3>
<p>For the most current information regarding major and minor program requirements and college-wide policies, please see the following pages on the CED website:</p>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/newly-admitted-students/" target="_blank">Newly-Admitted Students</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/continuing-students/" target="_blank">Current Students</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/graduation-commencement/" target="_blank">Graduation and Commencement</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/services-contract/" target="_blank">Services and Contract</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/articulation/" target="_blank">Articulation</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/policies-resources/" target="_blank">Policies and Resources</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/forms-documents/" target="_blank">Forms and Documents</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Mission</h3>
<p>The College of Environmental Design (CED) Office of Undergraduate Advising helps students graduate in a timely way with a meaningful educational experience at Berkeley. In alignment with the College's Vision and Principles, the Office collaborates with CED faculty, deans, and student service units across campus toward the common objective of supporting students as they achieve their educational and career goals. The Office of Undergraduate Advising seeks to achieve the following:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Attract a highly-motivated, diverse pool of applicants</li>
	<li>Connect students with resources that match their goals and aspirations</li>
	<li>Support the development and transformation of our undergraduates as they become educated, active and socially just citizens of the world</li>
	<li>Prepare graduates who are uniquely qualified and highly sought after in their field of choice</li>
</ul>
<h3>Advising Values</h3>
<p><strong>Student Success.</strong> Above all, the Office of Undergraduate Advising dedicates itself to maximizing student potential and to helping students succeed in their university experiences. Advisors encourage students to explore their minds and their hearts, challenge them to do their best work, and help them realize their talents and passions and achieve their goals.</p>
<p><strong>Equity &amp; Inclusion.</strong> Commitment to creating an inclusive environment in which any individual or group can be and feel welcomed, respected, supported and valued. Advisors aspire to provide fair treatment, access, opportunity, and advancement for all students and to identify and eliminate barriers that prevent the full participation of all.</p>
<p><strong>Health &amp; Well-Being.</strong> Collaboration with campus partners to keep the CED community healthy by helping students balance the physical, intellectual, emotional, social, occupational, spiritual and environmental aspects of life.</p>
<p><strong>Advising Excellence.</strong> In all that they do, advisors strive to deliver personalized advising services of the highest quality. They also seek to continuously educate themselves on developments in the field and to evaluate, improve, and streamline services to support students in obtaining the best education and experience possible.</p>
]]>
</advisingtext>
<academicopportunitiestext name="Academic Opportunities">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Study Abroad</h3>
<p>The College of Environmental Design (CED) encourages all undergraduates in the College to study abroad. Whether students are interested in fulfilling general education requirements, taking courses related to their major/career, or simply living and studying in a country that is of interest to them, CED will work with students to make it happen. For further information, please see the <a href="https://ced.berkeley.edu/academics/study-abroad" target="_blank">CED Study Abroad website</a></p>
<h3>CED Career Services</h3>
<p>The CED Career Services Center (CSC) offers personalized career counseling, a yearly CED Career Fair, and a wide variety of professional-development workshops on topics such as licensure, internships, and applying for graduate school. For further information, please see the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/students/career-services/" target="_blank">CED Career Services website</a>.</p>
<h3>Prizes and Awards</h3>
<p>CED offers a number of annual prizes, awards, scholarships, fellowships, and grants to its currently enrolled students. Some of these prizes and awards are college-wide, and some are geared toward students in specific majors. For information regarding CED prizes and awards, including application instructions and a deadline calendar, please click <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/prizes/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>CED Events and Exhibits Calendar</h3>
<p>CED and Bauer Wurster Hall is home to a variety of events, lectures, and exhibitions that welcome professors, professionals, and friends to the College to discuss and celebrate the community and professions. Through events and media, CED is constantly creating ways to keep the college connected and up-to-date. To view the calendar, please click <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/events-media/events/" target="_blank">here</a>. </p>
<h3>CED Lecture Series</h3>
<p>The departments of Architecture, City and Regional Planning, and Landscape Architecture and Environmental Planning each sponsor lecture series, which offers students the opportunity to hear internationally-acclaimed speakers for free. These speakers often also participate in classes and seminars as part of their visit to campus. For a schedule of speakers and events in these lecture series, please see the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/events-media/lecture-series/" target="_blank">CED website</a>.</p>
<h3>Research Opportunities, Internships, Public Service, and Volunteer Opportunities</h3>
<p>For additional opportunities, please see the <a href="http://ced.berkeley.edu/ced/students/undergraduate-advising/" target="_blank">CED Advising website</a>.</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/59611725522/" target="_blank">CED on Facebook</a></h3>
<h3><a href="https://www.instagram.com/wursterlife/" target="_blank">CED on Instagram</a></h3>
]]>
</academicopportunitiestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

