<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>College of Letters &amp; Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Introduction to the College</h2>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-5ed62535-7fff-6a36-f2c6-3a33eb62288b">The College of Letters &amp; Science is the great, big heart of UC Berkeley: great because our international stature is the core of the university’s intellectual preeminence, and big because we are by far the largest of Berkeley’s colleges, comprising 38 departments and offering more than 80 majors across an extraordinary range of disciplines.  </span></p>
<p>Our rigorous academic programs are second to none and our capacity for impact far exceeds that of our private peers — every year 6,000 talented people graduate from our college, ready to lead change for the greater good.</p>
<p>L&amp;S is for all of us and we are committed to making our community as welcoming and respectful as it is intellectually stimulating.</p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/?filter_4=true">Explore majors and minors</a><span> available through the College of Letters &amp; Science.</span></p>
<p>For more information, <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/appointments-advice">meet with a College advisor</a>.</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<ucandcampusrequirementstext name="UC and Campus Requirements">
<![CDATA[
 <h3>University of California Requirements</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">Entry Level Writing</a></p> <p>All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by satisfying the Entry Level Writing Requirement (ELWR). <span style="font-size:1em">The </span><a href="https://admission.universityofcalifornia.edu/elwr/requirements/test-scores-grades.html" style="font-size: 1em;">UC Entry Level Writing Requirement website</a><span style="font-size:1em"> provides information on how to satisfy the requirement</span></p> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American History and American Institutions</a></p> <p>The American History and Institutions (AH&amp;I) requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</p> <h3>Campus Requirement</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American Cultures</a></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c47924ad-7fff-1b30-99f8-3c345cb2b997">The American Cultures requirement is a Berkeley campus requirement, one that all undergraduate students at Berkeley need to pass in order to graduate. You satisfy the requirement by passing, with a grade not lower than C- or P, an American Cultures course. You may take an American Cultures course any time during your undergraduate career at Berkeley. The requirement was instituted in 1991 to introduce students to the diverse cultures of the United States through a comparative framework. Courses are offered in more than fifty departments in many different disciplines at both the lower and upper division level.</span></p> <div> </div>
]]>
</ucandcampusrequirementstext>
<collegerequirementstext name="College Requirements">
<![CDATA[
 <p>Undergraduate students must fulfill the following requirements in addition to those required by their major program.</p> <p>For detailed lists of courses that fulfill college requirements, please review the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/">College of Letters &amp; Sciences</a> page in this Guide. For College advising appointments, please visit the <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/home">L&amp;S Advising</a> Pages. </p> <h3>University of California Requirements</h3> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/entry-level-writing-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-b6fc-99fe-5be6e0865dad">Entry Level Writing</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-c602-c395-1fb0f53c604b">All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by fulfilling the Entry Level Writing requirement. Fulfillment of this requirement is also a prerequisite to enrollment in all reading and composition courses at UC Berkeley. </span></p> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/american-history-institutions-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-ed90-bc30-8e7c7e9092f7">American History and American Institutions</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-fe3e-933e-7102e097ef4b">The American History and Institutions requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university, should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</span></p> <h3><span>Berkeley Campus Requirement</span></h3> <h5><a href="http://americancultures.berkeley.edu/students/courses"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-3abc-dc51-fc563caacff1">American Cultures</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-47e1-1ad4-b918d33461cf">All undergraduate students at Cal need to take and pass this course in order to graduate. The requirement offers an exciting intellectual environment centered on the study of race, ethnicity and culture of the United States. AC courses offer students opportunities to be part of research-led, highly accomplished teaching environments, grappling with the complexity of American Culture.</span></p> <h3><span>College of Letters &amp; Science Essential Skills Requirements</span></h3> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/quantitative-reasoning-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-a7b1-d295-ee03b476bcfe">Quantitative Reasoning</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-cbac-1c7a-d74abefae398">The Quantitative Reasoning requirement is designed to ensure that students graduate with basic understanding and competency in math, statistics, or computer science. The requirement may be satisfied by exam or by taking an approved course.</span></p> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/foreign-language-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-ff23-6ff3-47abec092456">Foreign Language</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-12d9-db19-1b37f6639ef7">The Foreign Language requirement may be satisfied by demonstrating proficiency in reading comprehension, writing, and conversation in a foreign language equivalent to the second semester college level, either by passing an exam or by completing approved course work.</span></p> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/reading-composition-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-3e15-2491-27223f91e87d">Reading and Composit</span>ion</a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-4ef4-4b87-0d26195a0d3c">In order to provide </span>a solid foundation in reading, writing, and critical thinking the College requires two semesters of lower division work in composition in sequence. Students must complete parts A &amp; B reading and composition courses in sequential order by the end of their fourth semester.</p> <h3>College of Letters &amp; Science 7 Course Breadth Requirements</h3> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/#breadthrequirementstext"><span id="docs-internal-guid-79a9fe70-d405-7c7e-e34f-837b91cc1d58">Breadth Requirements</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-9db4-c30e-bca05ecf44f3">The undergraduate breadth requirements provide Berkeley students with a rich and varied educational experience outside of their major program. As the foundation of a liberal arts education, breadth courses give students a view into the intellectual life of the University while introducing them to a multitude of perspectives and approaches to research and scholarship. Engaging students in new disciplines and with peers from other majors, the breadth experience strengthens interdisciplinary connections and context that prepares Berkeley graduates to understand and solve the complex issues of their day.</span></p> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-abca8c8f-d405-c4ad-0be7-1638c654345c">Unit Requirements</span></h3> <ul> 	<li> 	<p>120 total units</p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>Of the 120 units, 36 must be upper division units</p> 	</li> 	<li>Of the 36 upper division units, 6 must be taken in courses offered outside your major department</li> </ul> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-2bb674c5-d406-43a4-39ed-40d6e86d6760">Residence Requirements</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-8d38-492a-067b2e0bac2d">For units to be considered in &quot;residence,&quot; you must be registered in courses on the Berkeley campus as a student in the College of Letters &amp; Science. Most students automatically fulfill the residence requirement by attending classes here for four years. In general, there is no need to be concerned about this requirement, unless you go abroad for a semester or year or want to take courses at another institution or through UC Extension during your senior year. In these cases, you should make an appointment to meet an adviser to determine how you can meet the Senior Residence Requirement.</span></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-a2e5-35d5-82895d287218">Note: Courses taken through UC Extension do not count toward residence.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-44b2bced-d406-cb13-a0f5-0c6f75ed8972">Senior Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-e3bd-f620-e9bef1331f97">After you become a senior (with 90 semester units earned toward your BA degree), you must complete at least 24 of the remaining 30 units in residence in at least two semesters. To count as residence, a semester must consist of at least 6 passed units. Intercampus Visitor, EAP, and UC Berkeley-Washington Program (UCDC) units are excluded.</span></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-f7f7-c9da-c2732368bc4e">You may use a Berkeley Summer Session to satisfy one semester of the Senior Residence requirement, provided that you successfully complete 6 units of course work in the Summer Session and that you have been enrolled previously in the college.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-abb18f5b-d407-0e0f-9d41-83c0ea3c3c7b">Modified Senior Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d407-3956-aeef-b67b71969fca">Participants in the UC Education Abroad Program (EAP), Berkeley Summer Abroad, or the UC Berkeley Washington Program (UCDC) may meet a Modified Senior Residence requirement by completing 24 (excluding EAP) of their final 60 semester units in residence. At least 12 of these 24 units must be completed after you have completed 90 units.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-62f287bf-d407-4ca6-5bbd-2d1393418d66">Upper Division Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d407-6060-9575-98782777275a">You must complete in residence a minimum of 18 units of upper division courses (excluding UCEAP units), 12 of which must satisfy the requirements for your major.</span></p>
]]>
</collegerequirementstext>
<breadthrequirementstext name="Breadth Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>The undergraduate breadth requirements provide Berkeley students with a rich and varied educational experience outside of their major program. As the foundation of a liberal arts education, breadth courses give students a view into the intellectual life of the University while introducing them to a multitude of perspectives and approaches to research and scholarship. Engaging students in new disciplines and with peers from other majors, the breadth experience strengthens interdisciplinary connections and provides context that prepares Berkeley graduates to understand and solve the complex issues of their day.</span></p>
<p><span>The requirement consists of seven distribution areas:<strong> Arts and Literature, Biological Science, Historical Studies, International Studies, Philosophy and Values, Physical Science, and Social and Behavioral Sciences.</strong> </span></p>
<p><span>For descriptions of these distribution areas, as well as a more information on options to complete breadth, visit the <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/seven-course-breadth" target="_blank">L&amp;S Seven-Course Breadth</a> webpage.</span></p>
<h3><span>Guidelines for Seven-Course Breadth</span></h3>
<p>Complete one approved course for each of the seven areas with a minimum grade of C- or P. To find course options for breadth, go to the <a class="ext" href="http://classes.berkeley.edu/">Class Schedule</a>, select the term of interest, and use the &quot;Breadth Requirements&quot; filter to select the breadth area(s) of interest.  When selecting a course, keep the following in mind:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Some courses may list multiple breadth areas. These are <em>options</em> for which breadth areas the course can satisfy. A course may only be used for <em>one</em> of the approved breadth areas. To satisfy the breadth requirement, complete seven distinct courses, one for each breadth area.</li>
	<li>Students may use up to two courses from any one academic department to satisfy the Seven-Course Breadth. This includes all <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/depts_multiple_subjects_02_02_22.pdf">subject areas offered by the department</a> and—if a course is cross-listed (indicated by a 'C' prefix)—all other departments offering the course as well. <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/courses/l_s/" target="_blank">Letters and Science (&quot;LS&quot;)</a> courses are an exception to this restriction. Students may complete as many LS courses as they wish for the Seven-Course Breadth. This includes LS courses offered through the <a class="ext" href="http://lsdiscovery.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Discovery</a> and <a class="ext" href="http://bigideascourses.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Big Ideas</a> programs. </li>
	<li>Courses fulfilling <a class="ext" href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/american-history-institutions-requirement/" target="_blank">American History &amp; Institutions</a>, <a class="ext" href="http://americancultures.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">American Cultures</a> or requirements in the major program may also be applied to the Seven-Course Breadth requirement.</li>
	<li>Exams, such as Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate exams, cannot be used to fulfill breadth requirements.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Satisfying the Seven Course Breadth Requirement with Transfer Work</h3>
<ul>
	<li>All transfer courses must be completed with a grade of C- or better, or the equivalent of a Passed grade on the host campus, in order to be considered for Seven-Course Breadth. </li>
	<li>To be eligible for consideration, the minimum unit requirement for a course offered from a campus on the semester system is 3.0 units, and for courses offered from campuses on the quarter system, 4.0 units.</li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-adb2dc41-7fff-dd50-4472-2e94acbbecb4">Students can complete pre-approved breadth courses at a California Community College. Pre-approved courses can be found on </span><a href="http://www.assist.org/web-assist/welcome.html">ASSIST</a>. Refer to the <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/progress-planning/transfer-credit">L&amp;S Transfer Coursework page</a> for instructions on how to take transfer credit as an L&amp;S student before enrolling at a California Community College.</li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-a00a21c8-7fff-9d81-db65-e09d3f789e75">Successful completion of transferable courses from other higher education institutions (i.e. 2-year or 4-year campus in the U.S. or non-UCEAP courses from abroad) may also be considered. Course descriptions and syllabi will be required to make a breadth determination. For more information on pursuing transfer courses for Seven-Course Breadth at another higher education institution, review L&amp;S’s </span><a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/progress-planning/transfer-credit/other-higher-education-institution">Transfer Credit: Other Higher Education Institutions</a> webpage.</li>
</ul>
]]>
</breadthrequirementstext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>The <a href="https://ls.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">College of Letters and Science (L&amp;S</a>) is looking for students who are excited to engage in a wide range of intellectual inquiry. Success in the College is achieved by adventurous, self-motivated, and self-aware students who thrive in an environment of broad-ranging exploration. To find out more about undergraduate admissions, please review the <a href="http://admissions.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Admissions</a> website.</p>
<h3>Already a student and want to change colleges to L&amp;S?</h3>
<p>Students in other UC Berkeley colleges who feel their educational goals are best met with a degree in L&amp;S are welcome to petition for a Change of College. </p>
<p>Visit the <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/majors-minors/change-colleges-letters-and-science" target="_blank">Change of College page</a> for more information.</p>
<p>The application period for the spring semester is the first day of fall instruction through <span class="aBn" data-term="goog_2077660687" tabindex="0"><span class="aQJ">November 1</span></span>. The application period for the fall semester is the first day of spring instruction through <span class="aBn" data-term="goog_2077660688" tabindex="0"><span class="aQJ">June 1</span></span>.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<advisingtext name="Advising">
<![CDATA[
<p>The <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/">Office of Undergraduate Advising</a>, with a <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/ls-advising-staff">staff</a> of highly skilled and experienced College Advisers, is here to help students make the best choices for their academic career and get the most out of their time at Berkeley. </p>
<h3>L&amp;S College Advisers </h3>
<p>We can help you understand college requirements and academic rules and procedures. We also help students explore their interests, <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/discover-connect">discover opportunities, and connect with the campus</a>. L&amp;S College Advisers can support you in finding a major, navigating unexpected hurdles, and enhancing your undergraduate experience. </p>
<p>Below are common topics you would discuss with an L&amp;S College Adviser:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Satisfying College requirements, including Essential Skills and the Seven-Course Breadth</li>
	<li>Choosing a major or minor</li>
	<li>Exploring transfer work options for college requirements</li>
	<li>Clarifying academic options if you are struggling with a class</li>
	<li>Incorporating college requirements and enrichment opportunities to a 4-year plan </li>
	<li>Connecting with campus resources for support and enrichment opportunities</li>
</ul>
<p>Our Advising Neighborhood model will help you connect with L&amp;S College Advisers who are more familiar with your intended/declared major. It will also help you more easily find Undergraduate Major Advisers for your major-specific questions. Advisers in these neighborhoods will work closely together to give you a more consistent and holistic academic advising experience during your time at Cal. </p>
<p><a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/appointments-advice/find-your-advising-neighborhood" target="_blank">Find your Advising Neighborhood</a></p>
<p>If you are among our many students still exploring major options, check out our <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/undecided-major" target="_blank">Undecided on Major</a> page. </p>
<h4><strong>Contact Information for L&amp;S College Advising</strong></h4>
<p><strong>Front Desk / Virtual Front Desk Hours: </strong>See website<br/>
<strong>Main Office</strong>: 156 Dwinelle Hall, Berkeley, CA 94720-2924<br/>
<strong>Email</strong>: asklns@berkeley.edu</p>
<p><strong>Website</strong><span>: <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu</a></span></p>
<p><span>Remote and in-person services available. See website for more details. </span></p>
<h3>Undergraduate Major Advisers (UMAs) </h3>
<p>UMAs specialize in advising for a particular major and/or minor. You are welcome to meet with advising staff for departments you are considering, even if you are not declared. They can support you in planning major coursework, learning about departmental opportunities, and with declaring your major. </p>
<p>Below are common topics you'd discuss with an Undergraduate Major Adviser:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Satisfying major prerequisites and upper division requirements</li>
	<li>Declaring or applying to the major; likelihood of admission</li>
	<li>Exploring transfer work options for major requirements</li>
	<li>Discussing how struggling in a major course may impact major progress</li>
	<li>Developing your 4-year major plan and graduating on time</li>
	<li>Learning about research and other departmental opportunities</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Contact Information for UMAs</strong></h4>
<p>See <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/major-adviser">How to Meet with an Undergraduate Major Adviser</a>. </p>
<div> </div>
]]>
</advisingtext>
<academicopportunitiestext name="Academic Opportunities">
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://bigideascourses.berkeley.edu/">Big Ideas Courses</a><span>, launched in 2012, bring together two or more faculty members from different disciplines to co-teach innovative breadth courses. Big Ideas Courses take up key intellectual and societal challenges that cannot be adequately addressed by the perspective or methodology of one discipline alone. For more information, visit the </span><a href="http://bigideascourses.berkeley.edu/">website</a><span>.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/">Cal Teach</a> is a program for undergraduate science, math, and engineering majors interested in exploring a career in education. Through our courses, students learn conceptual teaching skills and practice these methods in local K-12 classrooms. Cal Teach offers the minor in Science and Math Education, as well as a unique opportunity for students to complete both a degree and a California teaching credential as an undergraduate.</p>
<p><a href="http://fss.berkeley.edu/">Freshman and Sophomore Seminars</a> arose from the conviction that early intellectual contact with faculty members would greatly enhance the undergraduate experience at Berkeley. Professors from nearly every campus department join together each semester to offer an impressive array of seminars. The courses numbered 24 bear one unit of credit; they are limited to 15 students and freshmen are given priority for enrollment. The courses numbered 84 bear one or two units of credit; they are limited to 15 sophomores. The courses numbered 39A-39Z are limited to 25 freshmen and sophomores.</p>
<p>Seminars, which emphasize interaction and discussion, provide a counterpoint to the learning experience in Berkeley's large lecture halls. These seminars also offer lower division students an unprecedented opportunity to explore a wide range of majors and even fields of study usually reserved for graduate students. As you browse through this Guide<em>,</em> you will find lower division seminars sponsored by Letters and Science departments, as well as by the professional schools and colleges. Descriptions of all the seminars scheduled for the upcoming semester can be found on the program's website, which also contains other useful information and features for undergraduates. For additional information regarding the Freshman and Sophomore Seminars, <span id="docs-internal-guid-fa80b6c5-7fff-0927-66a3-df24d9f1d4cd">visit the </span><a href="https://fss.berkeley.edu/">website</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://lsdiscovery.berkeley.edu/">Letters and Science Discovery Courses</a> are exemplary breadth courses, designed to engage and broaden the minds of non-experts. Taught by some of the most distinguished faculty members on campus, the L&amp;S Discovery Courses are guaranteed to deliver a high-quality educational experience.</p>
<p><a href="http://onthesamepage.berkeley.edu">On the Same Page</a> is a campus-wide book-in-common program, designed to welcome new freshmen and transfer students into the intellectual dialogue that characterizes the Berkeley campus. Each year all of the faculty and all new students receive a book (or film or other study object) that provides the focus for discussions, courses, events, and activities in the fall term. For more information, visit the <a href="http://onthesamepage.berkeley.edu">website.</a> For the most up-to-date information, follow On the Same Page on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/On-the-Same-Page-12900743724/">facebook</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/UCOnthesamepage?lang=en">twitter</a>. </p>
<p><a href="http://scholarships.berkeley.edu/">Scholarship Connection</a> administers the application process for over a dozen prestigious external scholarships (such as the Rhodes, Marshall, Truman, and Goldwater scholarships) and offers a clearinghouse for information on 500+ other external scholarships. For more information, visit us online at <a href="http://scholarships.berkeley.edu/">Scholarship Connection</a> or contact Scholarship Connection at 2410 Dwinelle Hall, <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/mailto:ourscholarships@berkeley.edu">ourscholarships@berkeley.edu</a>, or 510-643-6929.</p>
<p><a href="http://research.berkeley.edu">The Office of Undergraduate Research and Scholarships</a> (OURS) helps students get engaged in research while at Cal: connecting with faculty and mentors, obtaining funding opportunities to support your research pursuits, and integrating research with your other academic goals. Research programs run directly by OURS include the following:</p>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Apprentice with Faculty:</strong> The <a href="http://urap.berkeley.edu">Undergraduate Research Apprentice Program</a> (URAP) provides opportunities for you to receive course credit to work with faculty on cutting-edge research projects during the academic year. Approximately 1,500 students and 300+ faculty members participate each semester.</li>
	<li><strong>Independent research:</strong> The <a href="http://surf.berkeley.edu/">Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowships</a>  (SURF L&amp;S and SURF Rose Hills) fund over 100 students each summer with stipends from $4,500–$6,000 to carry out research projects. In addition, the <a href="http://hsp.berkeley.edu/">Haas Scholars Program</a> funds twenty students a year, with stipends up to $13,800 for independent research. These programs are primarily designed for juniors intending to do research over the summer to support their thesis work. </li>
	<li><strong>Public service: </strong>The <a href="http://stronach.berkeley.edu/">Stronach Baccalaureate Prize</a> funds four to six recent Cal grads for up to $25,000 to carry out a public service project of their own designs.</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, the Office of Undergraduate Research provides services to promote undergraduate research campus-wide:</p>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Campus-wide research database:</strong> OURS maintains a <a href="http://research.berkeley.edu/opportunities">database of research programs </a>at UC Berkeley and beyond with updates on application deadlines and eligibility. </li>
	<li><strong>Workshops and Peer Advising: </strong>We regularly offer workshops to help you get started and succeed in research. Workshop topics include the following: &quot;Getting Started,&quot; &quot;Professional Communication,&quot; &quot;Finding a Faculty Mentor,&quot; and &quot;Writing a Research Proposal.&quot; Check our <a href="https://events.berkeley.edu/index.php/calendar/sn/OURS.html">events calendar</a> for times and dates. Also check our main website to find out about OURS Peer-Adviser drop-in office hours. Speaking with a Peer Adviser is a great way to explore your options.</li>
	<li><strong>OURS Listserv and Social Media:</strong> Sign up for OURS' popular announcement listserv on our <a href="http://research.berkeley.edu">homepage</a> and be sure to follow OURS on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/OURSUCBerkeley/">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/BerkeleyOURS">Twitter</a>. </li>
</ul>
<p>For information on the great variety of undergraduate research opportunities at Berkeley, visit <a href="http://research.berkeley.edu/">Research@Berkeley</a> or visit <a href="http://research.berkeley.edu">research.berkeley.edu.</a></p>
<div>
<p><a class="m_-8784271413921261748m_-5525913221221896417gmail-m_-3925998416240494399m_5774211766234448235gmail-" href="http://ucdc.berkeley.edu/uc-washington-program" target="_blank">UC Washington Program</a>:  UCDC sends juniors and seniors to Washington, D.C. to intern, research, and take classes fall or spring semester.  UCDC students come from all majors and remain eligible for financial aid.  While interning three to four days a week, students live and take classes at the UC Washington Center, in the heart of the city.  During their D.C. semester, students develop professional skills, clarify their future direction, and build professional networks.</p>
</div>
]]>
</academicopportunitiestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

