<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Women, Gender, and Sexuality</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>PhD students at UC Berkeley may add a Designated Emphasis in Women, Gender, and Sexuality (DEWGS) to their major fields. Designed to enhance interdisciplinary graduate studies at Berkeley, the DEWGS provides curricular and research resources and opportunities to students who are already admitted to graduate degree programs on campus.</p>
<p>The designated emphasis program was developed to accommodate some of the many students who conduct graduate-level research in related topics across numerous fields. Administered by the Department of Gender and Women's Studies, the designated emphasis program provides its students with certification, as well as with a context for the interdisciplinary exchange of ideas and development of research.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Programs</h3>
<p>The <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/departments/gender-womens-studies/">Department of Gender and Women's Studies</a> offers a major and minor program in <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/gender-womens-studies/">Gender and Women's Studies</a>, and a minor program in <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-studies/">Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender (LGBT) Studies</a>.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/women-gender-sexuality/">Women, Gender, and Sexuality</a>: Designated Emphasis (DE)</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Paola Bacchetta, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ethnicity, postcolonial theory, transnational feminist and queer of color theories, theories of the inseparability of gender, theories of the inseparability of sexuality, theories of the inseparability of, theories of the inseparability of class, theories of the inseparability of nation, theories of the inseparability of religion, global political and religious conflict (especially Hindu nationalism and racializations of Muslims and Islam), theories of resistance and transgression, right-wing movements, geographic areas of specialization outside the U S- India and France.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/paola-bacchetta"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mel Y. Chen, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Queer and feminist theory, Disability theory, Critical animal studies, Materiality studies, Cultural politics of race, sexuality, ability, and immigration, Critical linguistics, Paradigms of inter- and transdisciplinarity.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/mel-y-chen"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Minoo Moallem, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Transnational and Postcolonial Feminist Studies, cultural studies, Visual and Material Cultures of Religion, Immigration and Diaspora Studies, Middle East Studies, and Iranian Studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15131"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Courtney Desiree Morris, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Black women’s social movements; state violence and authoritarianism; racial formations in Latin America, the Caribbean and the US; Critical race theory; Feminist and queer theory; environmental ethics; black visual culture and aesthetics.<br/><a href="http://womensstudies.berkeley.edu/about/department-faculty/courtney-desiree-morris/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Laura C. Nelson, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Gender, medicine, and politics, Cultural, political, and experiential aspects of breast cancer in South Korea, How, why, and to what effect constructions of gender, class, and race are mobilized and manipulated in South Korea, Structures of cultural temporality (future, present, or past orientation) and anti-poverty policies (US and South Korea).<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/laura-c-nelson"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leslie Salzinger, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Political economy, feminist theory, finance, sociology of gender, Gender and Work, gendering of transnational processes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15303"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eric Stanley, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Critical prison studies; Queer/trans social movements; Anti-colonial feminism.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/eric-stanley"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Barbara A. Barnes, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Evelyn Nakano Glenn, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Labor, citizenship, undocumented students, caring work, settler colonialism, skin color bias.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13857"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barrie Thorne, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, gender theory, ethnography, qualitative methods, sociology, women, sociology of gender, sociology of age relations.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15542"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Irene Tinker, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>International development and women, Electoral quotas in legislatures for women.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Minh-Ha Trinh, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Gender and sexuality, womens studies, rhetoric, feminist postcolonial theory, film theory and production, music composition, ethnomusicology, contemporary critical theory and the arts.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/minh-ha-trinh"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

