<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Romance Languages and Literatures</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p><span>The Romance Languages and Literatures (RLL) interdepartmental PhD program is a joint venture by the Departments of French, Italian Studies, and Spanish and Portuguese. It offers students a unique opportunity to work with distinguished faculty in all three departments as they take advantage of Berkeley's unmatched resources for comparative study of the literatures and linguistics of the Romance language family.</span></p>
<p>The program is a doctorate in three Romance languages and literatures taught in the Departments of French, Italian Studies, and Spanish and Portuguese, and prepared with emphasis in one of the languages (referred to as the “Primary” language). </p>
<p>While RLL is an independent program, students are normally affiliated with the department of their primary language, which is referred to as the “Host” department. Students may opt for either the Literature track or the Linguistics track.</p>
<p>The mission of the RLL program is: (1) To take a multilingual approach to language and literature; (2) To combine literary and philological/linguistic study; (3) To offer flexibility in the design of students’ programs: the unity of a common heritage and common evolution of the Romance family allows diversity in topics and approaches; and (4) To train Romance scholars of linguistics, literature, and culture who can take jobs in Romance-language departments, single-language departments, or Linguistics departments.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Romance Languages and Literatures.</p>
<h3>Graduate Programs</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/romance-languages-literatures/">Romance Languages and Literatures</a>: PhD, with emphases in French, Italian, or Spanish<br/>
 </p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><a name="french"></a><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Deborah Anne Blocker, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Early modern French literature and history.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14450"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Karl A. Britto, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Africa, cultural studies, the Caribbean, literature, francophone literature, colonial and postcolonial literature, Vietnam, gender and identity.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14471"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>William M. Burton , <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>French literature, gender, sexuality, and feminism, (especially lesbianism), intellectual history, translation studies, Quebec studies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/william-m-burton"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Timothy Hampton, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Culture, politics, English, comparative literature, French, renaissance and early modern European culture, the romance languages, the ideology of literary genre, the literary construction of nationhood, the rhetoric of historiography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14784"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard G. Kern, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Literacy, second language acquisition, writing, psycholinguistics, reading, French language, French linguistics, technology and education.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14986"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Lucey, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Pragmatics, the novel, sexuality studies, comparative literature, French, French literature, nineteenth and twentieth centuries, British literature and culture, social and literary theory, cultural studies of music, studies of language in use, theories of practice, twentieth-century American literature .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15326"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Susan Maslan, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>French, early modern French literary, political history, the enlightenment, human rights.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15091"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mairi Mclaughlin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>French linguistics, Italian linguistics, romance linguistics, translation studies, history of French, History of Italian, History of the Romance Languages, language contact, History of the Press, Speech Reporting.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15338"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nicholas Paige, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cinema (French New Wave), 17th- and 18th-century French literature and culture, history and theory of the novel, quantitative literary history and digital humanities, aesthetics and image theory, subjectivity and autobiography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15366"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Debarati Sanyal, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Violence, poetry, the relationship between literary form, politics in 19th-century France, the connection between performance, performativity, ethics in modernist texts.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15407"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Soraya Tlatli, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Francophone literature, colonial and postcolonial studies, literature and psychoanalysis, twentieth-century continental philosophy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15547"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Damon R. Young, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Film theory, digital media, global art cinema, gender and sexuality studies, critical theory.</p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Arrigo, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Hoffmann, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Vesna Rodic, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ariel Shannon, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rachel Shuh, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maya Sidhu, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Margot Szarke, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Claire Tourmen, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Esther Alder, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leo Bersani, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ulysse Dutoit, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Suzanne Guerlac, <i>Professor Emerita</i>. </strong>Nationalism, literature, philosophy, 19th- and 20th-century literature, myths of literature and theory, contemporary cultural criticism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14757"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Basil Guy, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Hult, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Literary theory, medieval French literature, allegory, hermeneutics, text editing, French Studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14875"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leonard W. Johnson, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Thomas M. Kavanagh, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ann Smock, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Poetry, French, France during World War II, the Algerian War, 20th-century writing by women, relations between literature and music, Jacques Roubaud, Danielle Collobert.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15467"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><a name="italian"></a><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Mia Fuller, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Anthropology, Italy, fascism, urban design, architecture, Italian colonialism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14694"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Henrike Lange, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Medieval art.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Diego Pirillo, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Renaissance Europe, History of Books and Reading, history of political thought, History of Historiography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16367"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barbara Spackman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, psychoanalysis, culture, fascism, gender studies, comparative literature, Italian studies, narrative, European decadence, travel writing.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15481"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rhiannon Welch, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>* Anna M. Bellezza, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Giuliana Perco, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Albert Russell Ascoli, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Italy, national identity, literature and history, Dante, authorship and authority, Ariosto, Machiavelli, Petrarch, Boccaccio, epic and romance, Renaissance, early modern, Middle Ages.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15005"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gavriel Moses, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Violence, body, comparative literature, Italian studies, film studies, English literatures, philology, film making, Italian cinema history and genres, auteur effects in Antonioni Kieslowski and Rohmer, cultural objects in cinema, novels on film, love.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15147"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><a name="spanpor"></a><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Natalia Brizuela, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Spanish, Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14472"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anthony J. Cascardi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English, comparative literature, literature, Spanish, Portuguese, philosophy, aesthetics, early modern literature, French, Spanish Baroque.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14481"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Justin Davidson, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Spanish linguistics, romance linguistics, contact linguistics, bilingualism, Catalan, sociophonetics, language variation and change, quantitative methods.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16916"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ivonne Del Valle, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Colonial period in Mexico, internal colonialism in Mexico, Jesuits (Loyola, Acosta, Baegert), Baroque and Enlightenment from a colonial perspective, technology and environment, drainage of Mexico City lakes, Christianity and Pre-Hispanic religions .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15015"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daylet Dominguez, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Modern and Contemporary Latin American and Caribbean Literatures and Cultures.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16365"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Iarocci, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Spanish, literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14878"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Tom McEnaney, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Connections between Argentine, Cuban, and U S  literature, the history of media and technology, sound studies, linguistic anthropology, computational (digital) humanities and new media studies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/tom-mcenaney"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nasser Meerkhan, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Transcultural, transtemporal and translinguistic texts, Medieval Iberia.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/nasser-meerkhan"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ignacio Navarrete, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Spanish literature: poetry, poetic theory, narrative and culture, history of the book, Cervantes, Don Quixote, Medieval and Early Modern Spanish literature  Modern Spain .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15166"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alexandra Saum Pascual, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Spain, electronic literature, contemporary literature, digital humanities, new media.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16273"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Candace Slater, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Spanish, Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15457"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Estelle Tarica, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Latin America, Mexico, race, nationalism, Spanish, mestizo, Indians, Andes, Bolivia, Peru, Holocaust, Quechua.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15524"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nathaniel Wolfson, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Avant-garde poetry and aesthetics, media studies,  literature and philosophy, comparative modernisms and the history of science and technology.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/nathaniel-wolfson"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4></h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Amir Effat, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jose Roman Lujan Perez, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Oscar Perea Rodriguez, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jhonni Carr, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Clelia Francesca Donovan, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Miriam Hernandez-Rodriguez, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ana Belen Redondo Campillos, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Victoria Martinez Robertson, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Donna A. Southard, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Tanya Varela, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4></h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Amelia R. Barili, <i>Lecturer Emerita</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Arthur L. Askins, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Spanish, Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14646"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Milton M. Azevedo, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Linguistics, Spanish, Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14350"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Emilie L. Bergmann, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Early modern Spain, colonial Spanish America, Spanish literature, Sor Juana Ines de la Cruz, visual studies, gender and sexuality studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14434"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jerry R. Craddock, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Spanish, Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14497"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dru Dougherty, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Poetry, stage history, Valle-Inclan, Spanish poetics, war and literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14633"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles Faulhaber, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Medieval Spanish literature, medieval rhetoric, codicology, paleography, computerization of scholarly methodology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14657"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Francine R. Masiello, <i>Professor Emerita</i>. </strong>Gender theory, culture, globalization, comparative literature, Spanish, Latin American literature of the 19th and 20th centuries, comparative North and South literatures.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15332"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John H. R. Polt, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Spanish literature, 18th century, 19th century.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15233"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jose Rabasa, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Spanish, Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15250"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Julio Ramos, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Spanish, Portuguese.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15259"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

