<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Medieval Studies</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Medieval Studies Program at UC Berkeley is an interdisciplinary group that coordinates and sponsors lectures, events, and visiting professorships; promotes scholarly interests common to medievalists of different academic departments; and communicates information of interest among them. The committee on Medieval Studies offers a concurrent PhD program in which candidates have both a home department and training in the core disciplines of medieval studies. The degree granted is the concurrent PhD in the departmental discipline and medieval studies (e.g., English and medieval studies, history and medieval studies). The concurrent PhD is designed to preserve an established standard of training in a major subject while broadening the student's experience in other aspects of the field. A candidate for the concurrent PhD is expected to fulfill all the PhD requirements of the major field of study.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
<h3>Admission to the Program</h3>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Graduate students must be accepted for admission to a regular department (e.g., English or History) before applying for a concurrent degree in Medieval Studies.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext name="Doctoral Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">Candidates for this concurrent degree program must fulfill the following requirements:</p>
<ol>
	<li class="Normal1">Completion of three courses, which must include:
	<ol>
		<li class="Normal1"><span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MED ST 200">MED ST 200</span></span>, the proseminar introduces students to a broad range of approaches to medieval materials from across multiple subdisciplines and familiarizes them with specialized research tools and resources.</li>
		<li class="Normal1"><span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="HISTORY 275B">HISTORY 275B</span></span> or another course on a solely medieval topic (Other appropriate graduate courses in history may be substituted with the consent of the graduate adviser.) Students whose home department is History must take two courses in category (c), below.</li>
		<li class="Normal1">Any course from outside the student’s home department, normally drawn from the following:
		
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COM LIT 212">COM LIT 212</span></td><td>Studies in Medieval Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 205B">ENGLISH 205B</span></td><td>Old English</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 211">ENGLISH 211</span></td><td>Chaucer</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 212">ENGLISH 212</span></td><td>Readings in Middle English</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FRENCH 210A">FRENCH 210A</span></td><td>Studies in Medieval Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FRENCH 211A">FRENCH 211A</span></td><td>Reading and Interpretation of Old French Texts</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GERMAN 205">GERMAN 205</span></td><td>Studies in Medieval Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="HISTART 258">HISTART 258</span></td><td>Seminar in Late Medieval Art in Northern Europe</td><td class="hourscol">2,4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ITALIAN 212">ITALIAN 212</span></td><td>Seminar on Dante</td><td class="hourscol">2,4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MED ST 205">MED ST 205</span></td><td>Medieval Manuscripts as Primary Sources</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MED ST 250">MED ST 250</span></td><td>Seminar in Medieval Culture</td><td class="hourscol">2-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SCANDIN 201B">SCANDIN 201B</span></td><td>Norse Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SCANDIN 220">SCANDIN 220</span></td><td>Early Scandinavian Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

		(In addition to the courses listed, any graduate-level course in the relevant departments whose content is wholly medieval may, with the permission of the graduate advisers, be counted toward this requirement.) All courses for this requirement must be completed for a letter grade.</li>
	</ol>
	</li>
	<li class="Normal1">Advanced competence in Latin, which will normally be demonstrated through two graduate-level or upper division courses in medieval Latin literature (one of which must normally be Latin 140, Latin 155A or 155B, or Classics 241). The Latin proficiency exams that are offered by some departments may not be used to fulfill this requirement.</li>
	<li class="Normal1">Reading proficiency in at least one medieval vernacular, one of which must be outside the major field of study. Ordinarily such knowledge will be demonstrated through graduate-level or approved upper division coursework, drawn from the following:
	
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CELTIC 105A">CELTIC 105A</span></td><td>Old and Middle Irish</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CELTIC 146A">CELTIC 146A</span></td><td>Medieval Welsh Language and Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass odd"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CELTIC 146B">CELTIC 146B</span></td><td colspan="2"> Medieval Welsh Language and Literature</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 104">ENGLISH 104</span></td><td>Introduction to Old English</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 111">ENGLISH 111</span></td><td>Chaucer</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 112">ENGLISH 112</span></td><td>Middle English Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 205B">ENGLISH 205B</span></td><td>Old English</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 211">ENGLISH 211</span></td><td>Chaucer</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH 212">ENGLISH 212</span></td><td>Readings in Middle English</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FRENCH 112A">FRENCH 112A</span></td><td>Medieval Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass even"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FRENCH 112B">FRENCH 112B</span></td><td colspan="2"> Medieval Literature</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FRENCH 114A">FRENCH 114A</span></td><td>Late Medieval Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FRENCH 210A">FRENCH 210A</span></td><td>Studies in Medieval Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="FRENCH 211A">FRENCH 211A</span></td><td>Reading and Interpretation of Old French Texts</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GERMAN 105">GERMAN 105</span></td><td>Middle High German for Undergraduates</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GERMAN 205">GERMAN 205</span></td><td>Studies in Medieval Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GERMAN 273">GERMAN 273</span></td><td>Gothic</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GERMAN 276">GERMAN 276</span></td><td>Old High German</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GERMAN 280">GERMAN 280</span></td><td>North Sea Germanic</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GERMAN 282">GERMAN 282</span></td><td>Old Saxon</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ITALIAN 109">ITALIAN 109</span></td><td>Dante's Commedia (in Italian)</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ITALIAN 110">ITALIAN 110</span></td><td>Literature and Culture of the 13th and 14th Centuries</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ITALIAN 212">ITALIAN 212</span></td><td>Seminar on Dante</td><td class="hourscol">2,4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SCANDIN 101A">SCANDIN 101A</span></td><td>Introduction to Old Norse I</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SCANDIN 101B">SCANDIN 101B</span></td><td>Introduction to Old Norse II</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SCANDIN 201A">SCANDIN 201A</span></td><td>Old Norse</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SCANDIN 201B">SCANDIN 201B</span></td><td>Norse Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SCANDIN 220">SCANDIN 220</span></td><td>Early Scandinavian Literature</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

	Other courses offering readings exclusively in a medieval vernacular may be substituted with the permission of the graduate adviser. Also with the permission of the graduate adviser, medieval versions of other relevant languages (such as Arabic, Greek, Hebrew, or Old Church Slavonic) may be accepted in fulfillment of this requirement.</li>
	<li class="Normal1">Working knowledge of the material sources of medieval culture. Ordinarily, this requirement is met through coursework, or approved specialist training, in the study of medieval manuscripts: e.g., palaeography, diplomatics, or codicology. Students may also demonstrate their mastery of primary material sources through an extended essay making substantial and original use of these skills. When appropriate, and with the consent of the graduate adviser, training in allied disciplines making use of primary materials (such as epigraphy or medieval archaeology) may be accepted.</li>
	<li class="Normal1">A field statement of 30-50 pages, which situates the major area of interest in an interdisciplinary setting. This is not a prospectus setting out the specific plan of research for a dissertation, but a broader and more preliminary contextualizing essay, placing the present state and resources of the student’s home discipline in relation to those other disciplines of medieval studies of which the student will need to have a sophisticated apprehension in order to conceive such a plan of research. This statement will be evaluated by the student’s adviser and the Medieval Studies representative to the examination committee (see [6], below). <em>The field statement must be approved by both the adviser and examiner at least 30 days prior to the oral qualifying examination.</em> It should thus ordinarily be submitted to the relevant faculty members about six weeks prior to the date of the oral examination.</li>
	<li class="Normal1">A special committee for the PhD qualifying examination. A representative of Medieval Studies must serve on the PhD orals examination committee. In the event of a failure on either the field statement or the Medieval Studies portion of the qualifying exam, the candidate may revise the field statement and/or retake the Medieval Studies portion of the orals in accordance with the policies of the Graduate Division, Policies and Procedures F.2.7.</li>
	<li class="Normal1">Regular participation in the Medieval Studies Colloquium, and one presentation of dissertation-work in progress to that colloquium.</li>
</ol>
]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Medieval Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_medst200" data-toggle="#cb_medst200">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">MED ST 200</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Research Materials and Methods</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_medst200">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2021, Spring 2019<br/>
The gradute proseminar. Basic materials and resources in fields represented in the Medieval Studies program, and in some subjects involving expertise in more than one discipline (e.g., liturgy, codicology). Emphasis on methods of interdisciplinary research, research tools, and critical evaluation of their use.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Research Materials and Methods:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="368" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Medieval Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Research Materials and Methods:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_medst205" data-toggle="#cb_medst205">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">MED ST 205</span> 
<span class="title">Medieval Manuscripts as Primary Sources</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_medst205">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2012, Fall 2007, Fall 1998<br/>
This course explores the use of medieval manuscripts as primary sources for contemporary scholarship and as evidence of book culture in the medieval West.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Medieval Manuscripts as Primary Sources:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="60" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Medieval Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Medieval Manuscripts as Primary Sources:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_medst210" data-toggle="#cb_medst210">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">MED ST 210</span> 
<span class="title">Paleography and Codicology</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_medst210">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2019, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Instruction in Medieval Latin paleography and/or the paleography of one or more of the medieval vernacular languages of Western Europe, emphasizing the evolution of scripts as well as practice in reading them. Ancillary instruction in the principles of codicology with attention to the process of text-making and book manufacture.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Paleography and Codicology:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="939" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of Instructor required</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Medieval Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Paleography and Codicology:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_medst250" data-toggle="#cb_medst250">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">MED ST 250</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Medieval Culture</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_medst250">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2018, Fall 2017, Spring 2010<br/>
Taught by the Distinguished Visiting Professor of Medieval Studies on a topic related to his or her specialty. In the event that the instructor is in residence for fewer than 15 weeks, the course will be offered for either 2 or 3 units of credit, in proportion to the number of actual contact hours.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Seminar in Medieval Culture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="252" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Course may be taken for less than 4 units on a &lt;satisfactory/unsatisfactory&gt; basis with consent of instructor.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Medieval Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Seminar in Medieval Culture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>* Sabrina C. Agarwal, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Bioarchaeology, skeletal biology, gender research, biological and evolutionary anthropology, osteology and osteoporosis, health and disease, paleopathology .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14383"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Asad Ahmed, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Islam (social and intellectual history).<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16446"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Diliana Angelova, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Gender, early Christian art, Byzantine art, late antique art, the Virgin Mary, early Christian empresses, imperial iconography, power and material culture, the empress Helena, the relic of the True Cross, urban development of Constantinople, textiles, ivories, mythology in Byzantine art, myth and genre in Archaic and Classical Greek art, romantic love in ancient and medieval art.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15002"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Deena Aranoff, <i>Director</i>. </strong>Richard S  Dinner Center for Jewish Studies, Senior Lecturer in Medieval Jewish Studies, Graduate Theological Union, Specialty: Jewish Studies.<br/><a href="http://medieval.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/deena-aranoff"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Susanna Elm, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>History of the Later Roman Empire, pagan - Christian interactions, ancient medicine, slavery and the evolution of Christianity, leadership and empire, reception of antiquity.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14637"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kate Heslop, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Medieval Studies, Old Norse literature, Viking and medieval Scandinavia.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16884"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Hult, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Literary theory, medieval French literature, allegory, hermeneutics, text editing, French Studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14875"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rosemary Joyce, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Latin America, anthropology, gender, archaeology, sexuality, museums, cultural heritage, ethics, Central America, feminism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14308"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven Justice, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English, late medieval literature, medieval Latin, Chaucer, hagiography, Latin religious thought, literary criticism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14208"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Geoffrey Koziol, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Medieval history, History of Medieval Christianity, Medieval Political Institutions.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14708"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Henrike Lange, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Medieval art.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Niklaus Largier, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Religion, literature, German, history of medieval and early modern German literature, theology, mysticism, secularism, senses, sensuality, history of emotions, passions, asceticism, flagellation, sexuality.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14949"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Margaret Larkin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Near Eastern studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14950"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Lee, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Political theory, history of political thought, jurisprudence.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maria Mavroudi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Byzantine studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14106"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Laurent Mayali, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Professor Berkeley Law,  Specialty: Law, European legal history, comparative law, medieval jurisprudence, customary law.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14187"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer Miller, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>English, philology, paleography, hagiography, medieval literature, literature in old and middle English, historiography, medieval rhetorical culture, insular political relations, multilingualism, translation and textual transmission, dialectology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15123"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maureen Miller, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Medieval history.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15124"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ignacio Navarrete, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Spanish literature: poetry, poetic theory, narrative and culture, history of the book, Cervantes, Don Quixote, Medieval and Early Modern Spanish literature  Modern Spain .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15166"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maura Bridget Nolan, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chaucer, drama, Middle English literature, Gower, Lydgate, medieval, 16th century, literary form, style.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15183"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher Ocker, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Specialty: Religious studies.<br/><a href="https://sfts.edu/academics/faculty/christopher-ocker/#toggle-id-1"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Irmengard Rauch, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Semiotics, Germanic linguistics, linguistic archeology, paralanguage, Old Saxon, Old Frisian, linguistic fieldwork, socio-cultural and cognitive approaches to language variation and language change, contrastive analysis and linguistic methodology, Gothic, Modern High German and its dialects, Old/Middle High/Early New High German.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15609"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Thomas F. Shannon, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Linguistics, control, German, Dutch, syntax, phonology, naturalness, syllable structure, complementation, ergative phenomena, passivization, perfect auxiliary selection, word order, processing factors syntactic phenomena, cognitive, functional grammar, corpus.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/elaine-tennant"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Elaine C. Tennant, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>German, Habsburg court society in the early modern period, the development of the German language at the end of the middle ages, the Middle High German narrative tradition, literary and cultural traditions of the holy roman empire, European reactions.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15668"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jonas Wellendorf, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Old Norse language and literature, Scandinavian mythology, Scandinavian cultural history (Viking Age and Middle ages).<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15610"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Emily Zazulia, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Medieval and Renaissance Music, the intersection of musical style, complex notation, and intellectual history .<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/emily-zazulia-0"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Kathryn Klar, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Annalee Rejhon, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Albert Russell Ascoli, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Italy, national identity, literature and history, Dante, authorship and authority, Ariosto, Machiavelli, Petrarch, Boccaccio, epic and romance, Renaissance, early modern, Middle Ages.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15005"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Carol J. Clover, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Medieval studies (Northern Europe), film (especially American) .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14513"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary Kay Duggan, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles Faulhaber, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Medieval Spanish literature, medieval rhetoric, codicology, paleography, computerization of scholarly methodology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14657"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Lindow, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Department of Scandinavian, Specialty: Folklore, Scandinavian, old Norse-Icelandic literature, Scandinavian folklore, Finno-Ugric folklore, Pre-Christian religion of the North, Scandinavian mythology  .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14231"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel F. Melia, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Department of Rhetoric, Celtic Studies Program  Specialty: Rhetoric, oral literature, Celtic studies, Celtic languages (Welsh, Irish), Folklore, medieval history and literature .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>James T. Monroe, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David H. Wright, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Art from Augustus to Charlemagne, palaeography and codicology, late Roman numismatics,  Art History, Manuscript Illumination, Codicology, Numismatics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15635"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

