<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>College of Chemistry</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Introduction to the College</h2>
<p>Chemistry, chemical biology, and chemical and biomolecular engineering provide fantastic opportunities for pursuing a stimulating and gratifying career while making a positive impact on society.  Since chemistry is the gateway to all the molecular sciences and much of engineering, the College of Chemistry facilitates many possible career paths. </p>
<p>Humans live in a chemical world where their lives, environment, energy, food, and products are all impacted and/or provided by the activities of chemists and chemical engineers. Making new organic, inorganic, and nano materials; developing new drugs and methods for delivery; developing new synthetic procedures; understanding fundamental elements of chemical structure, bonding, and reactions; exploring chemical biology, the chemical basis of biological processes; producing sustainable energy through biofuels and photovoltaics; and improving the environment through green chemical processes all depend critically upon chemistry and chemical engineering. Students entering these fields today will find exciting careers addressing fundamental challenges in chemistry, applying chemical concepts to problems in related scientific areas, and using established concepts to pioneer new technologies.</p>
<p>The Department of Chemistry and the Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering in the College of Chemistry rank among the most prominent in the nation, and both are renowned for their excellence in a diverse range of subdisciplines and applications. Nowhere else will students find such a wide selection of instructional excellence in the chemical sciences and their applications or such varied opportunities for research.  Superb facilities at the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory enhance many of the College’s research programs.  The California Institute for Quantitative Biomedical Research (QB3) provides a dynamic interdisciplinary environment in which students and faculty in the college collaborate with their colleagues in the physical and biological sciences and in engineering to conduct cutting-edge research into biological problems and to produce the breakthroughs of the future.</p>
<p>With only two departments, the College of Chemistry provides a relatively small and collegial place in which to live and work while being nestled in one of the most beautiful and vibrant cosmopolitan areas in the world.  Students' intellectual, scientific, and social experiences at Berkeley will shape their lives and outlooks for years to come.</p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/?filter_1=true">Explore majors and minors</a> available through the College of Chemistry.</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<ucandcampusrequirementstext name="UC and Campus Requirements">
<![CDATA[
 <h3>University of California Requirements</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">Entry Level Writing</a></p> <p>All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by satisfying the Entry Level Writing Requirement (ELWR). <span style="font-size:1em">The </span><a href="https://admission.universityofcalifornia.edu/elwr/requirements/test-scores-grades.html" style="font-size: 1em;">UC Entry Level Writing Requirement website</a><span style="font-size:1em"> provides information on how to satisfy the requirement</span></p> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American History and American Institutions</a></p> <p>The American History and Institutions (AH&amp;I) requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</p> <h3>Campus Requirement</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American Cultures</a></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c47924ad-7fff-1b30-99f8-3c345cb2b997">The American Cultures requirement is a Berkeley campus requirement, one that all undergraduate students at Berkeley need to pass in order to graduate. You satisfy the requirement by passing, with a grade not lower than C- or P, an American Cultures course. You may take an American Cultures course any time during your undergraduate career at Berkeley. The requirement was instituted in 1991 to introduce students to the diverse cultures of the United States through a comparative framework. Courses are offered in more than fifty departments in many different disciplines at both the lower and upper division level.</span></p> <div> </div>
]]>
</ucandcampusrequirementstext>
<collegerequirementstext name="College Requirements">
<![CDATA[
 <p>All students in the College of Chemistry are required to complete the University requirements of <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/american-cultures-requirement/">American Cultures</a>, <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/american-history-institutions-requirements/">American History and Institutions</a>, and <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/entry-level-writing-requirement/">Entry-Level Writing</a>.  In addition, they must satisfy the following College requirements:</p> <h3><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/reading-composition-requirement/">Reading and Composition</a></h3> <p>In order to provide a solid foundation in reading, writing, and critical thinking the College requires lower division work in composition.</p> <ul> 	<li class="li2">Chemical Engineering majors: A-level Reading and Composition course (e.g., English R1A) by end of the first year</li> 	<li class="li2"><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/reading-composition-requirement/">Chemical Biology and Chemistry majors: A- and B-level courses by end of the second year</a></li> 	<li>R&amp;C courses must be taken for a letter grade</li> 	<li>English courses at other institutions may satisfy the requirement(s); check with your Undergraduate Adviser</li> 	<li>After admission to Berkeley, credit for English at another institution will not be granted if the Entry Level Writing requirement has not been satisfied</li> </ul> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-ba6ca1b2-dd73-5506-154b-3a5a6c6795f1">Humanities and Social Sciences Breadth Requirement: Chemistry &amp; Chemical Biology majors</span></h3> <p>The College of Chemistry’s humanities and social sciences breadth requirement promotes educational experiences that enrich and complement the technical requirements for each major.  </p> <ul> 	<li>15 units total; includes Reading &amp; Composition and American Cultures courses</li> 	<li>Remaining units must come from the following L&amp;S breadth areas, excluding courses which only teach a skill (such as drawing or playing an instrument):</li> </ul> <p style="margin-left:120px">Arts and Literature<br/> <a class="ext" href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/approved-foreign-language-courses/" target="_blank">Foreign Language<sup>1,2</sup></a><br/> Historical Studies<br/> International Studies<br/> Philosophy and Values<br/> Social and Behavioral Sciences</p> <p style="margin-left:80px">To find course options for breadth, go to the <a class="ext" href="http://classes.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Berkeley Academic Guide Class Schedule</a>, select the term of interest, and use the 'Breadth Requirements' filter to select the breadth area(s) of interest.</p> <ul> 	<li>Breadth courses may be taken on a <em>Pass/No Pass</em> basis (excluding Reading and Composition)</li> 	<li><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/students/current-undergraduates/exam-credit-info">AP, IB, and GCE A-level exam credit</a> may be used to satisfy the breadth requirement</li> </ul> <p style="margin-left:40px"><sup>1 </sup>Elementary-level courses may not be in the student's native language and may not be structured primarily to teach the reading of scientific literature.</p> <p style="margin-left:40px"><sup>2 </sup>For Chemistry and Chemical Biology majors, elementary-level foreign language courses are not accepted toward the 15 unit breadth requirement if they are used (or are duplicates of high school courses used) to satisfy the Foreign Language requirement.</p> <h4 style="margin-left:40px">Foreign Language (Language Other Than English [LOTE]) Requirement</h4> <p style="margin-left:40px"><strong>Applies to Chemistry and Chemical Biology majors only.</strong></p> <p style="margin-left:40px">The LOTE requirement may be satisfied with one language other than English, in one of the following ways:</p> <ul style="margin-left:80px"> 	<li>By completing in high school the third year of one language other than English with minimum grades of C-.</li> 	<li>By completing at Berkeley the second semester of a sequence of courses in one language other than English, or the equivalent at another institution. Only LOTE courses that include reading and composition, as well as conversation, are accepted in satisfaction of this requirement. LOTE courses may be taken on a Pass/No Pass basis.</li> 	<li>By demonstrating equivalent knowledge of a language other than English through examination, including a College Entrance Examination Board (CEEB) Advanced Placement Examination with a score of 3 or higher (if taken before admission to college), an SAT II: Subject Test with a score of 590 or higher, or a proficiency examination offered by some departments at Berkeley or at another campus of the University of California.</li> </ul> <h3><span>Humanities and Social Sciences Breadth Requirement: Chemical Engineering major</span></h3> <ul> 	<li>22 units total; includes Reading and Composition and American Cultures courses</li> 	<li>Breadth Series requirement: As part of the 22 units, students must complete two courses, at least one being upper division, in the same or very closely allied humanities or social science department(s).  AP credit may be used to satisfy the lower division aspect of the requirement.</li> 	<li>Breadth Series courses and all remaining units must come from the following lists of approved humanities and social science courses, excluding courses which only teach a skill (such as drawing or playing an instrument):</li> </ul> <p style="margin-left:120px">Arts and Literature<br/> <a class="ext" href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/approved-foreign-language-courses/" target="_blank">Foreign Language<sup>1,2</sup></a><br/> Historical Studies<br/> International Studies<br/> Philosophy and Values</p> <p style="margin-left:120px">To find course options for breadth, go to the <a class="ext" href="http://classes.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Berkeley Academic Guide Class Schedule</a>, select the term of interest, and use the 'Breadth Requirements' filter to select the breadth area(s) of interest.</p> <ul> 	<li>Breadth courses may be taken on a <em>Pass/No Pass</em> basis (excluding Reading and Composition)<!--class="Mso"--></li> 	<li><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/students/current-undergraduates/exam-credit-info">AP, IB, and GCE A-level exam</a> credit may be used to satisfy the breadth requirement</li> </ul> <p style="margin-left:40px"><sup>1 </sup>Elementary-level courses may not be in the student's native language and may not be structured primarily to teach the reading of scientific literature.</p> <p style="margin-left:40px"><sup>2 </sup>For chemical engineering majors, no more that six units of language other than English may be counted toward the 22 unit breadth requirement.</p> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-8432fa8b-dd75-5af0-9fc4-8d46de66f4f6">Class Schedule Requirements</span></h3> <ul> 	<li>Minimum units per semester: 13</li> 	<li>Maximum units per semester: 19.5</li> 	<li>12 units of course work each semester must satisfy degree requirements</li> 	<li>Chemical Engineering freshmen and Chemistry majors are required to enroll in a minimum of one chemistry course each semester</li> 	<li>After the freshman year, Chemical Engineering majors must enroll in a minimum of one chemical engineering course each semester</li> </ul> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-5e8e789e-dd75-d4eb-596e-c3da6bb449ce">Semester Limit</span></h3> <ul> 	<li> 	<p>Students who entered as freshmen: 8 semesters</p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>Chemistry &amp; Chemical Biology majors who entered as transfer students: 4 semesters</p> 	</li> 	<li>Chemical Engineering and Joint majors who entered as transfer students: 5 semesters</li> </ul> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7fa619cb-dd76-1ab4-4a01-8b481f964cfe">Summer sessions are excluded when determining the limit on semesters. Students who wish to delay graduation to complete a minor, a double major, or simultaneous degrees must request approval for delay of graduation before what would normally be their final two semesters. The College of Chemistry does not have a rule regarding maximum units that a student can accumulate.</span></p> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-b5bce6f8-dd76-5803-9316-546fee20bfb0">Senior Residence</span></h3> <p>After 90 units toward the bachelor’s degree have been completed, at least 24 of the remaining units must be completed in residence in the College of Chemistry, in at least two semesters (the semester in which the 90 units are exceeded, plus at least one additional semester).</p> <p>To count as a semester of residence for this requirement, a program must include at least 4 units of successfully completed courses. A summer session can be credited as a semester in residence if this minimum unit requirement is satisfied.</p> <p>Juniors and seniors who participate in the UC Education Abroad Program (EAP) for a <em>full</em> <em>year</em> may meet a modified senior residence requirement. After 60 units toward the bachelor’s degree have been completed, at least 24 (excluding EAP) of the remaining units must be completed in residence in the College of Chemistry, in at least two semesters. At least 12 of the 24 units must be completed after the student has already completed 90 units. Undergraduate Dean’s approval for the modified senior residence requirement must be obtained before enrollment in the Education Abroad Program.</p> <h3>Minimum Total Units</h3> <p>A student must successfully complete at least 120 semester units in order to graduate.</p> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-f7ca7222-dd76-d461-00af-132b9f50c0a6">Minimum Academic Requirements</span></h3> <p>A student must earn at least a C average (2.0 GPA) in all courses undertaken at UC, including those from UC Summer Sessions, UC Education Abroad Program, and UC Berkeley Washington Program, as well as XB courses from University Extension.</p> <h3>Minimum Course Grade Requirements</h3> <p>Students in the College of Chemistry who receive a grade of D+ or lower in a chemical engineering or chemistry course for which a grade of C- or higher is required must repeat the course at Berkeley.</p> <p>Students in the College of Chemistry must achieve:</p> <ul> 	<li> 	<p>C- or higher in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 4A">CHEM 4A</span></span> before taking <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 4B">CHEM 4B</span></span></p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>C- or higher in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 4B">CHEM 4B</span></span> before taking more advanced courses</p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>C- or higher in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 12A">CHEM 12A</span></span> before taking <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 12B">CHEM 12B</span></span> </p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>GPA of at least 2.0 in all courses taken in the college in order to advance to and continue in the upper division</p> 	</li> </ul> <p>Chemistry or chemical biology majors must also achieve:</p> <ul> 	<li> 	<p>C- or higher in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 120A">CHEM 120A</span></span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 120B">CHEM 120B</span></span> if taken before <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 125">CHEM 125</span></span> or <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM C182">CHEM C182</span></span></p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>2.0 GPA in all upper division courses taken at the University to satisfy major requirements</p> 	</li> </ul> <p>Chemical engineering students must also achieve:</p> <ul> 	<li> 	<p>C- or higher in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 140">CHM ENG 140</span></span> before taking any other CBE courses</p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>C- or higher in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 150A">CHM ENG 150A</span></span> to be eligible to take any other course in the 150 series</p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>2.0 GPA in all upper division courses taken at the University to satisfy major requirements</p> 	</li> </ul> <p>Chemical engineering students who do not achieve a grade of C- or higher in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 140">CHM ENG 140</span></span> on their first attempt are advised to change to another major. If the course is not passed with a grade of C- or higher on the second attempt, continuation in the Chemical Engineering program is normally not allowed.</p> <h3>Minimum Progress</h3> <p>To make normal progress toward a degree, undergraduates must successfully complete 30 units of coursework each year. The continued enrollment of students who do not maintain normal progress will be subject to the approval of the Undergraduate Dean. To achieve minimum academic progress, the student must meet two criteria:</p> <ol> 	<li> 	<p>Completed no fewer units than 15 multiplied by the number of semesters, less one, in which the student has been enrolled at Berkeley. Summer sessions do not count as semesters for this purpose.</p> 	</li> 	<li>A student’s class schedule must contain at least 13 units in any term, unless otherwise authorized by the staff adviser or the Undergraduate Dean.</li> </ol>
]]>
</collegerequirementstext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>The College of Chemistry admits students as first-semester freshmen or as junior transfer students.  The College does not accept spring admits. Spring admits who wish to change into the College of Chemistry must speak with <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/advisers#adv" target="_blank">an Undergraduate Adviser</a> as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Admission to the joint major programs (Chemical Engineering and Materials Science and Chemical Engineering and Nuclear Engineering) is closed to freshmen. Continuing students may petition for a change to a joint major program after their first year.</p>
<h3>Admission as a Freshman</h3>
<p>High school students preparing to major in Chemistry, Chemical Biology, or Chemical Engineering should take the following courses:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Chemistry (one year minimum; two years strongly recommended, including AP Chemistry)</li>
	<li>Physics (one year)</li>
	<li>Mathematics (four years, preferably ending with introductory calculus)</li>
	<li>Foreign language (three years)</li>
</ul>
<h3>Advice for Prospective Freshmen</h3>
<p>Before applying, please take some time to <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/degrees">learn about our majors</a> and make sure that the College of Chemistry is right for you!</p>
<h3>Frequently Asked Questions</h3>
<p><strong>How do I declare my major?</strong></p>
<p>When applying to the College of Chemistry as a Chemistry, Chemical Biology, or Chemical Engineering major, students are officially declaring their major. Students will be expected to enroll in courses that are appropriate for the major starting in the fall semester of their first year.  Students may petition to change into a different major within the College of Chemistry after their first year.</p>
<p><strong>Will I have time to take other courses?</strong></p>
<p>Students have some room in their schedule to explore other subjects and to take breadth electives, but they will be expected to follow the basic program for their major including courses in chemistry, mathematics, and physics.</p>
<p><strong>Can I follow the pre-med path in the College of Chemistry?</strong></p>
<p>Students can prepare for medical, dental, or pharmacy school with a major in the College of Chemistry. Generally, medical schools do not favor any particular undergraduate major. See the <a href="https://career.berkeley.edu/Health/Health.stm" target="_blank">UC Berkeley Career Center web site</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong>Is the College of Chemistry right for me?</strong></p>
<p>Choosing a major is a big decision. Students who are unsure about what they want to study may prefer to apply to the College of Letters and Science where they will have time to explore several different areas before declaring a major.</p>
<p>However, for students who are ready to commit to a course of study in the chemical sciences, the College of Chemistry is a good choice. With an undergraduate population of 900-1000, the College of Chemistry is a small, collegial college within a large cosmopolitan university. Students have access to a broad array of research facilities and other resources, including an in-house Career Counselor, a robust Peer Tutoring Program, and a strong support staff.</p>
<p>Find out more about the College of Chemistry by contacting a <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/advisers#adv" target="_blank">College of Chemistry Academic Adviser</a>.</p>
<h3>Admission as a Transfer Student</h3>
<p>The requirements for entry to the University may be met by establishing a good record at another collegiate institution. Transfer applicants must complete at least 60 semester units or 90 quarter units of UC-transferable course work by the end of the spring term before transferring to UC Berkeley. Students are encouraged to investigate the University-preparatory programs offered by the many community colleges throughout California. If admitted as a transfer student, only up to 70 UC-transferable semester units may be transferred from a community college.</p>
<p>Transfer students may apply to the following majors:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Chemistry</li>
	<li>Chemical Biology</li>
	<li>Chemical Engineering</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Chemistry or Chemical Biology </strong></em>applicants must complete, at a minimum, courses equivalent to the following:</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 1A">CHEM 1A</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 1AL">1AL</span></span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 1B">CHEM 1B</span></span></td><td>General Chemistry<br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and General Chemistry Laboratory</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and General Chemistry</span></td><td class="hourscol">9</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3A">CHEM 3A</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3AL">3AL</span></span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3B">CHEM 3B</span></span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3BL">CHEM 3BL</span></span></td><td>Chemical Structure and Reactivity<br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Organic Chemistry Laboratory</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Chemical Structure and Reactivity</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Organic Chemistry Laboratory</span></td><td class="hourscol">10</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 1A">MATH 1A</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 1B">MATH 1B</span></span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 53">MATH 53</span></span></td><td>Calculus<br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Calculus</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Multivariable Calculus</span></td><td class="hourscol">12</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 7A">PHYSICS 7A</span></td><td>Physics for Scientists and Engineers <sup>1</sup></td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH R1A">ENGLISH R1A</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH R1B">ENGLISH R1B</span></span></td><td>Reading and Composition<br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Reading and Composition</span></td><td class="hourscol">8</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<dl class="sc_footnotes" aria-label="Footnotes"><dt> <sup> 1 </sup> </dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent">Choice of <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 7A">PHYSICS 7A</span></span> or <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 8A">PHYSICS 8A</span></span> for chemical biology majors</p></dd></dl>
<p>In addition, chemistry or chemical biology candidates are encouraged to complete <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 54">MATH 54</span></span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 7B">PHYSICS 7B</span></span> (choice of <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 8B">PHYSICS 8B</span></span> for chemical biology majors). Chemical biology majors are also encouraged to complete <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="BIOLOGY 1A">BIOLOGY 1A</span></span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="BIOLOGY 1AL">BIOLOGY 1AL</span></span>.</p>
<p>Please note that courses taken the summer before enrollment at Berkeley are not considered in the selection of applicants.</p>
<p>Completion of a year of organic chemistry (lecture and lab), with grades of B or better, constitutes satisfactory completion of UC Berkeley's <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 12A">CHEM 12A</span> Organic Chemistry</span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 12B">CHEM 12B</span> Organic Chemistry</span> sequence. If you are admitted, and received below a grade of B in any of your organic chemistry courses, please consult with your CoC adviser.</p>
<p>Completion of the Intersegmental General Education Transfer Curriculum (IGETC) is not required.  However, when completed by the end of the spring term before transferring to UC Berkeley, IGETC is accepted in satisfaction of the English Reading and Composition Requirement and the Foreign Language Requirement (IGETC does not necessarily satisfy the entire breadth requirement).</p>
<p>Transfer applicants need grades of A or B in math and science courses to be adequately prepared to continue with junior-level courses.</p>
<p><em><strong>Chemical Engineering </strong></em>applicants must complete, at a minimum, courses equivalent to the following:</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 1A">CHEM 1A</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 1AL">1AL</span></span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 1B">CHEM 1B</span></span></td><td>General Chemistry<br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and General Chemistry Laboratory</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and General Chemistry</span></td><td class="hourscol">9</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 1A">MATH 1A</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 1B">MATH 1B</span></span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 53">MATH 53</span></span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 54">MATH 54</span></span></td><td>Calculus<br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Calculus</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Multivariable Calculus</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Linear Algebra and Differential Equations</span></td><td class="hourscol">16</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 7A">PHYSICS 7A</span><br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">&amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 7B">PHYSICS 7B</span></span></td><td>Physics for Scientists and Engineers<br/><span style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">and Physics for Scientists and Engineers</span></td><td class="hourscol">8</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGLISH R1A">ENGLISH R1A</span></td><td>Reading and Composition</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="listsum"><td colspan="2">Total Units</td><td class="hourscol">37</td></tr></tbody></table>

<p>In addition, chemical engineering candidates are encouraged to complete <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 7">ENGIN 7</span> Introduction to Computer Programming for Scientists and Engineers</span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MAT SCI 45">MAT SCI 45</span> Properties of Materials</span> plus <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MAT SCI 45L">MAT SCI 45L</span></span>, if available. Chemical engineering applicants are also encouraged to complete <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="BIOLOGY 1A">BIOLOGY 1A</span></span>, as well as <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3A">CHEM 3A</span> Chemical Structure and Reactivity</span>, <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3AL">CHEM 3AL</span> Organic Chemistry Laboratory</span>, <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3B">CHEM 3B</span> Chemical Structure and Reactivity</span>, and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 3BL">CHEM 3BL</span> Organic Chemistry Laboratory</span>.</p>
<p>Please note that courses taken the summer before enrollment at Berkeley are not considered in the selection of applicants.</p>
<p>Completion of a year of organic chemistry (lecture and lab), with grades of B or better, constitutes satisfactory completion of UC Berkeley's <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 12A">CHEM 12A</span> Organic Chemistry</span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 12B">CHEM 12B</span> Organic Chemistry</span> sequence. If you are admitted, and received below a grade of B in any of your organic chemistry courses, please consult with your CoC adviser.</p>
<p>Completion of the Intersegmental General Education Transfer Curriculum (IGETC) is not required.  However, when completed by the end of the spring term before transferring to UC Berkeley, IGETC is accepted in satisfaction of the English Reading and Composition Requirement and the Foreign Language Requirement (IGETC does not necessarily satisfy the entire breadth requirement).</p>
<p>Transfer applicants need grades of A or B in math and science courses to be adequately prepared to continue with junior-level courses.</p>
<p>Applicants must satisfy <a href="http://admission.universityofcalifornia.edu/counselors/transfer/minimum-requirements/">UC minimum admissions requirements</a>.  For questions about admission as a transfer student, contact <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/advisers">the Undergraduate Advising office</a>.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<advisingtext name="Advising">
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/advisers#adv" target="_blank"><strong>The College of Chemistry Undergraduate Advising team</strong> </a>supports student success by helping students define and achieve their academic and personal goals. Advisers guide students in course selection, completion of degree requirements, and other academic decision-making. They serve as a resource for information about research and internship opportunities, enrichment programs, and a wide variety of campus support services. Their goal is to empower students to create a meaningful educational experience at UC Berkeley.</p>
<p>Each College of Chemistry student also has a <a href="https://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/faculty-mentoring" target="_blank"><strong>Faculty Mentor</strong></a>, who provides professional mentoring in Chemistry, Chemical Biology, or Chemical Engineering. Students meet with their Faculty Mentor at least once per semester to discuss course planning, research, and professional development.</p>
<p>Finally, College of Chemistry <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/peer-advising" target="_blank"><strong>Peer Advisers</strong> </a>offer an essential student perspective on academic and co-curricular issues and opportunities. They hold office hours in the Undergraduate Advising Center and maintain an active social media presence.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Advising Contact Information</h3>
<p>Prof. John Arnold, Undergraduate Dean<br/>
<a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/mailto:undergrad.dean@cchem.berkeley.edu">undergrad.dean@cchem.berkeley.edu</a> </p>
<p>Maura Daly, Director of Undergraduate Student Services + Adviser for Last Names Y-Z<br/>
510-643-0550; <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/colleges-schools/chemistry/mailto:mdaly@berkeley.edu">mdaly@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<p>Korshid Tarin, Change of College Adviser + Last Names A-G<br/>
510-642-3451; ktarin@berkeley.edu</p>
<p>Jahzeel Flores Morales, Adviser for Last Names H-R<br/>
510-642-7919; jahzeel_flores@berkeley.edu</p>
<p>Shamaya Pellum, Adviser for Last Names S-X + L&amp;S Chemistry BA<br/>
510-643-1745; spellum@berkeley.edu</p>
<p><span>Maritsi Perez, Intake Adviser<br/>
510-664-5264; maritsip@berkeley.edu</span></p>
<p><span>Address</span></p>
<p>College of Chemistry Undergraduate Student Services<br/>
Que Family Undergraduate Advising Center<br/>
121 Gilman Hall, #1460<br/>
University of California, Berkeley<br/>
Berkeley, CA  94720-1460</p>
<h4>Web Information</h4>
<p>College of Chemistry Undergraduate Information<br/>
<a href="https://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/student-services" target="_blank">http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/student-services</a></p>
<p>Degree Program Information<br/>
<a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/student_info/undergrad_info/degree_programs/" target="_blank">http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/student_info/undergrad_info/degree_programs/</a></p>
]]>
</advisingtext>
<academicopportunitiestext name="Academic Opportunities">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Awards &amp; Scholarships</h3>
<p>The College of Chemistry offers a number of awards and scholarships to its currently enrolled sophomores, juniors, and seniors. </p>
<h3>College of Chemistry Scholars Program</h3>
<p>The <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/scholars-program">College of Chemistry Scholars Program</a> promotes and advances the educational and career opportunities of students from underrepresented groups in the fields of chemistry and chemical engineering. </p>
<h3>College of Chemistry Teacher-Scholars Program</h3>
<p>The <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/teacher-scholars">College of Chemistry Teacher-Scholars Program</a> enables undergraduate students to participate in the instruction of lower division chemistry courses. The program fosters a sense of community in chemistry courses, and enhances conceptual learning via one-on-one interactions between students and instructors.  Participants gain a sound understanding of instructional techniques and strategies while earning two units of <em>Pass/No Pass</em> credit.</p>
<h3>Dean’s Honor List</h3>
<p>A list comprised of students who attain a term-GPA of 3.9 or higher, published every semester.</p>
<h3>Honors Program</h3>
<p>Students may earn Honors with the Bachelor's Degree in Chemistry, Chemical Biology, or Chemical Engineering by conducting research for at least three semesters, maintaining a GPA of at least 3.4, and producing a senior honors thesis. </p>
<h3>Study Abroad</h3>
<p>The College of Chemistry encourages all undergraduates in the college to study abroad.  Whether students are interested in fulfilling breadth requirements, taking courses related to their major/career, or simply living and studying in another country, the College will work with them to make it happen.</p>
<h3><span>Undergraduate Research</span></h3>
<p>College of Chemistry students are encouraged to do research for credit under the direction of a faculty member. Students follow their own scientific interests in the selection of research projects. Such research usually involves experimental, theoretical, or computational work within the context of funded research directed by a faculty member in the College of Chemistry or in other departments on campus.  Please go to the <a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/ugrad/current-students/research">Undergraduate Research page</a> for more information.</p>
]]>
</academicopportunitiestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

