<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Endocrinology</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p class="Normal1">The faculty associated with the Graduate Group in Endocrinology have diverse interests representing endocrinology in the broadest sense: chemical mediators in the living world directed by autocrine, paracrine, endocrine, and ectohormonal factors. Our program faculty encompasses hormone-oriented research programs such as cancer biology, signal transduction, drug design, membrane biology, virology, metabolism, differentiation, morphogenesis, toxicology, and gene transcription. Graduates from the endocrinology program have transitioned into careers in a variety of fields including education, research (in both academic and industry settings), government regulation, and private business.</p>
<p class="Normal1">The main goal of the graduate program is to engage students in the interdisciplinary aspects of the field of endocrinology through seminars, courses, and our diverse faculty research perspectives; which range from organismal and comparative endocrinology to chemical ecology to structural, molecular, and cellular endocrinology.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in endocrinology.</p>
<h3>Graduate Programs</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/endocrinology/">Endocrinology</a>: MA, PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Gregory W. Aponte, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Regulation of epithelial cell motility and differentiation by neuropeptides.<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/users/gregory-w-aponte"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George E. Bentley, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Avian reproductive biology, neuroendocrinology and behavior.<br/><a href="http://ib.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/bentleyg"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mina Bissell, <i>Principal Scientist</i>. </strong>Regulation of tissue-specific gene expression in normal and malignant breast cells.<br/><a href="http://www2.lbl.gov/LBL-Programs/lifesciences/BissellLab/main.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gertrude C. Buehring, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Etiology and prevention of breast cancer.<br/><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/gertrude-case-buehring-phd"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Danica Chen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Calorie restriction, oxidative stress, stem cell aging, tissue maintenance and metabolic disease.<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/users/danica-chen"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Gary L. Firestone, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Hormone and phytochemical regulation of human cancer cell signaling and gene expression.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/CDB/firestoneg.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Tyrone B. Hayes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Amphibian developmental endocrinology.<br/><a href="http://ib.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/hayest"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lin He, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Non-coding RNA regulation of cancer cell gene expression and stem cell differentiation.<br/><a href="https://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/CDB/hel.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marc Hellerstein, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Intracellular metabolic processes.<br/><a href="http://www.cnr.berkeley.edu/hellerstein-lab/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sona Kang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Influence of epigenetic events on cellular metabolism and adipose biology.<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/users/sona-kang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniela Kaufer, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Stress and steroid hormones effects on the brain.<br/><a href="http://ib.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/kauferd"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>'* Lance J. Kriegsfeld, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Neuroendocrinology, reproductive biology, and biological timing.<br/><a href="http://ist-socrates.berkeley.edu/~ljkriegs/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Polina V. Lishko, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Cell biology of mammalian fertilization and steroid control of ion channels.<br/><a href="http://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/CDB/lishkop.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kunxin Luo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Signal transduction pathways in mammary stem/progenitor cells and breast cancer progression.<br/><a href="https://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/CDB/luok.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel K. Nomura, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mapping metabolism in human disease.<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/users/daniel-nomura"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kaoru Saijo, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Nuclear Receptor-mediated regulation of Neuroinflammation.<br/><a href="https://mcb.berkeley.edu/faculty/IMM/saijok.html"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andreas Stahl, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular biology of obesity related disorders.<br/><a href="http://nature.berkeley.edu/stahllab"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hei Sook Sul, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Hormonal regulation of lipid metabolism and adipocyte differentiation.<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/users/hei-sook-sul"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jen-Chywan (Wally) Wang, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mechanisms of glucocorticoid receptor-regulated metabolism.<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/users/jen-chywan-wally-wang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

