<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Infectious Diseases and Immunity</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Infectious Diseases and Immunity (IDI) provides opportunities for the study of the biology of infectious agents, their interaction with human and other hosts, and their relationship with the environment. The program is unique in its emphasis on integrated multidisciplinary training in host-pathogen environmental interactions. Important areas of inquiry include the biology of host-pathogen interactions; molecular and cellular aspects of pathogenesis; the ecology and evolution of disease agents; environmental factors in transmission; intermediate hosts and vectors; the biology of surveillance and epidemiological analysis; vaccine and drug development; and public health practices for disease prevention and control.</p>
<p>The objective of this program is to provide students with research-oriented pursuits that will train them to design and implement independent investigations. The goal is to promote health by integration of basic research and applied technologies for the development of new approaches for the diagnosis, treatment, prevention, and control of infectious disease in humans.</p>
<p>Students matriculating through this program will acquire expertise in fundamental infectious disease research and thus are well prepared for careers in academia, governmental agencies, and biotechnology. For admission requirements and application process, visit both the <a href="http://idi.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">IDI website</a> and the <a href="https://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">Grad Division website</a> for details. Application deadline: December 1st for the following year's fall semester admission.</p>
<p>For a full list of IDI faculty, please visit the <a href="https://publichealth.berkeley.edu/academics/infectious-diseases-and-vaccinology/infectious-diseases-and-immunity-phd/ ">IDI website</a>.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Infectious Diseases and Immunity.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/infectious-diseases-immunity/">Infectious Diseases and Immunity</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

