<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Business Administration and Engineering: MBA/MEng</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>UC Berkeley’s integrated Master's of Business Administration/Master's of Engineering (MBA/MEng) program is designed to prepare students to become leaders in technological innovation in an array of different industries. It enables students to earn two master's degrees in the time it would normally take to earn only one, and at a lower cost than enrolling in each program separately. Applicants who have a technical undergraduate education can normally complete this program in four semesters.</p>
<p>Students will earn a Master of Business Administration (MBA) degree from the Haas School of Business and a Master of Engineering (MEng) degree from one of seven departments in the College of Engineering:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Bioengineering</li>
	<li>Civil and Environmental Engineering</li>
	<li>Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</li>
	<li>Industrial Engineering and Operations Research</li>
	<li>Materials Science and Engineering</li>
	<li>Mechanical Engineering</li>
	<li>Nuclear Engineering</li>
</ul>
<p>The concurrent degree program is designed to help address the need in the high-tech industry for leaders who possess both technical skills and business acumen. Academic excellence combined with the innovation culture of the San Francisco Bay Area makes UC Berkeley the perfect place to prepare graduates from this selective program to be leaders in technological innovation and entrepreneurship. Students will take both business and engineering courses, and they will participate in courses and interdisciplinary projects designed especially for the concurrent program. Employment opportunities abound, from Silicon Valley to Wall Street to locations around the world.</p>
<p>Curricular details can be found at the &quot;Master's Degree Requirements&quot; tab in the upper right of this page.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>MBA/MEng program applicants must complete the </span><a href="https://applynow.haas.berkeley.edu/apply" target="_blank">MBA application</a><span> form and select the concurrent degree program. Applicants will be considered for admission to both departments and a combined committee will make decisions on admission to the concurrent program. Applicants who are admitted to only one of the two programs may enroll in that program. When applying, applicants must indicate their first choice and second choice (optional) among the seven departments in the College of Engineering.</span></p>
<h3>Admission to the University</h3>
<div>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
</div>
<div> </div>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<mastersdegreerequirementstext name="Master's Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p class="introtext"><span>Students will earn a Master of Business Administration (MBA) degree from the Haas School of Business and a Master of Engineering (MEng) degree from one of seven departments in the College of Engineering:</span></p>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p class="introtext">Bioengineering</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p class="introtext">Civil and Environmental Engineering</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p class="introtext">Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p class="introtext">Industrial Engineering and Operations Research</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p class="introtext">Materials Science and Engineering</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p class="introtext">Mechanical Engineering</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p class="introtext">Nuclear Engineering</p>
	</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="introtext">MBA Requirements</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist fullHeight" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 200A">MBA 200A</span></td><td>Data Analytics</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 200C">MBA 200C</span></td><td>Leadership Communication</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 200D">MBA 200D</span></td><td>Data-Driven Presentations: Making the Business Case</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 200S">MBA 200S</span></td><td>Data and Decisions</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 201A">MBA 201A</span></td><td>Economics for Business Decision Making</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 201B">MBA 201B</span></td><td>Macroeconomics in the Global Economy</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 202">MBA 202</span></td><td>Financial Accounting</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 203">MBA 203</span></td><td>Introduction to Finance</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 204">MBA 204</span></td><td>Operations</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 205">MBA 205</span></td><td>Leading People</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 205D">MBA 205D</span></td><td>Business Communication in Diverse Work Environments</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 206">MBA 206</span></td><td>Marketing</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 207">MBA 207</span></td><td>Ethics and Responsible Business Leadership</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 299">MBA 299</span></td><td>Strategic Leadership</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">MBA Electives</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Six units of courses designed for the concurrent program or chosen from an approved list</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Twelve units of other MBA electives including an Applied Innovation course</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3 class="introtext">General MEng Requirements</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 270B">ENGIN 270B</span></td><td>R&amp;D Technology Management &amp; Ethics</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 270C">ENGIN 270C</span></td><td>Teaming &amp; Project Management</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3 class="introtext">Required Interdisciplinary Project</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even lastrow firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 296MS">ENGIN 296MS</span></td><td>Capstone Project Course</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3>Departmental MEng Requirements </h3>
<p>Further courses will be required to complete the Engineering degree within the chosen department. See below for details.</p>
<h5><span class="acronym">BIOENGINEERING</span></h5>
<p>Students must complete 12 units of approved graduate-level coursework in one of the concentrations listed on the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/bioengineering/#mastersdegreerequirementstext">Bioengineering MEng program page</a> or select their own courses with the approval of the <span id="docs-internal-guid-76b2f727-7fff-a6c4-f3a7-f12c694739fd">Bioengineering </span>MEng faculty advisor.</p>
<h5 class="introtext"><strong>CIVIL &amp; ENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEERING (CEE)</strong></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-03e31413-7fff-da18-5245-75f9fa8568c4">Students must complete 12 units of approved graduate-level coursework to satisfy one of the concentrations</span><span> (Systems Engineering and Transportation Engineering) listed on the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/civil-environmental-engineering/#mastersdegreerequirementsmengtext">Civil and Environmental Engineering MEng program page</a>. </span><span>Course substitutions may be allowed with the consent of the CEE MEng faculty advisor.</span></p>
<h5>ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING &amp; COMPUTER SCIENCE (EECS)</h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-1f334e72-7fff-460e-74d6-0e84488d6857">Students must complete four approved graduate-level courses chosen from the “Four Graduate Level Classes” subsection within the “Curriculum” section</span><span> available on the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/electrical-engineering-computer-sciences/#mastersdegreerequirementsmengtext">Electrical Engineering &amp; Computer Science MEng program page</a>. </span><span>MBA/MEng students may spread these four courses across the four semesters in their program. Other graduate-level courses in the department may be approved with the consent of the EECS MEng faculty advisor.</span></p>
<h5>INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING &amp; OPERATIONS RESEARCH (IEOR)</h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-e4ce0878-7fff-3924-a794-2d437d6e68d6">Students must complete the technical coursework requirements described on the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/industrial-engineering/#mastersdegreerequirementstext">Industrial Engineering &amp; Operations Research MEng program page</a>, </span><span>which consists of two required courses (<span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="IND ENG 240">IND ENG 240</span></span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="IND ENG 241">IND ENG 241</span></span>) and six units of technical electives. </span><span id="docs-internal-guid-532443d1-7fff-09f3-5561-b5498863d342">Course substitutions may be allowed with the consent of the IEOR MEng faculty advisor.</span></p>
<h5><span>MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; ENGINEERING</span></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-89e5964e-7fff-ff6a-d5ff-461bace19fe1">Students must complete 12 units of approved graduate-level coursework in one of the concentrations listed on the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/materials-science-engineering/#mastersdegreerequirementsmengtext">Materials Science &amp; Engineering MEng program page</a>. </span><span>The General Concentration allows students to tailor their program of study to their interests.</span></p>
<h5>MECHANICAL  ENGINEERING</h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Students must complete 12 units of approved graduate-level coursework in one of the following concentrations:</span></p>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Advanced Energy Technology</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Aerospace Engineering</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Biomechanics </span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Control of Robotic and Autonomous Systems</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Fluids and Ocean </span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Mems/Nano</span> </p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Mechanics and Dynamics </span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Modeling &amp; Simulation of Advanced Manufacturing Processes</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">Product Design</span></p>
	</li>
</ul>
<p><br/>
<span id="docs-internal-guid-b18111de-7fff-a9ad-145e-57f36924a733">More details on the concentrations are available on the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/mechanical-engineering/#mastersdegreerequirementsmengtex">Mechanical Engineering MEng program page</a>.</span> Course substitutions may be allowed with the consent of the department ME MEng faculty advisor.</p>
<h5>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING</h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-48903ed8-7fff-d711-4758-998e6defe646">Students must complete 12 units of approved graduate-level coursework (graded lecture courses) in the department. Please see the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/nuclear-engineering/#mastersdegreerequirementsmengtex">Nuclear Engineering MEng program page</a> </span><span>for information on course lists for optional technical concentrations. These lists provide suggested courses for students with specific interests.</span></p>
]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

