<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Logic and the Methodology of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Group in Logic and the Methodology of Science offers an interdisciplinary program of study and research leading to the PhD degree. Although the Department of Mathematics and the Department of Philosophy each offers a PhD degree toward which a student may write a dissertation in logic, the interdisciplinary program is designed for students with a broad interest in logic and the methodology of science who wish to explore the subject in both its mathematical and philosophical aspects. Here, methodology of science is understood to mean metascience, the study of the methods of the sciences by logical and mathematical means. The program is administered by an interdepartmental group which cooperates closely with the Computer Science Division, the Department of Mathematics, and the Department of Philosophy.</p>
<h3>Tarski Lectures</h3>
<p>Following the death of group founder Alfred Tarski in 1983, an endowment fund was established in his memory. Using income from this fund, a series of annual Alfred Tarski Lectures was inaugurated in 1989. Each spring, an outstanding scholar in a field to which Tarski contributed is selected to come to UC Berkeley and meet with faculty and students and to deliver several lectures. To see the schedule of these lectures, visit the <a href="http://logic.berkeley.edu/tarski-lectures.html">group's website</a>.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Logic and the Methodology of Science.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/logic-methodology-science/">Logic and the Methodology of Science</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Wesley H. Holliday, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Philosophy, logic.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16271"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Macfarlane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ancient philosophy, philosophical logic, philosophy of language, epistemology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14565"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Paolo Mancosu, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Philosophy, philosophy of mathematics and its history, philosophy of logic, mathematical logic.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15059"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Antonio Montalban, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mathematical logic.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16404"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stuart Russell, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Artificial intelligence, computational biology, algorithms, machine learning, real-time decision-making, probabilistic reasoning.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/stuart-j-russell"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Thomas Scanlon, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mathematics, model theory, applications to number theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15412"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sanjit Seshia, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Electronic design automation, theory, computer security, program analysis, dependable computing, computational logic, formal methods.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sanjit-seshia"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Pierre Simon, <i>Associate Professor </i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Theodore A. Slaman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mathematics, recursion theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15456"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hans Sluga, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Political philosophy, recent European philosophy, history of analytic philosophy, Frege, Wittgenstein, Foucault.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15462"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Steel, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mathematics, descriptive set theory, set theory, fine structure.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15675"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Umesh Vazirani, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Quantum computation, hamiltonian complexity, analysis of algorithms.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15573"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Seth Yalcin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Philosophy of language, logic, philosophy of mind, cognitive science, semantics, metaphysics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16255"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>John W. Addison, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Mathematics, theory of definability, descriptive set theory, model theory, recursive function theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14364"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Robert Anderson, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Finance, probability theory, mathematical economics, nonstandard analysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14042"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles S. Chihara, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alan D. Code, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leo A. Harrington, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Mathematics, model theory, recursion theory, set theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14792"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Richard Karp, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Computational molecular biology, genomics, DNA molecules, structure of genetic regulatory networks, combinatorial and statsitical methods.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/richard-karp"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Paul Kay, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Linguistics, sociolinguistics, linguistic anthropology, pragmatics, syntax, semantics, lexicon, grammar, color naming, lexical semantics, grammatical variation, cross-language color naming, the encoding of contextual relations in rules of grammar.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14914"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ralph N. McKenzie, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Mathematics, logic, universal algebra, general algebra, lattice theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15337"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>W. Hugh Woodin, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Mathematics, set theory, large cardinals.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15714"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

