<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Academic Policies</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0bf4181-1285-a327-40a8-231ef56db8cd">Academic policies and procedures allow students to clearly understand their rights and responsibilities. They protect the integrity of the UC Berkeley degree and provide fair and transparent guidelines for activities related to teaching and learning across campus. </span></p>
<p>UC Berkeley students are expected to familiarize themselves with all academic policies. Students seeking clarity on academic policies relevant to or beyond those stated on this website should consult with the appropriate office. </p>
<p>Please access the tabbed content on this page to learn more about policies relating to student conduct, grades, graduation and more. </p>
  
]]>
</text>
<semestersystemunitsrepetitionofcoursestext name="Semester System, Units, &amp; Repetition of Courses">
<![CDATA[
<div>
<h3>The Semester System</h3>
</div>
<div>
<p>Under the semester system on the UC Berkeley campus, the academic year is divided into two semesters and one summer session. Quarter units, either earned previously at Berkeley or at another institution, are converted to semester units by multiplying by two-thirds (for example, 180 quarter units equal 120 semester units).</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Courses and Units</h3>
<p>Most University courses are assigned a unit value. One unit represents three hours of work per week by the student, including class attendance, preparation, and outside work.</p>
<h4>Course Number Guide</h4>
 <p>For an explanation of the prefixes, suffixes, and course numbering system used in UC Berkeley's <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/courses" target="_blank">course listings</a>, please see the guide provided below.</p> <h3>Prefixes to Course Numbers</h3> <p><strong>C =</strong> Course is cross-listed with another department<br/> <strong>H =</strong> Honors course<br/> <strong>N =</strong> Summer-only course not equivalent to a regular session course with the same number<br/> <strong>R =</strong> Satisfies Reading and Composition (R &amp; C) requirement<br/> <strong>W =</strong> Offered fully or predominantly online (prefix no longer required for online courses)</p> <hr/> <h3>Suffixes to Course Numbers</h3> <p><strong>AC =</strong> Satisfies American Cultures requirement</p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-272b5241-7fff-fb24-8009-399a578519c2">Students should check with their major or minor advising unit to verify which courses will satisfy curriculum requirements.</span></p> <hr/> <h3>Key to Course Numbers</h3> <p><strong>1-99 =</strong> Lower division (undergraduate) courses<br/> <strong>100-199 =</strong> Upper division (undergraduate) courses<br/> <strong>200-299 = </strong>Graduate courses<br/> <strong>300-399 =</strong> Professional courses for teachers and prospective teachers<br/> <strong>400-499 =</strong> Other professional courses (acceptable toward academic degrees only within limitations prescribed by a college, school, or the Graduate Division)<br/> <strong>601 =</strong> Special study for graduate students in preparation for master's examination<br/> <strong>602 =</strong> Special study for graduate students in preparation for doctoral qualifying examination</p> <hr/> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 24, 39, &amp; 84</strong></h5> <p>Freshman and Sophomore Seminars<br/> For further information, please see the <a href="http://fss.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Freshman and Sophomore Seminars at Berkeley website</a>.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 97</strong></h5> <p>Field Studies (lower division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. <span id="docs-internal-guid-d7e644cf-7fff-1b43-631c-e4648de38152">You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester</span>. Courses with this number are restricted to <em>passed/not passed </em>grading. To take them you must be in good academic standing (2.00 GPA or better). A written proposal for each Field Studies Course, signed by the faculty sponsor, must receive approval by the Chair of the Department. In certain cases, exceptions to these rules may be granted by the dean of your college or school.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 98</strong></h5> <p>Organized Group Study (lower division) <br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. Each section of a 98 course must receive approval by the chair of the department, based upon a written proposal submitted by the instructor who is to supervise the course that describes the matter to be studied, the methods of instruction, the number of units to be credited, and methods of evaluation of student performance. A copy of the approved proposal must be submitted for information to the Committee on Courses of Instruction. Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed </em>is to be assigned. In certain cases, the dean of your college or school may authorize exceptions to these limitations.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 99</strong></h5> <p>Supervised Independent Study by academically superior students (lower division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. You must have a 3.3 GPA and prior consent of the instructor who is to supervise the study, and you must submit a written proposal to the chair of the department (or equivalent) for approval. <span id="docs-internal-guid-fa9b52ef-7fff-ecdc-795c-fdade3a5043a">The proposal must specify the nature of the study, number of units to be credited, and the basis for grading. </span>Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed</em> is to be assigned. In certain cases, the dean of your college or school may authorize exceptions to these limitations.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 197</strong></h5> <p>Field Studies (upper division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. Courses with this number are restricted to <em>passed/not passed </em>grading. A written proposal for each Field Studies Course, signed by the faculty sponsor, must receive approval by the Chair of the Department. In certain cases, exceptions to these rules may be granted by the dean of your college or school.</p> <h5><strong>Courses numbered 198</strong></h5> <p>Organized Group Study (upper division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. Each section of a 198 course must receive approval by the chair of the department, based upon a written proposal submitted by the instructor who is to supervise the course that describes the matter to be studied, the methods of instruction, the number of units to be credited, and methods of evaluation of student performance. A copy of the approved proposal must be submitted for information to the Committee on Courses of Instruction. To enroll in 198 courses, you must be in good academic standing (2.00 GPA or better). Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed </em>is to be assigned. <span id="docs-internal-guid-e95f35e1-7fff-531d-d5c2-49d453908f51">In certain cases, exceptions to these rules may be granted by the dean of your college or school.</span></p> <h5><strong>Courses numbered 199</strong></h5> <p>Supervised Independent Study (upper division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. You must have prior approval of your major adviser, the instructor who is to supervise the study, and the chair of the department. Approval must be based on a written proposal that you submit to the chair that specifies the nature of the study, the number of units to be credited, and the basis for grading. To enroll in 199 courses, you must be in good academic standing (2.00 GPA or better). Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed</em> will be assigned. In certain cases, the dean of your college or school may authorize exceptions to these limitations.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 601 &amp; 602</strong></h5> <p>Individual Study (601 – master level, 602 – doctoral level)<br/> You may enroll in no more than 8 semester units of courses numbered 601 or 602 to meet the requirements for a master’s or doctoral degree, up to 4 units per summer session. Only a grade of <em>satisfactory/unsatisfactory</em> will be assigned. Enrollment in these courses must be approved by the student’s graduate advisor. Units earned in these courses may not be used to meet academic residence of unit requirements towards a degree.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Repetition of Courses</h3>
<p>You may repeat only courses in which you received a grade of D+, D, D-, F, NP, or U. You may repeat an I grade subject to certain limitations (see Grade I). Courses in which you received a grade of D+, D, D-, or F, and courses that you undertook for a letter grade but for which you received a grade of I, may not be repeated on a passed/not passed or satisfactory/unsatisfactory basis. Repetition of a course more than once requires approval by the dean of the college, school, or division in which you are enrolled at the time you repeat the course. Without this approval, a course repeated more than once will not be included in the grade point average (GPA), but a passing grade in the repeated course will be accepted in satisfaction of unit requirements for the degree. Degree credit for a repeated course will be given only once, but the grade assigned at each enrollment is permanently recorded. If you repeat courses in which you received a grade of D+, D, D-, or F, the units are counted only once and only the most recently earned grades and grade points are used for the first 12 units repeated. Second repetitions that are approved by the dean of a student's college or school are to be included in the 12-unit limitation. In case of repetitions beyond the 12 units, the GPA is based on all grades assigned and total units attempted. If, however, you receive a grade of I upon repetition of a course, the grade of D+, D, D-, or F will continue to be computed in the GPA until the I grade is replaced. <span id="docs-internal-guid-69304604-7fff-dfca-350f-666b9eb5ea34"> If you repeat an I in a letter-graded course, the I will lapse to an F unless you have permission from the dean of your college or school to retain the I grade for a longer period.</span></p>
</div>
]]>
</semestersystemunitsrepetitionofcoursestext>
<gradestext name="Grades">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>The work of all students on the UC Berkeley campus is reported in terms of the following grades: A (excellent); B (good); C (fair); D (barely passed); F (failure); P (passed at a minimum level of C- for undergraduate students); NP (not passed); S (satisfactory, passed at a minimum level of B- for graduate students); U (unsatisfactory); I (work incomplete due to circumstances beyond the student’s control, but of passing quality); and IP (work in progress, final grade to be assigned upon completion of entire course sequence). The grades A, B, C, and D may be modified by plus (+) or minus (-) suffixes.</span></p>
<p>A course in which the grade A, B, C, D, or P (undergraduate students only) is counted toward degree requirements, as outlined in the regulations of a student's college or major. A course receiving the grade S (graduate students only) is similarly counted subject to Academic Senate regulations. A course in which the grade F, NP, or U is received is not counted toward degree requirements. A course in which the grade of I or IP is received is not counted toward degree requirements until the I or IP is replaced by grade A, B, C, D, P, or S.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Grade Points</h3>
<p>Grade points per unit are assigned as follows: A=4, B=3, C=2, D=1, and F=none. When attached to the grades A, B, C, or D, plus (+) grades carry three-tenths of a grade point more per unit, and minus (-) grades three-tenths of a grade point less per unit than unsuffixed grades, except for A+, which carries 4.0 grade points per unit as does the A.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Grade Point Average (GPA)</h3>
<p>Your GPA is computed on courses undertaken in the University of California. Effective fall 2005, XB courses undertaken in UC Berkeley Extension count toward your GPA. Grades A, B, C, D, and F are used in determining your GPA; grades IP, P, S, NP, and U carry no grade points and are excluded from all grade-point computations. Grade I, if assigned before fall 1973, is included and is computed as an F; an I grade assigned fall 1973 and later is excluded from computations. For additional information, see the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/academic-policies/#semestersystemunitsrepetitionofcoursestext">Repetition of Courses</a> section<a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/academic-policies/" target="_blank">.</a></p>
<hr/>
<h3>Special Provisions: Graduate Students</h3>
<p>Only courses graded A, B, C (with or without plus or minus signs), or S are accepted in satisfaction of degree requirements. Courses graded below C- do not yield unit credit toward a higher degree, regardless of your overall GPA. Graduate students must maintain a minimum GPA of 3.0 in all upper division and graduate coursework undertaken in graduate standing in the University of California or its exchange programs.</p>
<p><em>Note: </em>Departments, schools, and groups may have a higher performance standard than the minimum B average (3.0 GPA) required by the Graduate Division. You must also work full time at your academic or professional program unless a program with fewer units is approved under special circumstances by your graduate adviser. In addition, you must successfully complete all coursework required by your department, school, or group program, be advanced to candidacy, pass the required examinations, and fulfill other requirements specified for the program.</p>
<p>For a course extending over more than one semester in which evaluation of your performance is deferred until the end of the final semester, provisional grades of In Progress (IP) may be assigned in the intervening semesters. The provisional grades are replaced by the final grade if you complete the full sequence. If you do not complete the full sequence, then you will be given an I grade if the instructor has no other basis for assigning a grade. Further changes will be made according to Academic Senate regulations.</p>
<p>With the consent of the department involved, graduate students may enroll in courses in the 600-series. These courses are evaluated by means of the grades satisfactory and unsatisfactory (S and U). They prepare you for appropriate master’s or doctoral examinations and do not count toward academic residence or the unit requirements for a higher degree. You may earn 1-8 units of 601 or 602 per semester or 1-4 units per summer session toward examination preparation. Units earned in these courses may not be used to meet academic residence or unit requirements for the Master or Doctor's degree. No credit is allowed for work graded unsatisfactory.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Passed/Not Passed and Satisfactory/ Unsatisfactory Grades</h3>
<p>If you are an undergraduate in good academic standing (2.0 GPA or better, or in good academic standing under the academic probation regulations of your college or school), you may elect to take letter-graded courses on a passed/not passed basis, and if you are a graduate student in good academic standing, you may elect to take letter-graded courses on a satisfactory/unsatisfactory basis with the consent of your department, school, or group. Credit for courses taken on these bases is limited to one-third of the total units that you have taken and passed on the Berkeley campus at the time your degree is awarded. Included in this one-third are any units completed in an Education Abroad program, or on another University of California campus in an intercampus exchange program, or in a joint doctoral program. For graduate degree programs, grades of satisfactory assigned in courses numbered 299 and of the 300, 400, or 600 series are excluded from this computation. If you enroll in a course offered only on a passed/not passed or satisfactory/unsatisfactory basis, you will be graded P/NP if an undergraduate and S/U if a graduate.</p>
<p>A course that is required in or prerequisite to your major may be taken on a P/NP or S/U basis only upon approval of the faculty of your school or college.</p>
<p>If you are a special or limited-status student, you may take courses on a P/NP basis at the discretion of the dean of your college or school. You may not repeat a course on a P/NP basis that you have previously taken on a letter-graded basis.</p>
<p>The option of being graded P/NP or S/U in a course may be cancelled if you are found to be ineligible for the option.</p>
<p>If you want honors at graduation, you should consult your college, school, or division for additional restrictions.</p>
<p>Your level of performance must correspond to a minimum letter grade of C- if you are to receive a passed grade, and to a B- if you are to receive a satisfactory grade.</p>
<p>These rules may be further limited by the faculties of the various schools and colleges and by the Graduate Council.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Grade I (Incomplete)</h3>
<p>The grade I may be assigned if your work in a course has been of passing quality, but is incomplete for reasons beyond your control. Prior arrangements must be made with the instructor because in assigning the I grade the instructor is required to specify the reasons to the department chair.</p>
<p>For graduate students, the I grade will remain on the record until the required work is completed. Graduate students should finish the course requirements as soon as possible. The instructor will file a change of grade for Incompletes through CalCentral and Campus Solutions. The method of replacement of the I grade by a final grade will be determined by the Dean of the Graduate Division and the Graduate Council. </p>
<p>Although I grades are not counted in computing the GPA, it is important to remove them quickly. You should seek the advice of the Graduate Division if you have further questions concerning I grades.</p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-8970d779-7fff-275e-a28c-75b0b3205b5e">For undergraduate students, the I grade has completion and replacement deadlines. Students must complete the required course work at least 30 days prior to the deadline for replacing the I grade.</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:40px"><span id="docs-internal-guid-8970d779-7fff-275e-a28c-75b0b3205b5e">Fall Semester: An I grade received in the fall semester must be completed 30 days prior to the first day of instruction of the following fall semester or by the instructor-provided deadline, whichever is earlier. The I grade will be replaced by the first day of the following fall semester.</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:40px"><span id="docs-internal-guid-8970d779-7fff-275e-a28c-75b0b3205b5e">Spring Semester and Summer Sessions - An I grade received in the spring semester or summer session must be completed 30 days prior to the first day of instruction of the following spring semester or by the instructor-provided deadline, whichever is earlier. The I grade will be replaced by the first day of the following spring semester.</span></p>
<p>When you complete the required work or deferred examination, grade points will be assigned if you receive a grade of A, B, C, or D. If you repeat the course, grade points will then be assigned to the earned grade only if the dean has given prior written approval to repeat it. If you repeat the course without the approval of the dean, the I grade will be converted to an F and the repeated course will be treated the same as any other course in which you receive an F. The dean of your college or school may extend the deadline for undergraduate completion of an I grade. For undergraduates, except as noted below, any I grade which has not been replaced within the above deadlines will, at the end of that time, be converted to grade F (or NP if taken passed/not passed). After that time, but not retroactively, the grade is counted in computing your GPA.</p>
<p><strong>Exceptions:</strong> Within the above deadlines for completing an I grade, undergraduate students may notify the dean that they have not attempted completion and will not complete the work required for removal of the I grade, and may request that the grade not be replaced by an F (or NP). This procedure is limited to a maximum of two courses. Once the decision has been made, it is irrevocable; the course cannot afterward be completed by any means, including repetition of that course or any equivalent course.</p>
<p>If a degree is conferred before the end of the above deadlines following the assignment of an I grade, the grade will not be converted to an F (or NP). However, you still have the option of removing the I grade within the above deadlines.</p>
<p>If you are an undergraduate student with 12 or more units of I on your record, you may not register without the permission of the dean.</p>
<p>You should make arrangements to complete the course 30 days before the deadline. The instructor will file a change of grade <span id="docs-internal-guid-18b7afe2-7fff-2e7b-bb56-b7054806d730">for Incompletes through CalCentral and</span> Campus Solutions.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Grade IP (In Progress)</h3>
<p>If you take a course extending over more than one term and evaluation of your performance is deferred until the end of the final term, provisional grades of IP (In Progress) are assigned in the intervening term(s). The provisional grades are replaced by one final grade if you complete the full sequence. The IP grade is not included in the GPA. Effective with an IP assigned fall 1973 or later, if the full sequence is not completed as scheduled, the IP will be replaced by a grade of Incomplete. Further changes in your record will be subject to the rules pertaining to I grades above.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Changes of Grade</h3>
<p>All grades except I and IP above are considered final when assigned by an instructor at the end of a term. An instructor may request a change of grade when a computational, clerical, or procedural error occurred in the original assignment of a grade, but a grade may not be changed as a result of reevaluation of your work. No final grade may be revised as a result of reexamination or the submission of additional work after the close of the term.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Grade Appeal Process</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3a7cc1f4-7fff-a4de-dccc-41ca7d4f7afb">If you have a grievance about a grade, you should first try to speak with your instructor and/or the student </span><a href="http://sa.berkeley.edu/ombuds">ombuds</a>. If that does not resolve your grievance, you may initiate a formal appeal through the academic department where you received the grade. The following are grounds for appeal: the application of non-academic criteria, such as the consideration of race, politics, religion, sex, or other criteria not directly reflective of performance related to course requirements; sexual harassment; or improper academic procedures that unfairly affect your grade. Formal procedures may not be activated unless you (the student) and the instructor in charge have failed to resolve the dispute informally. You (the student) may opt to include an ombuds (or any mutually accepted third party) and/or the department chair in resolving the dispute informally. The formal process must be initiated within one calendar year from the last day of the semester in which the final grade for the course was posted. The formal process, once initiated, is to be completed at the unit level (academic department) within 20-working days and at the Senate level within 40-working days if both parties are in residence and the University is in regular session (excluding summer session).</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Formal Appeal of Grades in Courses </h3>
<p>Each department or other instructional unit shall establish a standing grievance committee chair who is not the chair of the department. For each case, the grievance committee chair will appoint an <em>ad hoc</em> grievance committee composed of three faculty members—only two of whom can be from the same unit—<span id="docs-internal-guid-d2df7a63-bcf9-7af0-0823-829c96ae66a9">and two students in good standing appointed by the student association of the unit</span>. If no student association exists, the students are to be appointed by the ASUC or the Graduate Assembly. (The student members must have passed courses or an examination in the unit at least at the level of the disputed course or examination and have been in residence for at least one year.) The instructor of record for the course in dispute cannot be a member of this committee. The ad hoc grievance committee will review all the required materials (from the student and instructor) and make a recommendation regarding a resolution to the grievance. The ad hoc grievance committee’s recommendation to the Committee on Courses of Instruction (COCI), including any minority views, must be given in writing.</p>
<p>If COCI finds in the student’s favor, it may change a failing grade to a P or S, drop a course retroactively, retain the course but eliminate the grade from the GPA, or adopt the letter grade, if any, that was recommended by four of the five members of the grievance committee of the unit(s).</p>
<p>For a complete copy of current grade grievance procedures, please see the <a href="http://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/committees/coci" target="_blank">COCI page on the Academic Senate's website</a>. Here is a complete copy of <a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/regulations/a207-grade-appeals" target="_blank">Berkeley Division Regulation A207</a>, which governs grade appeals.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Grade Reports and Transcripts</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-a505e89c-1cf9-d4a4-9f6a-832906becd76">Grades are available at</span><a href="https://calcentral.berkeley.edu/"> CalCentral</a> and will post the next day after approval by the instructor. Registered students may order a transcript online through <a href="https://calcentral.berkeley.edu/">CalCentral</a>. Alumni and students who are not registered may order transcripts online by following instructions on the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/Default.aspx?PageID=transcripts.html">Office of the Registrar’s website</a>.</p>
]]>
</gradestext>
<creditbyexaminationtext name="Credit by Examination">
<![CDATA[
<h3><span>Undergraduate Students</span></h3>
<p>You may earn credit by examination in two ways:</p>
<ol>
	<li>If you are a new or re-entering undergraduate student, on the recommendation of the Board of Admissions you may be allowed credit by examination for knowledge that you acquired since graduation from high school, either by independent study or at another institution, and for which you have not been allowed advanced standing credit. You should apply to the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/pdf/CREDIT.EXAM.Pet.pdf" target="_blank">Office of the Registrar</a> for credit.</li>
	<li>If you are a student in good standing and currently registered in a regular session, you may qualify for course credit by examination. You may apply for credit to the dean of your college or school on the “Petition for Credit by Examination,” obtainable from the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/pdf/CREDIT.EXAM.Pet.pdf" target="_blank">Office of the Registrar</a>. You may apply for credit by examination in any course listed in the current bulletin that pertains to the regular sessions at UC Berkeley. However, the subject in which you want to be examined should be one in which, in the opinion of the instructor in charge or the department, knowledge can be tested by examination. You must file a separate petition for each course. In certain laboratory, field, or practice courses, neither a written nor an oral examination may be a satisfactory test.</li>
</ol>
<p>You may <u>not</u> receive credit by examination:</p>
<ol>
	<li>If the credit would duplicate credit that you presented for admission to the University.</li>
	<li>In elementary courses in your native language if it is not English.</li>
</ol>
<p>The examination must cover the entire course and be administered at one sitting of no longer than three hours. It may be the regularly scheduled final examination for the class, provided that the examination meets the foregoing criteria. The result of the examination may be reported to the Office of the Registrar only as passed or satisfactory, according to the regulations governing the assignment of these grades. Further information concerning credit by examination may be obtained from the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/pdf/CREDIT.EXAM.Pet.pdf" target="_blank">Office of the Registrar</a>.</p>
<h3>Graduate Students</h3>
<p>If you are a graduate student in residence, you may petition to receive a limited amount of course credit toward your degree by passing examinations on material covered in certain courses in lieu of taking those courses. Laboratory courses, graduate seminar, and research courses are excluded. You must be registered for at least 4 units of upper division and/or graduate coursework at the time you take the examination and you must be in good academic standing (3.0 GPA or better). The final result of the examination will only be reported as satisfactory or unsatisfactory. You may obtain the petition from the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/pdf/CREDIT.EXAM.Pet.pdf" target="_blank">Office of the Registrar</a>. Approval to take these examinations must be given by the dean of the Graduate Division and by the course instructor, or, if no instructor is designated, by the department chair.</p>
]]>
</creditbyexaminationtext>
<midtermfinalexaminationstext name="Midterm &amp; Final Examinations">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>The number of midterm examinations varies at the discretion of the instructor. Deficient grades for undergraduate students whose work at midterm is of D+, D, D-, F, or NP quality are posted on CalCentral during the ninth week of the semester. </span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-33fe3d76-7fff-4309-2d08-8a3dd487e896">Final examinations are required in all undergraduate non-laboratory courses, with the exception of courses that the Committee on Courses of Instruction (COCI) has approved to offer an alternative form of final assessment or as exempt from a final examination. This requirement allows you to demonstrate mastery of course material while providing the instructor with written evidence for evaluation. The examination may last no longer than three hours and must be administered at the time announced in the </span><a href="https://registrar.berkeley.edu/scheduling/academic-scheduling/final-exam-guide-schedules">online Schedule of Classes</a>. Any deviation from this announced time requires approval from COCI or, in temporary changes, the department chair. This requirement guarantees you ample prior notice of the examination time and eliminates conflict with other examinations.</p>
<p>It is the responsibility of instructors and/or departments to return to students their final examinations or copies of them, or to retain students’ final examin­ations or copies of them, for 13 months after the dates of such examinations.</p>
<p>Here is information on faculty, student, and University responsibilities regarding <a href="http://sisproject.berkeley.edu/classroom/scheduling/final-exams" target="_blank">final exams</a>.</p>
<p>Go to the Registrar's website to find out about <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/sis-SC-message" target="_blank">final exam schedule dates</a>.</p>
<p>For further information regarding final examinations, including alternative methods of final assessment and changing the method of final assessment offered in a course, please see:<br/>
<a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/coci-handbook/2.1.3" target="_blank">Committee on Courses of Instruction (COCI) handbook, section 2.1.3</a> and <a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/coci-handbook/3.2.1" target="_blank">section 3.2.1</a></p>
<hr/>
<h3>Accommodation of Religious Creed and Exam Scheduling</h3>
<p>For information regarding the accommodation of religious creed and exam scheduling, please see the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/religious-creed-policy/" target="_blank">Religious Creed Policy.</a></p>
]]>
</midtermfinalexaminationstext>
<degreeprogresstext name="Degree Progress">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Undergraduate Students: Progress Toward a Degree</h3>
<p><span>At the close of each semester, the courses, units, grades, and grade points earned are added onto your cumulative University record. From this record, you may determine your progress toward a degree.</span></p>
<p>In working for a degree, you should keep in mind the various levels on which you must satisfy requirements-- University, campus, college or school, and department-- as well as the kinds of requirements you must fulfill: course, unit, grade point, and amount of upper division work. You may receive additional counsel in these matters from your adviser.</p>
<h4>Minimum Progress</h4>
<p>For undergraduates, normal progress toward a degree requires 30 units of successfully completed coursework each year. If you fail to achieve minimum academic progress, you may continue to be enrolled only with the approval of the dean of your college or school. To achieve minimum academic progress, you must have successfully completed a number of units no fewer than 15 times the number of semesters, less one, in which you have been enrolled on the Berkeley campus. Summer session is not counted as a semester. A course load of 15 units per semester is considered normal. Minimum course load requirements, however, vary by college or school; see the specific college or school announcement for details. If you enroll in a course load of fewer units than the minimum, you will need to have your schedule approved by the dean of your college or school.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Undergraduate Students: Probation and Dismissal</h3>
<h4>Academic Probation</h4>
<p>Regulations and procedures governing academic probation vary with each college and school. For specific details, consult your college or school website. Students on probation may not take courses on a passed/not passed basis.</p>
<h4>Academic Dismissal</h4>
<p>Regulations and procedures governing academic dismissal vary with each college and school. For specific details, consult your college or school.</p>
<p>If you are dismissed, you may appeal for a hearing by formal petition to the dean of your college or school, but the action of dismissal is normally considered final. If you are dismissed and want to transfer to another college or school at Berkeley, you may petition the dean of that college or school.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Graduate Students: Probation and Dismissal</h3>
<p><span>Graduate students are subject to probation and dismissal for academic deficiencies by the Graduate Division under the policies established by the Graduate Council of the Academic Senate. Probation may be initiated by the Graduate Division or by recommendation of the head graduate adviser of your major. The most common reasons for probation are a low GPA and failure to make adequate and timely progress toward the degree. If your probationary status is not rectified within the specified time allowed, you may be subject to dismissal.  If a student has advanced to doctoral candidacy and fails to make adequate progress toward completing the dissertation, probation takes the form of “lapsing” the student’s candidacy. This probationary status must also be resolved and the student’s candidacy reinstated to avoid dismissal.</span></p>
<p>There are circumstances that allow you to appeal dismissal from graduate standing. The “Graduate Appeal Procedure” is available on the <a href="http://www.grad.berkeley.edu/policies/pdf/gradappeal.pdf" target="_blank">Graduate Division website</a>. The procedure may not be used for complaints regarding actions based solely on faculty evaluation of the academic quality of a student’s performance, or decanal evaluations of a student’s appropriate academic progress, unless the complaint alleges that those actions were unduly biased by non-academic criteria.</p>
]]>
</degreeprogresstext>
<graduationtext name="Graduation">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Undergraduate Students: Graduation from Berkeley</h3>
<h4><span>Declaration of Candidacy</span></h4>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-f54bcfd5-f0d2-76b1-379c-c2037fa4f7dc">Registered undergraduates with eight or more terms (four or more terms for junior transfer students) completed on their record will be automatically added to the degree list. </span><span id="docs-internal-guid-9ef0a6d5-7fff-d437-471d-d7f91a92943e">To verify that your name is on the degree list for the appropriate term, please check </span><a href="https://calcentral.berkeley.edu/">CalCentral</a>. <span>Students placed on the degree list will see a note indicating that they are in their final term, e.g. &quot;Spring 2023 is your Final Term,&quot; appearing in the Notifications section of their CalCentral dashboard. This note does not mean that </span><span id="docs-internal-guid-bcd1e7ac-7fff-1960-a78d-14d5ea99953a">the student is necessarily </span>eligible to graduate (see confirmation of candidacy below)<span>, only that the student has been placed on the Spring 2023 degree list.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-aaa7b138-7fff-4fe7-dad7-8508fbfaa007">Both registered and unregistered students who plan to graduate but were not automatically added to the degree list should contact their college advising office at the beginning of the semester when they intend to graduate to be added to the degree list before their college deadline.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-f54bcfd5-f0d2-76b1-379c-c2037fa4f7dc">Students will not graduate if they are not on the degree list, even if they have met all degree requirements. Students who miss the deadline may be added to the degree list in the following term.</span></p>
<h4>Confirmation of Candidacy</h4>
<p>To verify that your name is on the degree list for the appropriate term, please check <a href="https://calcentral.berkeley.edu/">CalCentral</a>.</p>
<h4><span id="docs-internal-guid-f54bcfd5-f0d3-5d2b-30a2-a79cab935e5b">Opting Out of (Dropping From) a Degree List</span></h4>
<div>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-f54bcfd5-f0d3-9b00-b4a8-1c73d5399fd3">Students who believe they were added to a degree list in error, or who wish to appeal to graduate in a later term, should contact their college advisor </span><span>to discuss options for changing their Expected Graduation Term (EGT). </span></p>
</div>
<hr/>
<h3>Graduate Students: Graduation from Berkeley</h3>
<p>To receive a graduate degree, students must successfully complete all coursework required, pass the requisite examinations, advance to candidacy, and fulfill other requirements specified for the degree. For detailed procedures and requirements, students should consult their department, school, or graduate group, and become familiar with the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu">Graduate Division website</a>. General information regarding degree requirements and degree progress can be found in the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/graduate/education/">Graduate Education section</a> of this bulletin.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Commencement</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-122a1d11-7fff-b631-6b19-cfc9a0a5df81">A campuswide commencement is held each year in May to honor students who have earned undergraduate and graduate degrees and to recognize students graduating with distinction. Students who earned their degrees the previous fall semester or in summer sessions are also welcome to participate. The ceremony includes speeches from a keynote, the Chancellor, and University Medalist (the top graduating senior), as well as the conferring of degrees. </span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-122a1d11-7fff-b631-6b19-cfc9a0a5df81">Many schools/colleges, departments, and student organizations also hold individual ceremonies in the spring semester only. Participating in either the campuswide ceremony and/or individual ceremonies is up to each student. </span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-122a1d11-7fff-b631-6b19-cfc9a0a5df81">Berkeley also offers a campuswide commencement in December for all graduates who wish to participate in a ceremony at the end of the fall semester. </span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-122a1d11-7fff-b631-6b19-cfc9a0a5df81">For information, visit the </span><a href="https://commencement.berkeley.edu/">Berkeley Commencement website</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Diplomas</h3>
<p>Diplomas are not given out at Commencement but are available approximately four months afterward.</p>
<p>Diplomas will be mailed automatically without a fee. Degree candidates should update their diploma mailing addresses on CalCentral prior to the end of the term in which the degree is to be awarded. If a diploma address is not supplied, the diploma will be mailed to the student’s home address.</p>
<p>For further information, please see the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/current_students/academic_records_transcripts/diplomas.html">Diploma page on the Office of the Registrar's website</a>.</p>
]]>
</graduationtext>
<studentconductappealstext name="Student Conduct">
<![CDATA[
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-306bfb73-7fff-c9d7-29e3-bb2623b2d50a">The University of California at Berkeley is a community of scholars committed to maintaining an environment that encourages personal and intellectual growth. It is a community with high standards and high expectations for those who choose to become a part of it, including established rules of conduct intended to foster behaviors that are consistent with a civil and educational setting. Members of the University community are expected to comply with all laws, University policies and campus regulations, conducting themselves in ways that support a scholarly environment. The </span><a href="https://sa.berkeley.edu/code-of-conduct">Code of Student Conduct</a> available online at the <a href="http://sa.berkeley.edu/conduct">Center for Student Conduct's website</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Academic Misconduct, Cheating, or Plagiarism</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3ebef414-7fff-9ec6-5723-b082356523da">The high academic standard at the University of California, Berkeley, is reflected in each degree that is awarded. As a result, every student is expected to maintain this high standard by ensuring that all academic work reflects unique ideas and/or properly attributes the ideas to the original sources. Individual departments often have their own expectations for citing and attributing work, </span><span id="docs-internal-guid-6aaa5c6a-7fff-76bd-298f-850588520750">which are often based on citation style manuals or industry standards, </span><span>so it is the responsibility of each student to seek that information out if it is not otherwise provided through a syllabus, course website, or other means.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3ebef414-7fff-9ec6-5723-b082356523da">Faculty members may choose to informally resolve incidents of academic misconduct through the Faculty Disposition process or may refer complaints to the Center for Student Conduct. (See, </span><a href="https://sa.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/documents/Faculty%20Disposition%20Form-%20Fillable%20rev%209.3.2020.pdf">Faculty Disposition Form</a>). If the student has a history of prior misconduct at the University, the Center for Student Conduct will investigate the matter and issue formal academic misconduct charges. </p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3ebef414-7fff-9ec6-5723-b082356523da">If, upon discussion, the student a</span><span id="docs-internal-guid-b7d9ce60-7fff-ff8c-869f-5c092583a632">grees that there was a</span><span> violation and to the proposed academic penalty, the instructor may impose an appropriate academic penalty after confirming with the Center for Student Conduct that the student has no prior history of academic misconduct. If the student does not agree that there was an academic misconduct, violation, or consent to the academic penalty proposed by the faculty member, the matter will be administered through the Center for Student Conduct. Academic penalties may only be imposed by faculty members and include but are not limited to resubmitting assignments, grade adjustments, or even failing the assignment or course.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3ebef414-7fff-9ec6-5723-b082356523da">If a student is found responsible for academic misconduct through the Center for Student Conduct’s process there will be a resolution plan, which will include University sanctions. Sanctions range from a non-reportable warning through dismissal from the University. In most cases, resolution plans will also include educational sanctions such as reflective writing assignment, activities, and workshops.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3ebef414-7fff-9ec6-5723-b082356523da">Information cited from the Code of Student Conduct.</span></p>
<hr/>
<h3>Sexual Violence and Sexual Harassment Policy</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-68b5656a-7fff-a166-8998-e48ec78f1a13">The Berkeley campus actively monitors and supports full compliance with the University of California Policy on Sexual Violence and Sexual Harassment. This Policy addresses the University’s responsibilities and procedures related to sexual violence, sexual harassment, retaliation, and other prohibited behavior as those terms are defined in this Policy (together, “Prohibited Conduct”) in order to ensure an equitable and inclusive education and employment environment. The Policy defines Prohibited Conduct and explains the administrative procedures the University uses to resolve reports of Prohibited Conduct.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-68b5656a-7fff-a166-8998-e48ec78f1a13">The campus has complaint procedures designed to facilitate the prompt and equitable resolution of sexual violence and sexual harassment and other discrimination complaints. If you believe that you have been a target of sexual violence and/or sexual harassment, have questions about the policy or about the complaint resolution procedures, please contact the </span><a href="https://ophd.berkeley.edu/">Office for the Prevention of Harassment and Discrimination</a>, email ask_ophd@berkeley.edu, or call 510-643-7985. Here is the <a href="https://policy.ucop.edu/doc/4000385/SVSH">full text of the University Policy </a>and further information.</p>
<hr/>
<h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-29afbc12-7fff-2ada-345f-36ba06cf0f1a">PATH to Care Center</span></h3>
<div class="gmail_default">
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-632bdb7b-7fff-3955-ab13-09a9689601f8">The PATH to Care Center leads efforts to transform UC Berkeley into a community that is free from sexual violence, sexual harassment, relationship violence, and stalking through prevention, advocacy, training, and healing initiatives. The PATH to Care Center serves staff, faculty, undergraduate and graduate students, and visitors to the campus.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-632bdb7b-7fff-3955-ab13-09a9689601f8">Confidential advocates offer free, affirming, empowering support for those who have experienced sexual harassment, relationship violence, sexual violence, and stalking. Confidential advocates bring a non-judgmental, caring approach to exploring all options, rights, and resources. To schedule an appointment, call 510-642-1988. For urgent 24/7 support, call the Care Line: 510-643-2005. To learn more about PATH to Care Center services and programs visit, </span><a href="http://care.berkeley.edu/">care.berkeley.edu</a>.        </p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-632bdb7b-7fff-3955-ab13-09a9689601f8">The PATH to Care Center also works to promote positive norms of respect, consent, and inclusivity in order to prevent violence and harm before it happens. There are a number of ways you can promote prevention on campus, for example: attending a workshop facilitated by PATH to Care Center </span><a href="https://care.berkeley.edu/prevention-first/peer-to-peer-education-socialchange/">peer educators</a> – or becoming a peer educator; by being an active bystander when you notice concerning behavior; interacting with respect and civility with peers and colleagues; or earning a <a href="https://care.berkeley.edu/prevention-first/trail-certificate/">T.R.A.I.L. Prevention and Response Certificate</a>. </p>
</div>
<hr/>
<h3>Graduate Student Appeals</h3>
<p>Through the Graduate Appeal Procedure, graduate students have the right to appeal academic or administrative decisions that have materially hindered their degree progress or resulted in dismissal from their graduate program.</p>
<p>Students must first initiate an appeal with the academic unit (the department, school, or graduate group) responsible for the alleged action under dispute. The Graduate Council requires each instructional unit to maintain copies of its current internal appeal procedure for information and use by its graduate students.</p>
<p>The academic unit and the student must make all reasonable efforts at resolving the difficulty, as outlined in the Graduate Appeal Procedure, before the student may take the matter to the next level, which is the Graduate Division. Students may also consult with the <a href="http://sa.berkeley.edu/ombuds" target="_blank">Ombuds for Students</a> at 510-642-5754 for assistance with informal resolution.</p>
<p>If attempts to resolve the matter with the student's home unit were unsuccessful, the student may submit a formal appeal to the Graduate Division, after carefully following the guidelines and deadlines in the <a href="http://www.grad.berkeley.edu/policies/pdf/gradappeal.pdf" target="_blank">Graduate Appeal Procedure</a>. The <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/policies/pdf/appealform.pdf" target="_blank">Graduate Appeal Procedure Form</a> must accompany the appeal.</p>
]]>
</studentconductappealstext>
<otherpoliciestext name="Other Policies">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Cal Student Central</h3>
<p>Cal Student Central is your destination for information related to financial aid, fees and billing, payments, disbursements, registration and university enrollment status, as well as other campus systems and activities. Visit the help desk at 120 Sproul Hall, call (510) 664-9181, or visit their website if you need assistance. </p>
<hr/>
<h3><span>Cal 1 Card Photo ID</span></h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-29831ffa-7fff-28ae-3842-1031519a4615">The</span> <a href="https://cal1card.berkeley.edu/">Cal 1 Card</a> is the official campus photo ID and passport to accessing various campus services, facilities, and events. It is also linked to a declining balance stored value debit account in which you may deposit funds and then use them to pay for goods and services at multiple <a href="https://cal1card.berkeley.edu/home/where">campus dining facilities</a> and other <a href="https://cal1card.berkeley.edu/merchants/cal1card-merchants">merchant locations</a>.</p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-d1430823-7fff-a445-d37f-7a6d488a1de5">Successful issuance of a Cal 1 Card will require the following actions:</span></p>
<ol>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-87609529-7fff-265d-885b-0fd3e6553780">Submit a compliant photo online.  To do so, </span><a href="http://cal1card.berkeley.edu/login">login to your Cal 1 Card account</a>, select the Upload Photo menu option, review the photo submission requirements, and follow the steps to upload a compliant photo.<br/>
	<br/>
	NOTE: Enhanced photos (e.g. photoshop, filters, etc.) will be rejected.<br/>
	 </p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-87609529-7fff-265d-885b-0fd3e6553780">Present an original valid government-issued photo ID (e.g. driver license, state ID, passport) in person at your designated card issuance location (e.g. residential housing, GBO check-in, graduate program onboarding event, Cal 1 Card office, etc.).</span></p>
	</li>
</ol>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3996ae4b-7fff-ca18-fa98-d9ffa869e466">The AC Transit EasyPass Clipper Card is a separate card allowing access to </span><a href="https://pt.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/ucb_userguide_0160-16_clipper_web_8.18.16.pdf">Class Pass</a> ridership privileges on AC Transit bus lines.  Eligible students will receive the EasyPass Clipper Card in conjunction with Cal 1 Card issuance.  Accepting custody of the AC Transit EasyPass Clipper Card with the associatedClass Pass constitutes acceptance of the corresponding Clipper <a href="https://www.clippercard.com/ClipperWeb/agreement.do">Cardholder Agreement</a> and <a href="https://www.clippercard.com/ClipperWeb/privacy.do">Privacy Policy</a> stipulations.</p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-3996ae4b-7fff-ca18-fa98-d9ffa869e466">Questions may be sent via email to </span>c1c_notifications@berkeley.edu.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Change of Address</h3>
<p>Changes to your local or permanent address or telephone number can be entered directly at <a href="https://calcentral.berkeley.edu/">CalCentral</a>. </p>
<hr/>
<h3>Change of Name</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-25413e3f-7fff-0ae7-551f-8ee4041a6289">If you change your legal name, stop by Cal Student Central, 120 Sproul Hall, and complete a “Petition for Change of Name” form and provide appropriate documentation. For further information on the Name Change Policy and an alternative method to going to Sproul Hall in person, please see the</span><a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/Registrar/namechng.html"> Office of the Registrar's website</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Preferred Name</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-886b739a-7fff-65a9-cbf2-777cd37c18de">You may designate a preferred name via CalCentral. Your preferred name is the name you would like to be referred to in the classroom and elsewhere on campus. It is different than your legal name, which will still be used for financial aid, diplomas, transcripts, payroll documents, and other documents. For further information on Preferred Name, please see the</span><a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/Registrar/namechng.html"> Office of the Registrar's website</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Access to Records</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-a505e89c-1cfa-93f3-5262-305cab0f2a02">You are entitled by law and University policy to examine and challenge most of the records that the University maintains on you. These records may be confidential and in most circumstances may be released to third parties only with your prior consent. Such matters are detailed in the</span><a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/academic-policies-procedures/ferpa"> Berkeley Campus Policy Governing Disclosure of Information from Student Records</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Classroom Note-Taking and Recording Policy</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7f4505c1-22b4-2246-9fb6-3194aea4bbc4">The University encourages students to take notes in class and other instructional settings as part of their education. Note-taking is a means of recording information and helps students absorb and integrate what they learn. Note-taking or other recordings of an instructor’s presentation can also facilitate further discussion of the material with students and the instructor. However, class notes and recordings are based on the intellectual effort of the instructor, who has an interest in protecting this effort and ensuring the accuracy of any public representation of his or her work. Prior approval of the instructor is required for the recording of course notes and the sharing of course notes and other class materials beyond the students enrolled in the course. Only a course note-taking service authorized by the campus may make course notes available commercially. </span><span>Here are the</span><a href="http://dsp.berkeley.edu/students/returning-students/services/note-taking/dsp-process-class-notes"> relevant policies</a> for note-taking services.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Disability-Related Policies and Guidelines</h3>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7f4505c1-22b4-430d-b4a4-daeb640c8af0">In compliance with the Federal Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended (Public Law 93-112) and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (Public Law 101-336), the University of California policy prohibits unlawful discrimination on the basis of disability in its programs, services, and activities.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7f4505c1-22b4-65e7-657f-ced092e71372">The University of California's system-wide Policies Applying to Campus Activities, Organizations, and Students can be found on the</span> <a href="http://policy.ucop.edu/doc/2710534/PACAOS-140">UC Office of the President's website</a>.</p>
<p>For further information regarding services for students with disabilities, please see the <a href="http://dsp.berkeley.edu/">Disabled Students' Program website</a>.</p>
]]>
</otherpoliciestext>
<coursenumberguidetext name="Course Number Guide">
<![CDATA[
 <p>For an explanation of the prefixes, suffixes, and course numbering system used in UC Berkeley's <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/courses" target="_blank">course listings</a>, please see the guide provided below.</p> <h3>Prefixes to Course Numbers</h3> <p><strong>C =</strong> Course is cross-listed with another department<br/> <strong>H =</strong> Honors course<br/> <strong>N =</strong> Summer-only course not equivalent to a regular session course with the same number<br/> <strong>R =</strong> Satisfies Reading and Composition (R &amp; C) requirement<br/> <strong>W =</strong> Offered fully or predominantly online (prefix no longer required for online courses)</p> <hr/> <h3>Suffixes to Course Numbers</h3> <p><strong>AC =</strong> Satisfies American Cultures requirement</p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-272b5241-7fff-fb24-8009-399a578519c2">Students should check with their major or minor advising unit to verify which courses will satisfy curriculum requirements.</span></p> <hr/> <h3>Key to Course Numbers</h3> <p><strong>1-99 =</strong> Lower division (undergraduate) courses<br/> <strong>100-199 =</strong> Upper division (undergraduate) courses<br/> <strong>200-299 = </strong>Graduate courses<br/> <strong>300-399 =</strong> Professional courses for teachers and prospective teachers<br/> <strong>400-499 =</strong> Other professional courses (acceptable toward academic degrees only within limitations prescribed by a college, school, or the Graduate Division)<br/> <strong>601 =</strong> Special study for graduate students in preparation for master's examination<br/> <strong>602 =</strong> Special study for graduate students in preparation for doctoral qualifying examination</p> <hr/> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 24, 39, &amp; 84</strong></h5> <p>Freshman and Sophomore Seminars<br/> For further information, please see the <a href="http://fss.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Freshman and Sophomore Seminars at Berkeley website</a>.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 97</strong></h5> <p>Field Studies (lower division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. <span id="docs-internal-guid-d7e644cf-7fff-1b43-631c-e4648de38152">You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester</span>. Courses with this number are restricted to <em>passed/not passed </em>grading. To take them you must be in good academic standing (2.00 GPA or better). A written proposal for each Field Studies Course, signed by the faculty sponsor, must receive approval by the Chair of the Department. In certain cases, exceptions to these rules may be granted by the dean of your college or school.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 98</strong></h5> <p>Organized Group Study (lower division) <br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. Each section of a 98 course must receive approval by the chair of the department, based upon a written proposal submitted by the instructor who is to supervise the course that describes the matter to be studied, the methods of instruction, the number of units to be credited, and methods of evaluation of student performance. A copy of the approved proposal must be submitted for information to the Committee on Courses of Instruction. Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed </em>is to be assigned. In certain cases, the dean of your college or school may authorize exceptions to these limitations.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 99</strong></h5> <p>Supervised Independent Study by academically superior students (lower division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. You must have a 3.3 GPA and prior consent of the instructor who is to supervise the study, and you must submit a written proposal to the chair of the department (or equivalent) for approval. <span id="docs-internal-guid-fa9b52ef-7fff-ecdc-795c-fdade3a5043a">The proposal must specify the nature of the study, number of units to be credited, and the basis for grading. </span>Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed</em> is to be assigned. In certain cases, the dean of your college or school may authorize exceptions to these limitations.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 197</strong></h5> <p>Field Studies (upper division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. Courses with this number are restricted to <em>passed/not passed </em>grading. A written proposal for each Field Studies Course, signed by the faculty sponsor, must receive approval by the Chair of the Department. In certain cases, exceptions to these rules may be granted by the dean of your college or school.</p> <h5><strong>Courses numbered 198</strong></h5> <p>Organized Group Study (upper division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. Each section of a 198 course must receive approval by the chair of the department, based upon a written proposal submitted by the instructor who is to supervise the course that describes the matter to be studied, the methods of instruction, the number of units to be credited, and methods of evaluation of student performance. A copy of the approved proposal must be submitted for information to the Committee on Courses of Instruction. To enroll in 198 courses, you must be in good academic standing (2.00 GPA or better). Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed </em>is to be assigned. <span id="docs-internal-guid-e95f35e1-7fff-531d-d5c2-49d453908f51">In certain cases, exceptions to these rules may be granted by the dean of your college or school.</span></p> <h5><strong>Courses numbered 199</strong></h5> <p>Supervised Independent Study (upper division)<br/> You may use no more than 16 semester units of courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 to meet requirements for the bachelor's degree. You may aggregate no more than 4 units of credit for courses numbered 97, 98, 99, 197, 198, and 199 for a single semester. You must have prior approval of your major adviser, the instructor who is to supervise the study, and the chair of the department. Approval must be based on a written proposal that you submit to the chair that specifies the nature of the study, the number of units to be credited, and the basis for grading. To enroll in 199 courses, you must be in good academic standing (2.00 GPA or better). Only a grade of <em>passed/not passed</em> will be assigned. In certain cases, the dean of your college or school may authorize exceptions to these limitations.</p> <h5><strong>Courses Numbered 601 &amp; 602</strong></h5> <p>Individual Study (601 – master level, 602 – doctoral level)<br/> You may enroll in no more than 8 semester units of courses numbered 601 or 602 to meet the requirements for a master’s or doctoral degree, up to 4 units per summer session. Only a grade of <em>satisfactory/unsatisfactory</em> will be assigned. Enrollment in these courses must be approved by the student’s graduate advisor. Units earned in these courses may not be used to meet academic residence of unit requirements towards a degree.</p>
]]>
</coursenumberguidetext>
<spring2022covid19measurestext name="Spring 2022 COVID-19 Measures">
<![CDATA[
<p class="ui-sortable-handle">On January 7, UC Berkeley announced that the semester would begin with a two-stage process, with most courses being offered fully remote for the first two weeks (January 18-28) and then moving to fully in-person instruction in the third week of the semester on January 31.</p>
<p class="ui-sortable-handle">Read the <a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2022/01/07/uc-berkeley-will-begin-spring-semester-with-mostly-remote-instruction/" target="_blank">campus message</a> and visit the <a href="https://coronavirus.berkeley.edu/instruction/" target="_blank">instruction page</a> for more information.</p>
]]>
</spring2022covid19measurestext>
<newitemtext name="Fall 2021 COVID-19 Measures">
<![CDATA[
<p>On January 11, University of California President Michael Drake announced that UC campuses would return to primarily in-person instruction systemwide starting fall 2021. <span id="docs-internal-guid-efa9f31a-7fff-f029-7232-a1d24fdf55e2">See the </span><a href="https://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/press-room/uc-plans-fall-2021-person-instruction-across-its-10-campuses" target="_blank">UC Press Room message</a> for additional information.</p>
<p>On July 15, the University of California released a final <a href="https://policy.ucop.edu/doc/5000695/SARS-CoV-2%28Covid-19%29" target="_blank">COVID-19 vaccine policy</a>.</p>
]]>
</newitemtext>
<spring2021covid19measurestext name="Spring 2021 COVID-19 Measures">
<![CDATA[
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-efa9f31a-7fff-f029-7232-a1d24fdf55e2">On September 29, the campus announced that Berkeley will begin spring 2021 with fully remote delivery of instruction for at least two weeks, with limited in-person instruction to follow (assuming public health conditions permit). See the </span><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/09/29/uc-berkeley-announces-plans-for-the-spring-2021-semester/">campus message</a> for additional information.</p>
<p>On October 29, the campus announced <a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/10/29/updates-on-uc-berkeleys-spring-2021-semester-schedule/">updates on plans for the spring 2021 schedule</a>.</p>
<p><span id="m_-677961901735227388gmail-m_-48228793835613807gmail-docs-internal-guid-308a1520-7fff-665f-99db-f7211c5f20a6">On November 2, 2020 the Academic Senate’s Divisional Council (DIVCO) approved a recommendation to the schools and colleges to enact flexible and compassionate policies and practices in Fall 2020 and Spring 2021. For additional information, please see the Senate’s comments on </span><a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/divco_recommendations_on_pandemic_grading.pdf">pandemic grading policies</a> and each college’s website.      </p>
<p>On January 19, the campus announced <a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2021/01/19/uc-berkeley-updates-plans-for-spring-in-person-instruction/">updates on plans for spring 2021 in-person instruction.</a></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-efa9f31a-7fff-f029-7232-a1d24fdf55e2">For additional information, please see the following resources:</span></p>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-efa9f31a-7fff-f029-7232-a1d24fdf55e2"><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/coronavirus/">UC Berkeley's COVID-19 News Site</a></span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-efa9f31a-7fff-f029-7232-a1d24fdf55e2"><a href="https://registrar.berkeley.edu/service-adjustments/instruction-faq">Office of the Registrar Instruction FAQ</a></span></p>
	</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-efa9f31a-7fff-f029-7232-a1d24fdf55e2">Resources will be added to this page as they become available.</span></p>
<h4><strong>Spring 2021 Transcript Notation</strong></h4>
<div>
<p>A notation will appear on the official transcript under the Spring 2021 term for all undergraduate students who were enrolled for the semester. The following notation has been preliminarily approved assuming no substantive change during the semester. It will be added at the end of Spring 2021:</p>
<p><strong>Preliminary Undergraduate notation:</strong></p>
</div>
<p style="margin-left:40px">The COVID-19 global pandemic required changes to enrollment deadlines and <span>grading policy. Each college developed its own policy to allow students </span><span>increased flexibility in converting graded classes to passed/not passed.  </span></p>
<div> </div>
]]>
</spring2021covid19measurestext>
<fall2020covid19measurestext name="Fall 2020 COVID-19 Measures">
<![CDATA[
<p><strong>On July 21, the campus announced that Berkeley will begin fall 2020 with fully remote instruction, via messages specific to:</strong></p>
<ul>
	<li><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/07/21/fall-semester-update-student-resources-for-remote-instruction/">Students</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/07/21/uc-berkeley-to-begin-fall-semester-with-remote-instruction/">Faculty and staff</a></li>
</ul>
<p>On June 17, the Chancellor announced that fall 2020 instruction will include in-person and remote offerings via messages specific to:</p>
<ul>
	<li><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/06/17/uc-berkeley-announces-plans-for-fall-semester/" target="_blank">Undergraduate students</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/06/17/uc-berkeley-fall-2020-information-for-graduate-students/" target="_blank">Graduate students</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/06/17/fall-2020-information-for-faculty-and-staff/" target="_blank">Faculty, staff, graduate student instructors, and graduate student researchers</a>.</li>
</ul>
<div>On October 22, <a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2020/10/22/in-pilot-program-some-uc-berkeley-courses-are-moving-outside/" target="_blank">the campus announced</a> that limited in-person instruction will occur in the form of occasional, outdoor-only activities. The delivery of instruction will be consistent with public health guidelines.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><span id="m_-48228793835613807gmail-docs-internal-guid-308a1520-7fff-665f-99db-f7211c5f20a6">On November 2, the Academic Senate’s Divisional Council (DIVCO) approved a recommendation to the schools and colleges to enact flexible and compassionate policies and practices in Fall 2020 and Spring 2021. For additional information, please see the Senate’s comments on </span><a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/divco_recommendations_on_pandemic_grading.pdf" target="_blank">pandemic grading policies</a> and each college’s website.    </div>
<p>For additional information, please see the following resources:</p>
<div class="gmail_quote">
<div>
<ul>
	<li><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/coronavirus/" target="_blank">UC Berkeley's COVID-19 News Site</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/archive/Fall 2020 FAQ Archive.pdf" target="_blank">Office of the Registrar Instruction FAQ</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Resources will be added to this page as they become available.</div>
<div>
<h4><strong>Fall 2020 Transcript Notation</strong></h4>
<p>A notation will appear on the official transcript under the Fall 2020 term for all students who were enrolled for the semester. The graduate transcript notation is currently under review and will be updated soon.</p>
<p><strong>Undergraduate notation:</strong></p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">The COVID-19 global pandemic required mid-semester changes to enrollment <span>deadlines and grading policy. Each college developed its own policy to </span><span>allow students increased flexibility in converting graded classes to </span><span>passed/not passed. </span></p>
</div>
</div>
]]>
</fall2020covid19measurestext>
<summer2020covid19measurestext name="Summer 2020 COVID-19 Measures">
<![CDATA[
<p>Due to the COVID-19 global health pandemic, UC Berkeley announced on April 3 that all summer instruction would be remote. No changes made to the grading policy. </p>
]]>
</summer2020covid19measurestext>
<spring2020covid19measurestext name="Spring 2020 COVID-19 Measures">
<![CDATA[
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">In response to the unusual and challenging circumstances that instructors and students have experienced due to the COVID-19 pandemic, UC Berkeley implemented a number of emergency measures for the spring 2020 semester: </span></p>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">Effective Tuesday, March 10, 2020, the campus moved to remote instruction which will remain in place through the end of Summer Sessions 2020. </span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">The default grading basis for all undergraduate enrollment in the spring 2020 semester was changed to Passed/Not Passed (P/NP) effective March 20, 2020. Undergraduates have the option of reverting back to a letter grade until the Friday before final exams. Classes taken P/NP in spring 2020 will not count against the undergraduate ⅓ limit on P/NP courses.</span></p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">Graduate students may change the grading of their courses to Satisfactory/Unsatisfactory (S/U) until the Friday before final exams. Graduate programs may increase the fraction of S/U courses that can count toward degree requirements beyond the existing cap of 1/3.</span></p>
	</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Spring 2020 Transcript Notations</strong></h4>
<p>A notation will appear on the official transcript under the Spring 2020 term for all students who were enrolled for the semester. </p>
<p><strong>Undergraduate notation:</strong></p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">The COVID-19 global pandemic required mid-semester changes to enrollment deadlines and grading policy. All graded classes were converted to passed/not passed with the option to revert to letter grade prior to final exams. Students were encouraged to retain the passed/not passed option.</p>
<p><strong>Graduate notation:</strong></p>
<p style="margin-left:40px">The COVID-19 global health pandemic resulted in mid-semester academic policy changes in respect to enrollment deadlines, milestone completion, and grading.</p>
<h4><strong>Additional Resources</strong></h4>
<ul>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849"><a href="https://evcp.berkeley.edu/news/grading-policies-spring-semester-2020">Grading Policies for Spring 2020</a></span></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849"><a href="https://evcp.berkeley.edu/news/grading-principles-spring-semester-2020">Grading Principles for Spring 2020</a></span></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849"><a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/issues/coronavirus/student-qa-grading-spring-semester-2020">Student FAQ: Grading for Spring 2020</a></span></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849"><a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/issues/coronavirus/instructor-qa-grading-spring-semester-2020">Instructor FAQ: Grading for Spring 2020</a></span></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849"><a href="https://grad.berkeley.edu/covid-19-information-for-graduate-students/">COVID-19 Information for Graduate Students</a></span></li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Undergraduate College-Specific Policies</strong></h4>
<ul>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">College of Chemistry: </span><a href="https://chemistry.berkeley.edu/coronavirus">Coronavirus (COVID-19) Information</a> and <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/archive/COC Sp 20 Changes in Policies &amp; Procedures.pdf">Changes in College of Chemistry Policies &amp; Procedures for Spring 2020</a></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">College of Engineering: </span><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/archive/COE FAQ COVID19 impacts on 2020-21 student policies.pdf">Spring 2020 COVID-19 FAQs</a></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">College of Environmental Design: </span><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/archive/Spring 2020 Academic Policy Updates CED Website.pdf">Spring 2020 Academic Policy Updates</a></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">College of Letters and Science: </span><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/archive/LS Sp 2020 Policy Modifications and FAQs L&amp;S Advising.pdf">Spring 2020: Policy Updates and FAQs</a></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">Haas School of Business: </span><a href="https://haas.berkeley.edu/undergrad/academics/curriculum/degree-requirements/">Coronavirus (COVID-19) Information</a></li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-c8088bfa-7fff-e341-02ad-aede3d245849">Rausser College of Natural Resources: </span><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/archive/Rausser College of Natural Resources Spring 2020 Changes in Policies and Procedures.pdf">Changes in Policies and Procedures for Spring 2020</a></li>
</ul>
]]>
</spring2020covid19measurestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

