<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Women, Gender, and Sexuality</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">PhD students at UC Berkeley may add a Designated Emphasis (DE) in Women, Gender, and Sexuality (DEWGS) to their major fields. Designed to enhance interdisciplinary graduate studies at Berkeley, the DEWGS provides curricular and research resources and opportunities to students who are already admitted to graduate degree programs on campus.</p>
<p class="Normal1">The designated emphasis program was developed to accommodate some of the many students who conduct graduate-level research in gender and/or sexuality-related topics across numerous fields. Administered by the Department of Gender and Women's Studies, the designated emphasis program provides its students with certification as well as with a context for the interdisciplinary exchange of ideas and development of research.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>To be admitted to the Designated Emphasis in Women, Gender, and Sexuality, an applicant must already be accepted into a PhD program at the University of California, Berkeley. For further information regarding admission to graduate programs at UC Berkeley, please see the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">Graduate Division's Admissions website</a>.</p>
<p>Applicants for the DE will be selected according to their academic qualifications, the appropriateness of their interests to the program's teaching resources, and the enrollment capacity of its graduate seminars. Graduate students should apply in their third semester for admission to the program in their fourth semester. Students must apply before completing their qualifying examinations.</p>
<p>Materials should include four copies of the following:</p>
<ol>
	<li>A one-page statement of purpose which includes: your academic training in the field of Gender/Sexuality Studies, a short description of your dissertation project, and your stated interest in the DE.</li>
	<li>One letter of recommendation from your home department faculty indicating readiness to complete the DE requirements (letter can be mailed under separate cover or emailed).</li>
	<li>A gender/sexuality relevant writing sample (25 pages or less).</li>
	<li>A curriculum vitae.</li>
</ol>
<p>Deadline for spring admission: October 30 (If October 30 falls on a weekend, please submit materials the following Monday.)</p>
<p>Send all application materials to:<br/>
Director<br/>
DEWGS<br/>
c/o Gender &amp; Women's Studies Department<br/>
608 Social Sciences Building<br/>
University of California<br/>
Berkeley, CA 94720-1070</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequriementstext name="Designated Emphasis Requriements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Coursework/Curriculum</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 200">GWS 200</span></td><td>Theory and Critical Research</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 220">GWS 220</span></td><td>Research Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">One 200-level elective seminar in the Department of Gender &amp; Women's Studies</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>Students may petition the DEWGS director to use a gender or sexuality-focused graduate course taught outside GWS to fulfill the elective requirement. That request must include a copy of the course syllabus and a cover letter indicating how that course was directly related to your studies in DEWGS (assigned readings, research focus, or paper completed). <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 200">GWS 200</span></span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 220">GWS 220</span></span> can not be substituted by other classes.</p>
<p>Students admitted to the designated emphasis program should enroll in the required introductory seminar (<span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 200">GWS 200</span></span>) offered the following spring if possible, and must complete that seminar before taking their qualifying exams. Students must fulfill the aforementioned requirements before completion of the degree.</p>
<h3>Qualifying Examination</h3>
<p>A member of the GWS department or its affiliated faculty must be on the qualifying examination committee; a topic on women, gender, and sexuality must be on the qualifying examination.</p>
<h3>Dissertation</h3>
<p>A member of the GWS department or its affiliated faculty must be on the dissertation committee.</p>
<h3>Degree Conferral</h3>
<p class="Normal1CxSpFirst">The DE will be acknowledged solely in conjunction with the PhD in an established PhD program and will be signified by the transcript and diploma designation, “PhD in [major] with a Designated Emphasis in Women, Gender, and Sexuality.” The GWS department also provides each DE graduate with a DEWGS medal at the GWS commencement ceremonies.</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequriementstext>
<researchresourcestext name="Research Resources">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Stipends</h3>
<p>Students admitted to the DEWGS Program can apply for stipends to support research and activities related to their participation in the program. Awards are made available once a year in the fall. The total budget for graduate student stipends varies each year; individual awards can be up to $500.</p>
<h4>Purpose of the Stipends</h4>
<p>The stipends are intended to provide a source of funding for students in the DEWGS to engage in DEWGS-related activities or to pursue DEWGS scholarship. As such, it is for projects that are outside of the normal range of your home department activities. Examples include: travel to conferences or workshops that focus on gender or sexuality; travel to an archive or fieldwork site for the purpose of engaging in gender or sexuality-related scholarship; purchase of primary research materials that are necessary for your gender-related project and are not readily available on campus. Deadline to apply: October 30. (If October 30 falls on the weekend, please submit materials the following Monday.)</p>
<h4>Application Procedure</h4>
<p>Download the electronic application from the <a href="http://womensstudies.berkeley.edu/graduate" target="_blank">program's website</a> and forward the completed form to<strong>:</strong><br/>
Althea Grannum Cummings, DEWGS Graduate Student Affairs Officer<br/>
<a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/graduate/degree-programs/women-gender-sexuality/mailto:fcazares@berkeley.edu">cummings@berkeley.edu</a></p>
<p>You do not need letters of recommendation.</p>
<h4>Evaluation Criteria</h4>
<p>The executive committee of the DEWGS will meet shortly after each deadline to decide which applications to fund. The evaluation will be based on the following considerations:</p>
<ol>
	<li>Does the student have a well-defined use for the stipend, and has the student documented the specific costs involved?</li>
	<li>Does the student have a previous history of DEWGS funding, and if so in what amount? Students who have never received funding will be given the highest priority.</li>
	<li>Has the student exhausted other avenues of funding including their home department and Graduate Division?</li>
	<li>Would the funds contribute to the student's intellectual growth and/or professionalization in DEWGS scholarship?</li>
	<li>Is the project clearly a DEWGS related project which would not be likely to be funded elsewhere?</li>
</ol>
<h4>Receiving Your Award</h4>
<p>You will be notified by email immediately after the committee has met as to whether you received a stipend or not. In the event that your application was successful, you will be given instructions on how to receive your stipend. If your application was not successful, your message will contain an indication of why it did not succeed.</p>
]]>
</researchresourcestext>
<teachingopportunitiestext name="Teaching Opportunities">
<![CDATA[
<p>GWS provides GSI opportunities for DE Students to assist the instructor of record for:</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 10">GWS 10</span></td><td>Introduction to Gender and Women's Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 14">GWS 14</span></td><td>Gender, Sexuality, and Race in Global Political Issues</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 20">GWS 20</span></td><td>Introduction to Feminist Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 102">GWS 102</span></td><td>Transnational Feminism</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GWS 195">GWS 195</span></td><td>Gender and Women's Studies Senior Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LGBT 20AC">LGBT 20AC</span></td><td>Sexual Politics and Queer Organzing in the US</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p> Calls for applications go out every semester via the DE listserv, and all DE students are encouraged to apply.</p>
]]>
</teachingopportunitiestext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Women, Gender and Sexuality</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws200" data-toggle="#cb_gws200">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 200</span> 
<span class="title">Theory and Critical Research</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws200">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This course will provide an opportunity for the examination of diverse feminist theories produced in different disciplines and across disciplines. The course will ground contemporary philosophical and theoretical developments in the study of gender to specific histories of class, race, ethnicity, nation, and sexuality. Participants in the class will be urged to draw upon their own disciplinary and interdisciplinary backgrounds and interests</span><span class="deschide"> to produce multifaceted analyses of how feminist theory has acted to delimit the study of women in some instances as well as how it may be used critically and imaginatively to open the field in complex and dynamic ways. Graduate students research and write a substantial (25-50 page) paper for the course. They will also participate in organizing and leading class discussion on a rotating basis.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Theory and Critical Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="59" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor, 104, or the equivalent</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two to Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Women's Studies 200</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Theory and Critical Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws210" data-toggle="#cb_gws210">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 210</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Interdisciplinary Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws210">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Spring 2020<br/>
A cross-disciplinary examination of specific problems in the study of gender, women, and sexuality. Topics will vary; for example, representations of motherhood, women in the public sphere, work and gender, globalization of gender, and the history of sexuality.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Interdisciplinary Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="17" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 104 or equivalent and consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Women's Studies 210</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Interdisciplinary Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws220" data-toggle="#cb_gws220">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 220</span> 
<span class="title">Research Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws220">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Members of the seminar will present their ongoing dissertation research and mutually explore the interdisciplinary dimensions and implications of their work.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="870" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Open to graduate students advanced to Ph.D. candidacy</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Women's Studies 220</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws230" data-toggle="#cb_gws230">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 230</span> 
<span class="title">Transnational Feminist Theories</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws230">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2021, Fall 2012, Fall 2011<br/>
The aim of this course is to provide graduate students with an understanding of transnational feminist theories so that they may more effectively engage with this area of scholarship, but moreover so that they may critically and creatively contribute to it through their own writing.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Transnational Feminist Theories:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="392" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture/discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Transnational Feminist Theories:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws231" data-toggle="#cb_gws231">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 231</span> 
<span class="title">Proseminar in Transnational Gender and Women's Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws231">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
Designed to encourage dialogue around themes related to transnational gender and women's studies, this proseminar is organized around colloquia, panels, and conferences sponsored by the Department of Gender and Women's Studies, the Beatrice Bain Research Group, the Center for Race and Gender, the Center for the Study of Sexual Cultures, and (as relevant) other campus units.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Proseminar in Transnational Gender and Women's Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="246" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Proseminar in Transnational Gender and Women's Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws232" data-toggle="#cb_gws232">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 232</span> 
<span class="title">Transnational Feminist Approaches to Knowledge Production</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws232">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This course focuses on incorporating the analytic power of transnational feminist studies in academic reserch projects and practices. It examines the ways in which interdisciplinary and transnational approaches to gender and wormen replicate, challenge, reconfigure, and transform the emergence of new knowledge frames, analytics, and research practices. Students in this course will explore these and other questions in the context of their own research projects.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Transnational Feminist Approaches to Knowledge Production:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="669" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Transnational Feminist Approaches to Knowledge Production:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws235" data-toggle="#cb_gws235">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 235</span> 
<span class="title">Capitalism, Gender and the Present Moment</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws235">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2021, Fall 2018<br/>
Capitalism is often seen as a system that overrides everything in its path. However, a closer look at its development suggests that it emerged and still operates within and in relation to gender and racial domination, reconstituting those meanings and systems in turn. In this seminar, we will investigate that imbrication, exploring the role and constitution of gender and race in ongoing primitive accumulation, in the labor of social reproduction, and in the</span><span class="deschide"> unfolding of the neoliberal present. Over the course of the semester, we will explore exploitation’s ongoing operations amid a broad terrain of appropriation by other means.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Capitalism, Gender and the Present Moment:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="62" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Capitalism, Gender and the Present Moment:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws236" data-toggle="#cb_gws236">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 236</span> 
<span class="title">Diaspora, Border, and Transnational Identities</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws236">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2022, Fall 2016, Fall 2013<br/>
This course will study debates around the notions of home, location, migrancy, mobility, and dislocation by focusing on issues of gender and sexuality. We will examine the ways in which various cultural flows have fundamentally challenged and changed the nature of global economy by expanding mobility of capital, labor, and systems of representations in a transnational context. We will also look at the impact of new technologies in production, distribution</span><span class="deschide">, communication, and circulation of cultural meanings and social identites by linking nationalism, immigration, diaspora, and globalization to the process of subject formation in a postcolonial context.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Diaspora, Border, and Transnational Identities:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="374" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Diaspora, Border, and Transnational Identities:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws237" data-toggle="#cb_gws237">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 237</span> 
<span class="title">Transnational Science, Technology, and New Media</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws237">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2010, Fall 2008<br/>
This is a core class of the new Ph.D in Transnational Gender and Women's Studies. It will expose students to critical thinking about science, technology, and new media. The class explores intersections of gender and women's studies with science, technology, engineering, medicine, and new media around the world; including women in science; transnational feminist science and technology studies; technologies of reproduction, production and destruction; divisions</span><span class="deschide"> of scientific and technical labor; embodiment and subjectivity; digital divides, digital consumption, embodiment, and circulation; modernist projects of categorization; and the making and breaking of gendered bodies. It mixes secondary sources with primary sources, and among the primary sources, mixes scientific and technical documents with new media and the arts.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Transnational Science, Technology, and New Media:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="508" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Transnational Science, Technology, and New Media:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws238" data-toggle="#cb_gws238">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 238</span> 
<span class="title">Feminist Bio-Politics</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws238">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2010<br/>
This course is divided into three sections, Theorists and Methods, The Sciences of Life, and Bio-and-Necro-politics, and within each section there are further thematic headings. The course serves both to introduce graduate students to science and technology studies and to introduce new works and directions in the field. The syllabus foregrounds the life and biomedical sciences, and thematizes space and trans-place, time and genealogy, disciplines and inter-disciplines</span><span class="deschide">, method and/as theory, identity and governance, ethics and objectivity, knowledge and stratification, security and transparency.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Feminist Bio-Politics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="29" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Feminist Bio-Politics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws250" data-toggle="#cb_gws250">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 250</span> 
<span class="title">Queer Translation</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws250">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2020, Fall 2014, Fall 2010<br/>
This seminar aims for both a familiarization and a potential reworking of selected contemporary debates in queer theory: those concerning migration, race, globalization, and movements of theory. How do queer theories, queer theories-as-practice, queer practices travel? Furthermore, do critiques of stability found in queer theory invite presumptions of mobility? We will interrogate the shadow of &quot;mobility&quot; in queer theory by considering</span><span class="deschide"> queer tourism, gender identity, sub-class labor migration, and the outer zones of citizenship.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Queer Translation:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="54" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Queer Translation:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_gws299" data-toggle="#cb_gws299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">GWS 299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study and Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 9 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_gws299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Spring 2020<br/>
For students engaged in individual research and study. May not be substituted for available graduate lecture courses.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study and Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="496" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-9 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-17 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Regular meetings to be arranged with instructor.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Gender and Women's Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Women's Studies 299</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study and Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Paola Bacchetta, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ethnicity, postcolonial theory, transnational feminist and queer of color theories, theories of the inseparability of gender, theories of the inseparability of sexuality, theories of the inseparability of, theories of the inseparability of class, theories of the inseparability of nation, theories of the inseparability of religion, global political and religious conflict (especially Hindu nationalism and racializations of Muslims and Islam), theories of resistance and transgression, right-wing movements, geographic areas of specialization outside the U S- India and France.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/paola-bacchetta"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mel Y. Chen, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Queer and feminist theory, Disability theory, Critical animal studies, Materiality studies, Cultural politics of race, sexuality, ability, and immigration, Critical linguistics, Paradigms of inter- and transdisciplinarity.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/mel-y-chen"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Minoo Moallem, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Transnational and Postcolonial Feminist Studies, cultural studies, Visual and Material Cultures of Religion, Immigration and Diaspora Studies, Middle East Studies, and Iranian Studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15131"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Courtney Desiree Morris, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Black womenâ€™s social movements; state violence and authoritarianism; racial formations in Latin America, the Caribbean and the US; Critical race theory; Feminist and queer theory; environmental ethics; black visual culture and aesthetics.<br/><a href="http://womensstudies.berkeley.edu/about/department-faculty/courtney-desiree-morris/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Laura C. Nelson, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Gender, medicine, and politics, Cultural, political, and experiential aspects of breast cancer in South Korea, How, why, and to what effect constructions of gender, class, and race are mobilized and manipulated in South Korea, Structures of cultural temporality (future, present, or past orientation) and anti-poverty policies (US and South Korea).<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/laura-c-nelson"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leslie Salzinger, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Political economy, feminist theory, finance, sociology of gender, Gender and Work, gendering of transnational processes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15303"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eric Stanley, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Critical prison studies; Queer/trans social movements; Anti-colonial feminism.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/eric-stanley"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Barbara A. Barnes, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Evelyn Nakano Glenn, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Labor, citizenship, undocumented students, caring work, settler colonialism, skin color bias.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13857"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barrie Thorne, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, gender theory, ethnography, qualitative methods, sociology, women, sociology of gender, sociology of age relations.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15542"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Irene Tinker, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>International development and women, Electoral quotas in legislatures for women.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Minh-Ha Trinh, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Gender and sexuality, womens studies, rhetoric, feminist postcolonial theory, film theory and production, music composition, ethnomusicology, contemporary critical theory and the arts.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/minh-ha-trinh"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

