<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Race and the Law</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The summer minor in Race and the Law is a joint program in the Departments of African American Studies and Ethnic Studies and was created to develop students’ understanding of the fundamental interconnections between race and the law, nationally and internationally. Historically, the law has been instrumental in codifying racial difference and establishing racial hierarchies. Contemporary conflicts over migration, citizenship, indigenous claims to land, and environmental justice are part of a broader history that demands attention to the role of the law in creating and contesting social power. Course offerings will address these issues and demonstrate how law operates an essential component of racialization, and, conversely, why it is impossible to understand U.S. legal history without addressing race. The minor is available to UC Berkeley students, and a certificate is available to students outside of UC Berkeley.</p>
<h2>Enrolling in the Minor</h2>
<h4>UC Berkeley Students</h4>
<h5>Race and the Law Minor</h5>
<ol>
	<li>Enroll in Summer Session through <a href="https://calcentral.berkeley.edu/">CalCentral</a>.</li>
	<li><span>In Session A, fill out the Intent to Minor form. Email the form to racelawminor@berkeley.edu, or bring the form to an advisor in the Department of African American Studies or Department of Ethnic Studies. </span></li>
	<li><span>At the start of Session D, fill out the Completion of L&amp;S Minor form. Email the form to racelawminor@berkeley.edu, or bring the form to an advisor in the Department of African American Studies or Department of Ethnic Studies. </span></li>
	<li><span>You will receive a Completion of </span>Minor<span> document signed by the chairs of the Department of African American Studies and the Department of Ethnic Studies. </span></li>
</ol>
<h4><span>Students Outside of UC Berkeley</span></h4>
<h5>Race and the Law Certificate</h5>
<ol>
	<li><span>Enroll in Summer Session through <a href="http://summer.berkeley.edu/">Berkeley Summer Sessions</a>. </span></li>
	<li>At the start of Session D, fill out the Completion of Certificate form. Email the form to racelawminor@berkeley.edu, or bring the form to an advisor in the Department of African American Studies or Department of Ethnic Studies.</li>
	<li><span>You will receive a Certificate of Completion signed by the chairs of the Department of African American Studies and the Department of Ethnic Studies. </span></li>
</ol>
<h2><span>Financial Aid</span></h2>
<p>UC Berkeley students who enroll in the Race and the Law Minor and complete it within two consecutive Summer Sessions are eligible for a $1,500 scholarship<span>. To be awarded the scholarship, students must: </span></p>
<ul>
	<li><span>Be currently enrolled at UC Berkeley. </span></li>
	<li><span>Complete the academic requirements for the minor by the end of summer. </span></li>
	<li><span>Receive a grade of “C” or higher in all courses for the minor and complete all courses before graduation. </span></li>
	<li><span>Print out or complete the online Completion of L&amp;S Minor form and submit it to the Department of African American Studies or Department of Ethnic Studies within two </span>weeks of<span> the start of the final course. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>Submitting the Completion of L&amp;S Minor form will <span>trigger your scholarship application. You will receive an acknowledgment that you have successfully completed the Minor. Your $1500 scholarship will be posted as “Scholarship” to your CARS account by December of that year. Please note that certificate candidates and students not enrolled at UC Berkeley are not eligible for the scholarship.</span></span></p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<minorrequirementstext name="Summer Minor Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h4>Requirements For UC Berkeley <span>Students </span></h4>
<p><strong><span>Race and the Law Summer Minor</span></strong></p>
<p>The minor consists of two required core courses and three elective courses taught in two consecutive summer sessions. Students declaring a minor must do so in writing to <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/degree-programs/race-and-law/mailto:racelawminor@berkeley.edu">racelawminor@berkeley.edu</a>. The minor can be completed in one summer or more. </p>
<p>All minors must be declared no later than one semester before a student's Expected Graduation Term (EGT). If the semester before EGT is fall or spring, the deadline is the last day of RRR week. If the semester before EGT is summer, the deadline is the final Friday of Summer Sessions. To declare a minor, contact the department advisor for information on requirements, and the declaration process.</p>
<div class="yj6qo ajU"> </div>
<div class="yj6qo ajU"><strong>Requirements For non-UC Berkeley Students</strong></div>
<p><strong><span>Race and the Law Certificate </span></strong></p>
<p><span>The certificate consists of two required core courses and three elective courses taught in two consecutive summer sessions. The certificate can be completed in one summer or more. </span></p>
<h4><span>Required Core Courses </span></h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AFRICAM 136L">AFRICAM 136L</span></td><td>Criminal Justice and Surveillance in America</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ETH STD 144AC">ETH STD 144AC</span></td><td>Racism and the U.S. Law: Historical Treatment of Peoples of Color</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h4>Elective Courses</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AFRICAM 125AC">AFRICAM 125AC</span></td><td>The History of the Modern Civil Rights Movement</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AFRICAM 139L">AFRICAM 139L</span></td><td>Special Topics in Race and Law</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ETH STD 180L">ETH STD 180L</span></td><td>Selected Topics in Race and the Law</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</minorrequirementstext>
<academicadvisingtext name="Academic Advising">
<![CDATA[
<p>Students are encouraged to meet during the semester with an undergraduate advisor to discuss the Race and Law Summer Minor. Please see the Contact Information tab for more information.</p>
<p>Most advising is available during drop-in hours: Tuesday through Friday, 9 a.m. to noon and 1 to 4 p.m., and by appointment.</p>
]]>
</academicadvisingtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

