<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Molecular Toxicology</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Molecular Toxicology PhD program at UC Berkeley gives in-depth training on the foundations of toxicology as well as modern-age approaches used to study the toxicological mechanisms associated with environmental and pharmaceutical chemicals.</p>
<p>The Molecular Toxicology PhD program is a cross-departmental graduate program that trains the next generation of toxicologists to develop and apply innovative methodologies to identify chemical hazards and understand their toxicological mechanisms. The <a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/molecular-toxicology" target="_blank">faculty within the Molecular Toxicology PhD program</a> have diverse backgrounds and research interests, ranging from understanding the fundamental mechanisms of biology and disease; to characterizing toxicological mechanisms of environmental or pharmaceutical chemicals; from developing new technologies to understand chemical toxicology; to epidemiologically correlating chemical exposure to human pathologies. They span several departments and schools, including the departments of Nutritional Sciences and Toxicology, Chemistry, Molecular and Cell Biology, Plant and Microbial Biology, and the School of Public Health.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/molecular-toxicology/">Molecular Toxicology</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Danica Chen, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Aging, stem cell, diseases of aging.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14611"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Brenda Eskenazi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, epidemiology, biostatistics, maternal and child health.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14640"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Gary L. Firestone, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, steroid hormones, molecular endocrinology, tumor biology, growth factors, dietary compounds, tumor cells, glucocorticoids.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13887"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Tyrone Hayes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, amphibians, developmental endocrinology, steroid hormones, metamorphosis, sex differentiation, hormonal differentiation, African clawed frog, Japnanes Kajika, Pine Barrens treefrog.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14815"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Isao Kubo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Agriculture, insect biology, pest management.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14938"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fenyong Liu, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15029"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sheng Luan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microbial biology, plant biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15325"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel K. Nomura, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical biology, metabolism, toxicology, cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16349"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barry Shane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martyn T. Smith, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, genomics, toxicology, molecular epidemiology, exposome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15044"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Norman Terry, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Phytoremediation, Bioremediation, environmental cleanup, soil and water, plant biology, microbial biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15354"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jen-Chywan (Wally) Wang, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Steroid hormones, glucocorticoids, molecular physiology, Metabolic Diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15597"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

