<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Indigenous Language Revitalization</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Designated Emphasis (DE) in Indigenous Language Revitalization enables interested graduate students already enrolled in UC Berkeley PhD programs to specialize and obtain certification in language revitalization while pursuing a doctoral degree in their home departments. The DE in Indigenous Language Revitalization is not an independent degree-granting program. Students admitted to the program's DE and who complete its requirements will receive a notation to that effect on their doctoral degrees.</p>
<p>The DE in Indigenous Language Revitalization creates an interdisciplinary course of study, drawing together an intellectual cohort that will equip graduate students from various departments with knowledge of the methods, histories, and goals of Indigenous language revitalization and reclamation. The DE emphasizes interdisciplinary coursework and hands-on experience (through practicum or fieldwork credits) that center on the critical methods and histories of the attempted eradication, the persistence, and the revitalization of Indigenous languages in the context of colonization. While the content of the DE primarily focuses on Indigenous contexts in the Americas, it is relevant to Indigenous settings globally. </p>
<p>The DE draws upon and extends the unique resources available at Berkeley. The Linguistics Department has long been a leader in the study of Indigenous languages of the Americas (and throughout the world, e.g. in Africa and Southeast Asia), also supporting resources such as the Survey of California and Other Indian Languages and the California Language Archive. It has also been a leader in language revitalization. Indigenous community members and speakers teach and study at Berkeley and/or collaborate with Berkeley researchers. Community-driven language work is highly valued and supported. This rich intellectual heritage is the cornerstone of a DE that specifically trains and signals expertise in the area of Indigenous language revitalization. In Native American Studies and Education, courses and faculty research have long addressed the historical and cultural contexts of language loss; educational policies related to language; and the epistemological and cultural values of Indigenous languages. A critical mass of faculty and graduate students with shared interests in Indigenous language revitalization are working in linguistics, education, Native American studies, classics, music, romance languages, environmental sciences, biology, and anthropology. </p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>Graduate students are invited to apply to the DE after completion of their first year at Berkeley. The application consists of the following:</p>
<div>
<ol>
	<li>A completed <a href="https://lx.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/ilr-de-application.pdf">DE</a><a href="https://lx.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/ilr-de-application.pdf"> application form</a></li>
	<li>A short statement (up 500 words) describing the applicant's interest in the DE and how it fits into his or her graduate studies and research goals</li>
	<li>An unofficial transcript of coursework at Berkeley</li>
	<li>
	<p> A current C.V.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>A brief letter from the applicant's faculty advisor endorsing participation in the DE, sent under separate cover</p>
	</li>
</ol>
</div>
<p>All materials should be sent as email attachments to Belén Flores (<a class="m_-854088059701121765gmail-m_6938287040131133996gmail-m_811118333473881710gmail-m_-80938646979445365gmail-m_7350373908996350177moz-txt-link-abbreviated" href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/graduate/degree-programs/indigenous-language-revitalization/mailto:ling-gsao@berkeley.edu" target="_blank">ling-gsao@berkeley.edu</a>). Applications are due each year on <span class="m_-854088059701121765gmail-aBn"><span class="m_-854088059701121765gmail-aQJ"><span class="aBn" data-term="goog_700168223" tabindex="0"><span class="aQJ">November 2</span></span></span></span><strong>,</strong> and the Executive Committee meets to review the applications and make admissions decisions shortly thereafter.</p>
<p>For further information regarding admission to graduate programs at UC Berkeley, please see the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">Graduate Division's Admissions website</a>.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequirementstext name="Designated Emphasis Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Core Course</h3>
<p>Each student is required to take <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 251">LINGUIS 251</span></span>. This course draws components from each of the three core departments, focusing on historical contexts for language loss and challenges for revitalization; specific methods and theories for working with linguistic materials and collaborating with indigenous communities and speakers; and examining the results of language revitalization in cultural, linguistic, political and aesthetic terms. The course must be taken for a grade. (Another course can replace <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 251">LINGUIS 251</span></span> in special circumstances approved by the DE Head Graduate Adviser.)</p>
<h3>Elective Course</h3>
<p>Each student in the DE must take one elective course (that is not in the student’s home department), chosen from the following list of courses:</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Anthropology</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 122A">ANTHRO 122A</span></td><td>Archaeology of the Americas: Archaeology of North America</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 122F">ANTHRO 122F</span></td><td>Archaeology of the Americas: California Archaeology</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 124A">ANTHRO 124A</span></td><td>Pacific Cultures: Archaeology of the South Pacific</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 149">ANTHRO 149</span></td><td>Psychological Anthropology</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 174AC">ANTHRO 174AC</span></td><td>California Historical Anthropology</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 179">ANTHRO 179</span></td><td>Ethnography of the Maya</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 240A">ANTHRO 240A</span></td><td>Fundamentals of Anthropological Theory</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 240B">ANTHRO 240B</span></td><td>Fundamentals of Anthropological Theory</td><td class="hourscol">5</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ANTHRO 270B">ANTHRO 270B</span></td><td>Seminars in Linguistic Anthropology: Fundamentals of Language in Context</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Education</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 146A">EDUC 146A</span></td><td>Education and Migration: Indigeneity in Yucatan and Its Diaspora</td><td class="hourscol">6</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 188B">EDUC 188B</span></td><td>Native American Education: Critical Issues and Possibilities</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 188F">EDUC 188F</span></td><td>Language, Race, and Power in Education</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 240A">EDUC 240A</span></td><td>Language Study for Educators</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 240B">EDUC 240B</span></td><td>Theoretical Issues in the Study of Literacy</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 240C">EDUC 240C</span></td><td>Issues in First and Second Language Acquisition</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 241B">EDUC 241B</span></td><td>Language Socialization</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Ethnic Studies</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ETH STD 250">ETH STD 250</span></td><td>Research Seminar: Selected Issues and Topics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Linguistics</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 100">LINGUIS 100</span></td><td>Introduction to Linguistic Science</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 154">LINGUIS 154</span></td><td>Language Revitalization: Theory and Practice</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 175">LINGUIS 175</span></td><td>American Indian Languages</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 240A">LINGUIS 240A</span></td><td>Advanced Field Methods</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 240B">LINGUIS 240B</span></td><td>Advanced Field Methods</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 245">LINGUIS 245</span></td><td>Anthropological Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LINGUIS 255">LINGUIS 255</span></td><td>Advanced Sociolinguistics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Native American Studies</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NATAMST 190">NATAMST 190</span></td><td>Seminar on Advanced Topics in Native American Studies</td><td class="hourscol">1-4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>With approval from the DE Head Graduate Adviser, a student may fulfill the elective requirement through another course (including courses at Stanford or UC Davis as appropriate) or through a 299 Reading and Conference course. Students should note that some of the courses above have prerequisites which would also have to be satisfied.</p>
<h3>Practicum</h3>
<p>Each student in the DE must complete a field project (&quot;practicum&quot;) related to language revitalization, a hands-on project, under the supervision of a DE faculty member. This may be carried out through a structured program, including, but not limited to, the American Indian Language Development Institute; the Breath of Life Institute in Berkeley or Washington, D.C.; and the Northwest Indian Languages Institute. A field project can also be organized directly in collaboration with speakers, teachers, or language activists; tribal language programs; other governmental language programs; or other entities. The practicum should involve work equivalent to 2–4 semester units (45-90 hours) as approved by the DE Head Graduate Adviser.</p>
<h3>Qualifying Exam and Dissertation</h3>
<p>The student’s PhD Qualifying Exam Committee and Dissertation Committee must include at least one member of the Indigenous Language Revitalization Graduate Group core faculty. The dissertation project must address or engage with issues or methods in language revitalization in some substantive manner, from some academic perspective. The representative DE committee member will evaluate the substance of the material.</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Patricia Baquedano-Lopez, <i>Associate Professor, Graduate School of Education</i>. </strong>Immigration and diaspora from Latin America to the U S , Latinx and education, race and language, language socialization processes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14590"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christine Beier, <i>Assistant Adjunct Professor, Department of Linguistics</i>. </strong>Language endangerment, vitality, and revitalization; language documentation and description; Amazonian languages.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Andrew Garrett, <i>Professor, Department of Linguistics</i>. </strong>Linguistics, English, California, language change, Indo-European languages, historical linguistics, northern California Indian languages, linguistic structure, typology, ancient Greek, Latin, Irish, Oceanic languages.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14704"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Lev D. Michael, <i>Professor, Department of Linguistics</i>. </strong>Linguistic typology, Amazonian languages, anthropological linguistics, language contact and areal typology, language documentation and description.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14570"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Line Mikkelsen, <i>Professor, Department of Linguistics </i>. </strong>Morphology, syntax, semantics, Germanic and California languages.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15344"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Beth Piatote, <i>Associate Professor, Departments of English and Comparative Literature , Affiliated Faculty, Department of Linguistics, Affiliated Faculty, Department of Theater, Dance, and Performance Studies, Affiliated Faculty, American Studies</i>. </strong>Native American Studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15378"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

