<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Welcome from the Chancellor</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<p>Hello, and welcome to the Berkeley Academic Guide. </p>
<p>UC Berkeley offers myriad paths of discovery for students and scholars, and the Berkeley Academic Guide is an excellent place to begin your journey. Use the Guide to explore possible areas of study, learn about our academic programs and departments, access a wide range of resources, navigate degree requirements, plan your class schedule, and see the full breadth of academic opportunities available to you at UC Berkeley.</p>
<p><img alt="Chancellor Carol Christ" class="imgright" src="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/gallery/christwelcome_med.jpg"/></p>
<p>Our campus is one of the best places in the world to discover and develop your academic passions. Our faculty — filled with dedicated teachers, thinkers, innovators, and explorers — is second to none. An exemplary team of staff members, committed to excellence in every facet of the university’s operations, works hard to support our academic mission.​ Our graduate students — whom you will know as mentors, researchers, and teachers — are among the best. And your classmates will be by your side to partner with you and challenge you throughout your intellectual journey.</p>
<p>At Berkeley, we believe in the transformative power of a liberal arts education, and while the area of study you are <em>most</em> passionate about will likely become your academic major, I hope you’ll take this piece of advice to heart: Learn widely, not just deeply. I believe that the education you acquire outside of your major is just as important to your personal and professional development, and I encourage you to take advantage of the richness of our university by exploring different disciplines, building an array of skills, mastering many modes of thinking, and cultivating your whole self.</p>
<p>I hope the Academic Guide will prove to be a valuable tool as you chart your course through UC Berkeley. Fiat Lux!</p>
<p>Sincerely,</p>
<h4><strong>Carol Christ</strong></h4>
<h5><strong>Chancellor</strong></h5>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

