<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>American Studies</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Bachelor of Arts (BA)</h3>
<p>American Studies is an individualized interdisciplinary major that offers undergraduates a unique opportunity to take advantage of the depth and breadth of Americanist scholarship and research on the campus in order to explore and understand the United States and its place in the globalizing world. American studies courses integrate a variety of subjects, methods, and materials from many academic disciplines, including the traditional blend of history and literature, as well as the social sciences, material culture, built environment, law, technology, urbanism, ecology, economy, and arts.</p>
<h3>Declaring the Major</h3>
<p>In order to declare the major, students with less than 60 units must complete <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 10">AMERSTD 10</span></span> and one other lower division requirement. Students beyond 60 units must be enrolled in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 10">AMERSTD 10</span></span> and speak with a faculty adviser before being allowed to declare. For details on how to declare, please see the student academic adviser at 265 Evans Hall, email: <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/degree-programs/american-studies/mailto:amerstd@berkeley.edu">amerstd@berkeley.edu</a>.</p>
<h3>Honors Program</h3>
<p>Students who wish to be eligible to graduate with honors must enroll in the honors thesis seminar, <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD H195">AMERSTD H195</span></span>. For admission to the course, students must have senior standing, an overall GPA of 3.51, and a GPA of 3.65 in the major. For further information, please contact the student academic adviser in 265 Evans Hall, email: <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/degree-programs/american-studies/mailto:amerstd@berkeley.edu">amerstd@berkeley.edu</a>.</p>
<h3><span>Declaring the Minor</span></h3>
<p>Visit the <a href="https://as.ugis.berkeley.edu/american-studies-minor/" target="_blank">American Studies Minor webpage</a> for information about declaring the minor.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<majorrequirementstext name="Major Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p>In addition to the University, campus, and college requirements, listed on the College Requirements tab, students must fulfill the below requirements specific to their major program.</p>
<h3>General Guidelines</h3>
<ol>
	<li>All courses taken to fulfill the major requirements below must be taken for graded credit, other than courses listed which are offered on a <em>Pass/No Pass</em> basis only. Other exceptions to this requirement are noted as applicable.</li>
	<li>No more than one upper division course may be used to simultaneously fulfill requirements for a student's major and minor programs, with the exception of minors offered outside of the College of Letters &amp; Science.</li>
	<li>A minimum grade point average (GPA) of 2.0 must be maintained in both upper and lower division courses used to fulfill the major requirements.</li>
</ol>
<p>For information regarding residence requirements and unit requirements, please see the College Requirements tab.</p>
<h3>Summary of Degree Requirements</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Lower Division Prerequisites: Four courses total</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Upper Division Requirements: 30-36 units</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Historical Requirement</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Senior Thesis Requirement: Four units</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>Please see below for the specific details regarding these requirements.</p>
<h3>Lower Division Prerequisites</h3>
<p>The lower division prerequisites are meant to introduce the student to a variety of scholarly approaches to the study of American culture and society. In order to determine whether particular courses fulfills the prerequisites, please contact the American Studies student academic adviser in 237 Evans Hall or an American Studies faculty adviser.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 10">AMERSTD 10</span></td><td>Introduction to American Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass even firstrow"><td class="codecol orclass">or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 10AC">AMERSTD 10AC</span></td><td colspan="2"> Introduction to American Studies</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select three lower division courses that focus on the United States</span> <sup>1, 2</sup></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<dl class="sc_footnotes" aria-label="Footnotes"><dt> <sup> 1 </sup> </dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent">No more than three of these courses may be from the same department.</p></dd><dt> <sup> 2 </sup> </dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent"> Appropriate courses taken at other universities or community colleges may be substituted with faculty adviser approval.</p></dd></dl>
<h3>Upper Division Requirements</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">30-36 units, distributed among the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Core Methods Courses: 6-8 units</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Students are required to take one course each from the two methods series, &quot;Examining US Cultures in Time&quot; and &quot;Examining US Cultures in Place.&quot; See the program's website for available courses every semester. It is expected that these courses will be completed during the junior year. Due to the unique interdisciplinary nature of the courses, these requirements should be satisfied at UC Berkeley.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Area of Concentration: minimum of six courses, 18-20 units</span> <sup>1</sup></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Upper division coursework drawn from the College of Letters &amp; Science and the professional schools and colleges, in the student's individually articulated area of concentration. Areas of concentration may be highly individualized, depending on the student's intellectual focus, prior preparation, and the availability of courses. Students planning to declare the major should complete a four year plan, major application form and meet with a faculty adviser in their sophomore year or early in their junior year to plan their upper division program. Subsequently, this program can be revised with the approval of the faculty adviser.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<dl class="sc_footnotes" aria-label="Footnotes"><dt> <sup> 1 </sup> </dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent">The area of concentration must include courses from at least two different departments, but no more than three courses from any one discipline. The area may include courses from up to six different departments.</p></dd></dl>
<h3>Historical Requirement</h3>
<p>One of the courses taken to complete the American Studies major (either upper or lower division) must focus on US history, culture, and/or politics before 1900. Students should check with an American Studies student academic adviser to ensure that the course they take meets this requirement.</p>
<h3>Senior Thesis Requirement</h3>
<p>Because American Studies at UC Berkeley is an interdisciplinary program based on the major's own offerings and supplemented by individualized programs of study drawing on the resources of the whole campus, students in this major complete their work in the major with an interdisciplinary senior thesis. The thesis is intended to give students the opportunity to develop an extended analysis of a significant problem related to their area of concentration and to craft the essay into a finished piece of scholarly work. It is designed to give students a sense of competence and confidence in researching, framing, and completing an explicitly interdisciplinary project.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select one of the following thesis course options:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 191">AMERSTD 191</span></div></td><td>Senior Thesis Seminar [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 190">AMERSTD 190</span></div></td><td>Senior Thesis [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD H195">AMERSTD H195</span></div></td><td>Senior Honors Thesis Seminar [4]</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">A thesis course offered by another department</span> <sup>1</sup></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

<dl class="sc_footnotes" aria-label="Footnotes"><dt> <sup> 1 </sup> </dt><dd start-indent="3%"><p class="noindent">A thesis course from another department must be approved in advance by an American Studies faculty adviser. </p></dd></dl>
]]>
</majorrequirementstext>
<newitemtext name="Minor Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p>The American Studies minor allows students to take advantage of the one of largest and most diverse course curricula available anywhere in the world as well as learn about the American context that impacts and defines the issues they are learning about in their departmental majors. Open to all UC Berkeley students, the minor will introduce students to interdisciplinary modes of inquiry, foster knowledge about the culture of the U.S., and train students to write and communicate clearly about it.</p>
<p>To receive a minor in American Studies, students must complete 24-units as follows:</p>
<ul>
	<li>One lower-division Introduction to American Studies course: <span class="sc_courseinline">Introduction to American Studies (<span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 10">AMERSTD 10</span>, 4 s.h.)</span> or <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 10AC">AMERSTD 10AC</span> Introduction to American Studies (4 s.h.)</span> (4 units)</li>
	<li>Two upper-division courses that focus on “Time,” and two upper-division “Place” courses in American Studies (16 total units)</li>
	<li>One capstone research/writing project to be completed in one of the existing seminar courses taught by American Studies affiliated faculty (4 units)</li>
</ul>
<p>All students in the minor will have hands-on guidance and advice from American Studies faculty. For more information about the minor, please <a href="https://as.ugis.berkeley.edu/american-studies-minor/">see our website</a> and contact the American Studies Student Academic Advisor, Laura Spautz at <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/undergraduate/degree-programs/american-studies/mailto:amerstd@berkeley.edu" target="_blank">amerstd@berkeley.edu</a>.</p>
]]>
</newitemtext>
<collegerequirementstext name="College Requirements">
<![CDATA[
 <p>Undergraduate students must fulfill the following requirements in addition to those required by their major program.</p> <p>For detailed lists of courses that fulfill college requirements, please review the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/">College of Letters &amp; Sciences</a> page in this Guide. For College advising appointments, please visit the <a href="https://lsadvising.berkeley.edu/home">L&amp;S Advising</a> Pages. </p> <h3>University of California Requirements</h3> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/entry-level-writing-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-b6fc-99fe-5be6e0865dad">Entry Level Writing</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-c602-c395-1fb0f53c604b">All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by fulfilling the Entry Level Writing requirement. Fulfillment of this requirement is also a prerequisite to enrollment in all reading and composition courses at UC Berkeley. </span></p> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/american-history-institutions-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-ed90-bc30-8e7c7e9092f7">American History and American Institutions</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-fe3e-933e-7102e097ef4b">The American History and Institutions requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university, should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</span></p> <h3><span>Berkeley Campus Requirement</span></h3> <h5><a href="http://americancultures.berkeley.edu/students/courses"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-3abc-dc51-fc563caacff1">American Cultures</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-47e1-1ad4-b918d33461cf">All undergraduate students at Cal need to take and pass this course in order to graduate. The requirement offers an exciting intellectual environment centered on the study of race, ethnicity and culture of the United States. AC courses offer students opportunities to be part of research-led, highly accomplished teaching environments, grappling with the complexity of American Culture.</span></p> <h3><span>College of Letters &amp; Science Essential Skills Requirements</span></h3> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/quantitative-reasoning-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-a7b1-d295-ee03b476bcfe">Quantitative Reasoning</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-cbac-1c7a-d74abefae398">The Quantitative Reasoning requirement is designed to ensure that students graduate with basic understanding and competency in math, statistics, or computer science. The requirement may be satisfied by exam or by taking an approved course.</span></p> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/foreign-language-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-ff23-6ff3-47abec092456">Foreign Language</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-12d9-db19-1b37f6639ef7">The Foreign Language requirement may be satisfied by demonstrating proficiency in reading comprehension, writing, and conversation in a foreign language equivalent to the second semester college level, either by passing an exam or by completing approved course work.</span></p> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/reading-composition-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-3e15-2491-27223f91e87d">Reading and Composit</span>ion</a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-4ef4-4b87-0d26195a0d3c">In order to provide </span>a solid foundation in reading, writing, and critical thinking the College requires two semesters of lower division work in composition in sequence. Students must complete parts A &amp; B reading and composition courses in sequential order by the end of their fourth semester.</p> <h3>College of Letters &amp; Science 7 Course Breadth Requirements</h3> <h5><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/#breadthrequirementstext"><span id="docs-internal-guid-79a9fe70-d405-7c7e-e34f-837b91cc1d58">Breadth Requirements</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-9db4-c30e-bca05ecf44f3">The undergraduate breadth requirements provide Berkeley students with a rich and varied educational experience outside of their major program. As the foundation of a liberal arts education, breadth courses give students a view into the intellectual life of the University while introducing them to a multitude of perspectives and approaches to research and scholarship. Engaging students in new disciplines and with peers from other majors, the breadth experience strengthens interdisciplinary connections and context that prepares Berkeley graduates to understand and solve the complex issues of their day.</span></p> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-abca8c8f-d405-c4ad-0be7-1638c654345c">Unit Requirements</span></h3> <ul> 	<li> 	<p>120 total units</p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>Of the 120 units, 36 must be upper division units</p> 	</li> 	<li>Of the 36 upper division units, 6 must be taken in courses offered outside your major department</li> </ul> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-2bb674c5-d406-43a4-39ed-40d6e86d6760">Residence Requirements</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-8d38-492a-067b2e0bac2d">For units to be considered in &quot;residence,&quot; you must be registered in courses on the Berkeley campus as a student in the College of Letters &amp; Science. Most students automatically fulfill the residence requirement by attending classes here for four years. In general, there is no need to be concerned about this requirement, unless you go abroad for a semester or year or want to take courses at another institution or through UC Extension during your senior year. In these cases, you should make an appointment to meet an adviser to determine how you can meet the Senior Residence Requirement.</span></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-a2e5-35d5-82895d287218">Note: Courses taken through UC Extension do not count toward residence.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-44b2bced-d406-cb13-a0f5-0c6f75ed8972">Senior Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-e3bd-f620-e9bef1331f97">After you become a senior (with 90 semester units earned toward your BA degree), you must complete at least 24 of the remaining 30 units in residence in at least two semesters. To count as residence, a semester must consist of at least 6 passed units. Intercampus Visitor, EAP, and UC Berkeley-Washington Program (UCDC) units are excluded.</span></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-f7f7-c9da-c2732368bc4e">You may use a Berkeley Summer Session to satisfy one semester of the Senior Residence requirement, provided that you successfully complete 6 units of course work in the Summer Session and that you have been enrolled previously in the college.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-abb18f5b-d407-0e0f-9d41-83c0ea3c3c7b">Modified Senior Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d407-3956-aeef-b67b71969fca">Participants in the UC Education Abroad Program (EAP), Berkeley Summer Abroad, or the UC Berkeley Washington Program (UCDC) may meet a Modified Senior Residence requirement by completing 24 (excluding EAP) of their final 60 semester units in residence. At least 12 of these 24 units must be completed after you have completed 90 units.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-62f287bf-d407-4ca6-5bbd-2d1393418d66">Upper Division Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d407-6060-9575-98782777275a">You must complete in residence a minimum of 18 units of upper division courses (excluding UCEAP units), 12 of which must satisfy the requirements for your major.</span></p>
]]>
</collegerequirementstext>
<studentlearninggoalstext name="Student Learning Goals">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Mission</h3>
<p>The goal of the American Studies interdisciplinary major is to enable students to learn a set of research, critical thinking, and written and oral communication skills that will enable them to become self-conscious and thoughtful investigators of American society. To meet this basic goal, our courses are designed to give students a basic understanding of American history, culture, political economy, social structures, and environment (both natural and constructed), as well as to enable them to use a range of concepts and methods to define and analyze significant problems, issues, and questions relating to American life. Through a close reading of diverse texts and physical and cultural materials, American Studies students learn how to critically analyze how individuals, groups, and a wide variety of political, economic, and cultural institutions have interacted to shape and give meaning to the American experience.</p>
<h3>Learning Goals for the Major</h3>
<ol>
	<li>Research Skills:
	<ul>
		<li>Students learn how to locate and evaluate primary source materials and secondary texts. These include published contemporary and historical documents, artifacts of material culture, landscape and architectural structures, visual and auditory media, oral history, and folklore.</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>Critical Thinking Skills:
	<ul>
		<li>Students learn how to analyze and evaluate cultural texts including literature, performance, film, art, etc., and demonstrate a basic understanding of cultural theory and aesthetics (i.e., to understand and think critically about American society from a humanities perspective).</li>
		<li>Students learn to critically analyze and evaluate social science arguments, demonstrating an understanding of the premises of qualitative and quantitative evidence (i.e., understand and think critically about American society from a social science perspective).</li>
		<li>Students learn to analyze and understand the American past so as to gain perspective on and critical understanding of current issues and problems in American life (i.e., to understand and think critically about American society from an historical perspective, which by definition integrates humanities and social science approaches).</li>
		<li>Students learn to critically analyze and interpret the meaning of American material culture and its built and natural environments (i.e., understand and think critically about American society from the perspectives of the knowledges embodied in the disciplines of geography, architecture, landscape architecture, environmental studies, and art).</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>Written and Oral Communication Skills
	<ul>
		<li>Students learn how to communicate effectively in written form, demonstrating the ability to formulate a well organized argument supported by evidence.</li>
		<li>Students learn how to communicate effectively orally, while demonstrating the ability to listen and respond to what others are saying.</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>Specialized Knowledge
	<ul>
		<li>Time: Students gain in-depth, substantive knowledge about American life and culture in a particular year.</li>
		<li>Place: Students gain in-depth, substantive knowledge about American life and culture in a particular city, region, or other place.</li>
		<li>Students gain in-depth substantive knowledge about particular themes, issues, problems, and questions in American life and experience.</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>Integrative Knowledge and Skills
	<ul>
		<li>Students demonstrate their mastery of all of the above skills by writing a Senior Thesis that is a focused interdisciplinary research project in their specialized area of concentration. </li>
	</ul>
	</li>
</ol>
]]>
</studentlearninggoalstext>
<majormaptext name="Major Map">
<![CDATA[
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0b5c2d1-7fff-0bb8-5335-f025a2cbd465">Major Maps help undergraduate students discover academic, co-curricular, and discovery opportunities at UC Berkeley based on intended major or field of interest. Developed by the Division of Undergraduate Education in collaboration with academic departments, these experience maps will help you:</span></p>
<ul>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0b5c2d1-7fff-0bb8-5335-f025a2cbd465">Explore</span></strong> your major and gain a better understanding of your field of study</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0b5c2d1-7fff-0bb8-5335-f025a2cbd465">Connect</span></strong> with people and programs that inspire and sustain your creativity, drive, curiosity and success</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0b5c2d1-7fff-0bb8-5335-f025a2cbd465">Discover</span></strong> opportunities for independent inquiry, enterprise, and creative expression</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0b5c2d1-7fff-0bb8-5335-f025a2cbd465">Engage</span></strong> locally and globally to broaden your perspectives and change the world</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0b5c2d1-7fff-0bb8-5335-f025a2cbd465">Reflect</span></strong> on your academic career and prepare for life after Berkeley</p>
	</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-b0b5c2d1-7fff-0bb8-5335-f025a2cbd465">Use the major map below as a guide to planning your undergraduate journey and designing your own unique Berkeley experience.</span></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://ue.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/american_studies.pdf">View the American Studies Major Map PDF.</a></strong></p>
<div> </div>
]]>
</majormaptext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>American Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd5" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd5">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 5</span> 
<span class="title">Keywords in American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd5">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 2016 10 Week Session, Summer 2016 3 Week Session<br/>
Inspired by Raymond Williams’ classic text, Keywords: A Vocabulary of Culture and Society, and the recent Keywords of American Cultural Studies (Burgett and Hendler), this course will provide a short and focused introduction to central terms and debates in American Studies. The goal is: (1) to enable each student to develop a critical understanding of a key concept such as “Race,” “Representation,” “Class,” and “Democracy':</span><span class="deschide"> (2) allow students to become familiar with some of the major scholarly works on the keyword; and (3) introduce students to the kind of interdisciplinary inquiry that characterizes our American Studies program.<br/></span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Keywords in American Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="676" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 3 weeks - 9 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Nine hours of lecture per week for three weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Keywords in American Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd10" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd10">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 10</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd10">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Summer 2023 Second 6 Week Session, Spring 2023<br/>
American culture and cultural change, with attention to the multicultural basis of American society and emphasis on the need for multiple methods of analysis. The course will consistently draw on the arts, material culture, and various fields affecting cultural production and meaning. Those areas include literature, film, history, architecture, history of art, religion, music, engineering, environmental studies, anthropology</span><span class="deschide">, politics, economics, law, and medicine. This course may include discussion sections depending on available funding. Some versions of this course need four in-class contact hours because of the extensive use of media.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to American Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="859" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for American Studies 10 after completing American Studies 10AC. A deficient grade in American Studies 10 may be removed by taking American Studies 10AC.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture and 0-1 hours of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5-10 hours of lecture and 0-2.5 hours of discussion per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 6-7.5 hours of lecture and 0-2 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to four hours of lecture and zero to one hours of discussion per week. Six to seven and one-half hours of lecture and zero to two hours of discussion per week for 8 weeks. Seven and one-half to ten hours of lecture and zero to two and one-half hours of discussion per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Undergraduate Interdisciplinary Studies 10</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to American Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd10ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd10ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 10AC</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd10ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2013, Spring 2012, Fall 2011<br/>
American culture and cultural change, with attention to the multicultural basis of American society and emphasis on the need for multiple methods of analysis. The course will consistently draw on the arts, material culture, and various fields affecting cultural production and meaning. Those areas include literature, film, history, architecture, history of art, religion, music, engineering, environmental studies, anthropology, politics, economics</span><span class="deschide">, law, and medicine.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to American Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="239" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for 10AC after taking 10 or Undergraduate and Interdisciplinary Studies 10. A deficient grade in American Studies 10 or Interdisciplinary Studies 10 may be removed by taking American Studies 10AC.</p><p><strong>Requirements this course satisfies:</strong> Satisfies the American Cultures requirement</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to American Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc10" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc10">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C10</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to American Studies: Hollywood: the Place, the Industry, the Fantasy</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc10">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2013<br/>
This course will introduce students to the interdisciplinary field of American Studies, taking the &quot;Hollywood Dream Factory&quot; as the central theme. Focusing on both parts of that phrase, the course will proceed along a double path. We will examine the historical and geographical development of the motion picture industry from the rise of the studio system to the &quot;new&quot; entertainment economy of the 1980's and we will examine ways Hollywood is represented</span><span class="deschide"> in literature and film.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to American Studies: Hollywood: the Place, the Industry, the Fantasy:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="913" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Moran</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> L &amp; S C40T</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to American Studies: Hollywood: the Place, the Industry, the Fantasy:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd24" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd24">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 24</span> 
<span class="title">Freshman Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd24">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2019, Fall 2017, Fall 2009<br/>
The Freshman Seminar Program has been designed to provide new students with the opportunity to explore an intellectual topic with a faculty member in a small seminar setting. Freshman seminars are offered in all campus departments, and topics vary from department to department and semester to semester. Enrollment limited to 15 freshmen.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Freshman Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="508" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Freshman Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd98" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd98">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 98</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Group Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd98">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Spring 2022<br/>
Written proposal must be approved by sponsoring faculty. Seminars for the group study of selected topics, which will vary from year to year. Topics may be initiated by students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Directed Group Study:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="678" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Open only to freshmen and sophomores. Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Enrollment is restricted; see the section on Academic Policies-Course Number Guide in the Berkeley Bulletin.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of directed group study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Group meetings to be arranged.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Offered for pass/not pass grade only. Final exam not required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Directed Group Study:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd99" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd99">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 99</span> 
<span class="title">Supervised Independent Study and Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd99">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2001, Fall 2000, Spring 2000<br/>
Independent study and research by arrangement with faculty.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Supervised Independent Study and Research:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="381" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Restricted to freshmen and sophomores; consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Enrollment is restricted; see the section on Academic Policies-Course Number Guide in the Berkeley Bulletin.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Four hour of Independent study per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Offered for pass/not pass grade only. Final exam not required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Supervised Independent Study and Research:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd101" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd101">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 101</span> 
<span class="title">Examining U.S. Cultures in Time</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd101">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Summer 2023 Second 6 Week Session, Spring 2023<br/>
This course examines how U.S. cultures are constructed, reinforced, and changed, and how those cultures act simultaneously at a given time. To help students develop skills in cultural analysis, lectures will contrast various methods and perspectives as they apply to the study of a particular year or decade. Topics will vary from semester to semester. This course may include discussion sections depending on available funding.</span><span class="deschide"> Some versions of this course need four in-class contact hours because of the extensive use of media.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Time:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="529" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture and 0-1 hours of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to four hours of lecture and zero to one hours of discussion per week. Seven and one-half hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Time:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd101ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd101ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 101AC</span> 
<span class="title">Examining U.S. Cultures in Time</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd101ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Summer 2021 First 6 Week Session, Fall 2020<br/>
This course examines how U.S. cultures are constructed, reinforced, and changed, and how those cultures act simultaneously at a given time. To help students develop skills in cultural analysis, lectures will contrast various methods and perspectives as they apply to the study of a particular year or decade. Topics will vary from semester to semester.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Time:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="610" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 101AC">AMERSTD 101AC</span> after completing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EDUC 130">EDUC 130</span>, ISF 103, EDUC C130, or UGIS 101. A deficient grade in <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 101AC">AMERSTD 101AC</span> may be removed by taking <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 101">AMERSTD 101</span>.</p><p><strong>Requirements this course satisfies:</strong> Satisfies the American Cultures requirement</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture and 0-1 hours of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture and 0 hours of discussion per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 5.5 hours of lecture and 0 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to four hours of lecture and zero to one hours of discussion per week. Five and one-half hours of lecture and zero hour of discussion per week for 8 weeks. Seven and one-half hours of lecture and zero hour of discussion per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Time:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd102" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd102">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 102</span> 
<span class="title">Examining U.S. Cultures in Place</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd102">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
This course examines how U.S. cultures are constructed, reinforced, and changed--particularly in reference to place and material culture. Qualitative and quantitative methods of analysis drawn from several disciplines will help students develop skills in cultural interpretation. Case studies may focus on a neighborhood, a city, or a region. Topics will vary from semester to semester. This course may include discussion sections depending on available</span><span class="deschide"> funding. Some versions of this course need four in-class contact hours because of the extensive use of media.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Place:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="388" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture and 0-1 hours of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to Four hours of Lecture and Zero to One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks. Seven and one-half hours of Lecture per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Place:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd102ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd102ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 102AC</span> 
<span class="title">Examining U.S. Cultures in Place</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd102ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
This course examines how U.S. cultures are constructed, reinforced, and changed--particularly in reference to place and material culture. Qualitative and quantitative methods of analysis drawn from several disciplines will help students develop skills in cultural interpretation. Case studies may focus on a neighborhood, a city, or a region. Topics will vary from semester to semester.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Place:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="173" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Requirements this course satisfies:</strong> Satisfies the American Cultures requirement</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4-3 hours of lecture and 0-1 hours of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 10-7.5 hours of lecture and 0-2.5 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four to three hours of lecture and zero to one hours of discussion per week. Ten to seven and one-half hours of lecture and zero to two and one-half hours of discussion per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Examining U.S. Cultures in Place:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd110" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd110">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 110</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">3 or 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd110">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Summer 2023 Second 6 Week Session, Spring 2023<br/>
This course is designed primarily to allow faculty to develop focused interdisciplinary courses which address specific issues, themes, or problems in American society. Topics vary from semester to semester. Students should consult the department's webpage for current offerings before the start of the semester.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in American Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="412" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5-10 hours of lecture per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 6-8 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to Four hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks. Six to Eight hours of Lecture per week for 8 weeks. Seven and one-half to Ten hours of Lecture per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in American Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd110ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd110ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 110AC</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in American Studies--American Cultures</span> 
<span class="hours">3 or 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd110ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2015 First 6 Week Session, Summer 2015 Second 6 Week Session, Summer 2004 10 Week Session<br/>
This course is designed primarily to allow faculty to develop focused interdisciplinary courses that address specific issues, themes, or problems in American society and American cultures. Topics vary from semester to semester.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in American Studies--American Cultures:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="499" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Requirements this course satisfies:</strong> Satisfies the American Cultures requirement</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5-10 hours of lecture per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 5.5-7.5 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three or four hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in American Studies--American Cultures:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdh110" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdh110">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD H110</span> 
<span class="title">Honors Seminar: Special Topics in American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">3 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdh110">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2022, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This course is designed to introduce honors students (those who have achieved a minimum overall GPA of 3.3) to the history and theory of American studies as an interdisciplinary field and to explore current themes, debates, and researh problems in American studies.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Honors Seminar: Special Topics in American Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="163" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor may be required</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of seminar per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5-10 hours of seminar per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 6-8 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to four hours of seminar per week. Six to eight hours of seminar per week for 8 weeks. Seven and one-half to ten hours of seminar per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Honors Seminar: Special Topics in American Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc111a" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc111a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C111A</span> 
<span class="title">Architecture in Depression and War</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc111a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2010<br/>
The Great Depression and World War II are arguably the two most influential events for the development of the built environment in the 20th century. Not only did they alter the socio-economic and political landscape on which architecture and urban planning depend, but they also led to technological innovations and vital debates about the built environment. This course examines the 1930's and 1940's topically, studying the work of the New Deal, corporate responses</span><span class="deschide"> to the Depression and war, the important connections between architecture and advertising, the role of the Museum of Modern Art in the promotion of Modernism, the concept of the ideal house, and key tests, theories, and projects from the period.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Architecture in Depression and War:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="427" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture and 0-1 hours of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture and 0-2.5 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to Four hours of Lecture and Zero to One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks. Seven and one-half hours of Lecture and Zero to Two and one-half hours of Discussion per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Shanken</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> ARCH C174</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Architecture in Depression and War:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc111e" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc111e">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C111E</span> 
<span class="title">Topics in American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc111e">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
A course on the intellectual, cultural, historical, and social backgrounds to American literature. Topics will vary from semester to semester. Students should consult the department's &quot;Announcement of Classes&quot; for current offerings well before the start of the semester.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Topics in American Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="847" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-4 hours of lecture and 1-0 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three to four hours of lecture and one to zero hours of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> ENGLISH C136</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Topics in American Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc112" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc112">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C112</span> 
<span class="title">The American Landscape: Place, Power and Culture</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc112">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
What is America as a landscape and a place, and how do we know it when we see it? This course seeks to address such questions, to introduce ways of seeing and interpreting American histories and cultures, as revealed in everyday built surroundings—homes, highways, farms, factories, stores, recreation areas, small towns, city districts, and regions. It does so through the lens of cultural geography, an interdisciplinary practice that developed, in part, here</span><span class="deschide"> at Berkeley. Our goal in this course is thus twofold: First, to develop literacy in the role of space and place in American culture, and second to develop a working knowledge of cultural geography as a practice.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The American Landscape: Place, Power and Culture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="471" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> . To introduce students to the central themes and practices of cultural geography;<br/>To explore the interaction of landscape (space, place, and the built environment) with American economics, politics, and culture;<br/>To reinforce and further develop advanced skills in seeing, thinking, researching, and writing.<br/>To teach students how to “read” landscapes as records of past and present social relations, and to form their own speculations from evidence about the cultural meanings of those landscapes;<br/>Upon completion of this course, it is hoped that students will appreciate the way that the American landscape both shapes and is given shape by economics, politics and culture. In studying practices of cultural geography, as well as undertaking their own experiments through course assignments, students will emerge with a better grasp of how to examine landscapes in an intellectually rigorous manner, and how to use the landscape as evidence for scholarship.<br/></p></div>

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Craghead</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> GEOG C160</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The American Landscape: Place, Power and Culture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc112a" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc112a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C112A</span> 
<span class="title">American Cultural Landscapes, 1600 to 1900</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc112a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Fall 2013, Fall 2012, Fall 2011<br/>
Introduces ways of seeing and interpreting American histories and cultures, as revealed in everyday built surroundings-- houses, highways, farms, factories, stores, recreation areas, small towns, city districts, and regions. Encourages students to read landscapes as records of past and present social relations and to speculate for themselves about cultural meaning.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>American Cultural Landscapes, 1600 to 1900:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="893" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Groth</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> ENV DES C169A/GEOG C160A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>American Cultural Landscapes, 1600 to 1900:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc112b" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc112b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C112B</span> 
<span class="title">American Cultural Landscapes, 1900 to Present</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc112b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2017, Spring 2015, Spring 2014<br/>
Introduces ways of seeing and interpreting American histories and cultures, as revealed in everyday built surroundings--homes, highways, farms, factories, stores, recreation areas, small towns, city districts, and regions. Encourages students to read landscapes as records of past and present social relations, and to speculate for themselves about cultural meaning.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>American Cultural Landscapes, 1900 to Present:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="273" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Groth</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> ENV DES C169B/GEOG C160B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>American Cultural Landscapes, 1900 to Present:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc112f" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc112f">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C112F</span> 
<span class="title">The American Forest: Its Ecology, History, and Representation</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc112f">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2012, Spring 2011, Spring 2007, Fall 2004<br/>
The American forest will be examined in terms of its ecology, history, and representations in paintings, photographs, and literary essays. This examination seeks to understand the American forest in its scientific and economic parameters, as well as the historic, social, and ideological dimensions which have contributed to the evolution of our present attitudes toward the forest.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The American Forest: Its Ecology, History, and Representation:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="647" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Lovell, McBride</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> ESPM C191/HISTART C189/UGIS C136</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The American Forest: Its Ecology, History, and Representation:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc115" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc115">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C115</span> 
<span class="title">The American Detective in Fiction, Film, and Television</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc115">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This course considers how the American detective is represented in fiction, fil, and popular culture. We will examine how representations of the American detective are affected by diverse historican and socio-cultural factors, including the ideology of American individualism, paradigms of investigation and ordered knowledge, and competing discourses of race, class, gender, and sexual orientation. After a brief consideration of early American detectives and detectives</span><span class="deschide"> in the classic American hardboiled tradition, we will focus on many detectives from traditionally understudied groups, including female detectives, African American detectives, Chicana detectives, Asian American detectives, Native American detectives, and gay and lesbian detectives. This course may be used as an elective in the American Studies major.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The American Detective in Fiction, Film, and Television:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="61" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Seven and one-half hours of Lecture per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Dresner</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> FILM C115</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The American Detective in Fiction, Film, and Television:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd121" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd121">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 121</span> 
<span class="title">Photography in America</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd121">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 1996 10 Week Session<br/>
The topic of this course is the history of photography in the United States, from the introduction of the medium in 1839 to the present decade. We will consider the medium chronologically as well as thematically, focusing on the following kinds of issues: the photograph as document and as fine art, the &quot;language&quot; and intentionality&quot; of photography, work and image in photographically illustrated media, the social role of the photograph</span><span class="deschide">, photography and gender. This course may be used as an elective in the American studies major.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Photography in America:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="238" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 6.5 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifty-two hours of lecture and eight hours of field trips, to be offered during six- or eight-week sessions.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Graham</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Photography in America:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd132y" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd132y">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 132Y</span> 
<span class="title">Native American Indian Autobiographies</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd132y">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 1995 10 Week Session<br/>
This course considers several autobiographies written by Native American Indians. The lectures, discussions, and required books focus on various cultural themes and theories of autobiography; a comparative review of diverse tribal experiences and narratives. Theories of cultural simulations and literary forms of representation in autobiographical literature will receive general attention in the course. Students will be required to participate in class</span><span class="deschide"> discussions and complete two hours review papers and a final examination.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Native American Indian Autobiographies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="273" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 3 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Five hours of lecture per week for three weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Vizenor</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Native American Indian Autobiographies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc132b" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc132b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C132B</span> 
<span class="title">Intellectual History of the United States since 1865</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc132b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2015, Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2012<br/>
In this course we will be discussing key developments in U.S. thought since the middle of the nineteenth century, roughly beginning with the reception of Darwin. The broader story told in the class weaves together in the history of science and engineering, the arts and popular culture, philosophy, and education. Our goal is to trace how ideas, whether they are dominant, challenging, or look back, have affected the ways in which Americans</span><span class="deschide"> live together. We will look at how intellectual life has empowered and expanded the capacity of Americans to understand their world and achieve goals more effectively. We will also consider how intellectual theories have contributed to inequality and injustice.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Intellectual History of the United States since 1865:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="773" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for C132B after taking 132B.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of lecture and 0-1 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and zero to one hours of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> HISTORY C132B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Intellectual History of the United States since 1865:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc134" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc134">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C134</span> 
<span class="title">Information Technology and Society</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc134">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2017, Fall 2016, Fall 2015, Fall 2014<br/>
This course assesses the role of information technology in the digitalization of society by focusing on the deployment of e-government, e-commerce, e-learning, the digital city, telecommuting, virtual communities, internet time, the virtual office, and the geography of cyber space. The course will also discuss the role of information technology in the governance and economic development of society.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Information Technology and Society:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="292" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Laguerre</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> AFRICAM C134</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Information Technology and Society:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd138ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd138ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 138AC</span> 
<span class="title">From Civil Rights Era to the New Gilded Age: Struggles for Racial Equality and Economic Equity from 'Double Victory' to 'Occupy'</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd138ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2016<br/>
World War II lifted the U.S. from the Great Depression and launched a long economic boom that helped underwrite and propel efforts on behalf of greater racial equality and economic equity. As that boom began to fade in the late 1960s, America’s march toward greater racial equality foundered, while its march toward greater economic equity began to reverse course. The Civil Rights Era gave way to the New Gilded Age. This course will explore the political, legal, and</span><span class="deschide"> economic history of America’s struggles for racial equality and economic equity – and the relationship between them.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>From Civil Rights Era to the New Gilded Age: Struggles for Racial Equality and Economic Equity from 'Double Victory' to 'Occupy':</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="86" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture and 2.5 hours of discussion per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 6 hours of lecture and 2 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week. Six hours of lecture and two hours of discussion per week for 8 weeks. Seven and one-half hours of lecture and two and one-half hours of discussion per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> BRILLIANT</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> HISTORY C139D</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>From Civil Rights Era to the New Gilded Age: Struggles for Racial Equality and Economic Equity from 'Double Victory' to 'Occupy':</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd139ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd139ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 139AC</span> 
<span class="title">Civil Rights and Social Movements in U.S. History</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd139ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Summer 2018 Second 6 Week Session<br/>
Beginning with the onset of World War II, America experienced not a sigular,unitary Civil Rights Movement -- as is typically portrayed in standard textbood accounts and the collective memory -- but rather a variety of contemporaneous civil rights and their related social movements. This course explores the history, presenting a top-down (political and legal history), bottom-up (social</span><span class="deschide"> and cultural history), and comparative (by race and ethnicity as well as region) view of America's struggles for racial equality from roughly World War II until the present.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Civil Rights and Social Movements in U.S. History:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="552" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture and 2 hours of discussion per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 5.5 hours of lecture and 2 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week. Five and one-half hours of lecture and two hours of discussion per week for 8 weeks. Seven and one-half hours of lecture and two hours of discussion per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> HISTORY C139C</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Civil Rights and Social Movements in U.S. History:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd142y" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd142y">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 142Y</span> 
<span class="title">Community Development in the Bay Area</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd142y">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 1995 10 Week Session<br/>
This course will provide students with opportunites to discuss and observe in action the most recent theories and practices pertaining to community development in the urban United States. Readings and discussion will be rooted in field trips and interviews with community activists, executive staff and nonprofits, professional planners and designers in the Bay Area. Students will have opportunities to take their own field trips and conduct interviews</span><span class="deschide"> based on their own interests.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Community Development in the Bay Area:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="868" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 3 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Five hours of lecture per week for three weeks plus field trips.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Morris</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Community Development in the Bay Area:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc152" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc152">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C152</span> 
<span class="title">Native American Literature</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc152">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2018<br/>
An analysis of the written and oral tradition developed by Native Americans. Emphasis will be placed on a multifaceted approach (aesthetic, linguistic, psychological, historical, and cultural) in examining American Indian literature.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Native American Literature:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="45" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 151 is recommended but not required</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks. Seven and one-half hours of Lecture per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> NATAMST C152</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Native American Literature:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd170ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd170ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 170AC</span> 
<span class="title">Race and Representation in US Culture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd170ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 2015 10 Week Session, Summer 2015 3 Week Session, Summer 2014 3 Week Session<br/>
This course will explore the history<br/>
of race, ethnicity and<br/>
representation across the 20th<br/>
century by considering the<br/>
overlapping histories of African<br/>
Americans, Native Americans and<br/>
Whites through the study of film,<br/>
photography and art, and humor.<br/>
This course satisfies the American<br/>
Cultures requirement by combining<br/>
the following 1-unit courses:<br/></span><span class="deschide">
American Studies 181B - Race<br/>
Photography, and Art; American<br/>
Studies 180D - Race and American<br/>
Humor ; and American Studies 184I<br/>
- Race and American Film.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Race and Representation in US Culture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="586" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive 2 units for American Studies 170AC after taking American Studies 180D, 181B, or 184I. Not repeatable for credit with American Studies 178AC or American Studies 179AC. If student is enrolled in 170AC then they will receive no credit if they enroll separately and coterminously in 184I, 181B, or 180D.</p><p><strong>Requirements this course satisfies:</strong> Satisfies the American Cultures requirement</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 3 weeks - 15 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week for three weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Race and Representation in US Culture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc171" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc171">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C171</span> 
<span class="title">The American Designed Landscape Since 1850</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc171">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course surveys the history of American landscape architecture since 1850 in four realms: 1) urban open spaces--that is squares, plazas, parks, and recreation systems; 2) urban and suburban design; 3) regional and environmental planning; 4) gardens. The course will review the cultural and social contexts which have shaped and informed landscape architecture in the United States since the advent of the public parks movement, as well as, the</span><span class="deschide"> aesthetic precepts, environmental concerns, horticultural practices, and technological innovations of American landscapes. Students will complete a midterm, final, and a research assignment.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The American Designed Landscape Since 1850:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="100" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Mozingo</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> LD ARCH C171</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The American Designed Landscape Since 1850:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc172" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc172">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C172</span> 
<span class="title">History of American Business</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc172">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Spring 2019<br/>
This course will examine selected aspects of the history of American business. Included will be discussions of the evolution of the large corporation, the development of modern managerial techniques, and the changing relationship of business, government, and labor.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>History of American Business:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="266" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Rosen</p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> American Studies C172, Business Administration C172</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> UGBA C172</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>History of American Business:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdc174" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdc174">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD C174</span> 
<span class="title">Visual Autobiography</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdc174">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2008, Fall 2007, Fall 2003, Spring 2002<br/>
Since visual and literary studies have historically been viewed as separate disciplines, we will use theories from both to study those forms of self-representation that defy disciplinary boundaries, or what we call &quot;visual autobiography.&quot; The course aims to help students become conversant with the elements of alphabetic literacy (reading and writing) and visual literacy (observing and making) in order to develop a third distinctive</span><span class="deschide"> textual/visual literacy.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Visual Autobiography:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="905" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Six hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> ENGLISH C143V/UGIS C135/VIS STD C185A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Visual Autobiography:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd178ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd178ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 178AC</span> 
<span class="title">Race and Ethnicity in American Culture: Film, Music, and Advertising</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd178ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2009 10 Week Session, Summer 2009 3 Week Session<br/>
This course will examine the politics of racial representation and expression in popular music as well as film and advertising. This course combines 180C, 184I, and 188F.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Race and Ethnicity in American Culture: Film, Music, and Advertising:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="663" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 178AC">AMERSTD 178AC</span> after passing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 179AC">AMERSTD 179AC</span>, AMERSTD 180C, AMERSTD 184I, and AMERSTD 188F.</p><p><strong>Requirements this course satisfies:</strong> Satisfies the American Cultures requirement</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 3 weeks - 15 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture/discussion per week for three weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Race and Ethnicity in American Culture: Film, Music, and Advertising:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd179ac" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd179ac">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 179AC</span> 
<span class="title">Representing Race and Ethnicity in American Culture</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd179ac">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 2008 10 Week Session, Summer 2008 3 Week Session<br/>
This course offers students a unified course experience that examines the politics of visual representation and ways of &quot;seeing&quot; race and ethnicity in the U.S. in a comparative way. This course satisfies the American Cultures requirement by combining the following 1-unit courses: American Studies 180C - The Politics of Adverstising in the United States: Race, Ethnicity, and Representation; American Studies 181B</span><span class="deschide"> - Writing Narratives of Race and Gender: Photography and Art;and American Studies 184I - Race and American Film.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Representing Race and Ethnicity in American Culture:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="722" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit or partial credit for 179AC after taking 180C, 181B, or 184I.</p><p><strong>Requirements this course satisfies:</strong> Satisfies the American Cultures requirement</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 3 weeks - 15 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Fifteen hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week for three weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Representing Race and Ethnicity in American Culture:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd189" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd189">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 189</span> 
<span class="title">Research and Writing in American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd189">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2020<br/>
This course is designed to encourage research skills, critical thinking, and effective writing. An intensive reading and research seminar, the course will assist students in the development of skills fundamental to advanced research in the humanities, social sciences, and cultural studies. In addition to examining some topics in current American studies scholarship, students will conduct semester-long research projects. The effort entails identification</span><span class="deschide"> of research topics, cultivation of interdisciplinary methodologies, compilation of annotated bibliographies, and completion of a literature review, which may serve as the first portion of the American studies senior thesis. The course is strongly recommended for those who have been out of touch with the conventions of academic research and writing or who might wish to pursue a graduate degree in the future.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research and Writing in American Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="260" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Intended for American studies majors</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Three hour of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam not required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research and Writing in American Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd190" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd190">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 190</span> 
<span class="title">Senior Thesis</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd190">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Summer 2021 Second 6 Week Session, Spring 2021, Fall 2020<br/>
All American Studies majors must satisfy the senior thesis requirement. Three options are available:AS 190-Senior Thesis, AS 191-Senior Seminar, or students may (with prior Faculty Advisor approval) enroll in an upper division seminar appropriate to their concentration for which they write a substantial research paper. Students planning to enroll in AS 190 must complete the &quot;Thesis Proposal/Adviser Agreement&quot;</span><span class="deschide"> (available in the departmental office) prior to the semester in which the thesis is written.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Senior Thesis:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="666" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 190">AMERSTD 190</span> after completing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 191">AMERSTD 191</span>. A deficient grade in <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 190">AMERSTD 190</span> may be removed by taking <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AMERSTD 191">AMERSTD 191</span>.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 10 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four hours of independent study per week. Ten hours of independent study per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Senior Thesis:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd191" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd191">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 191</span> 
<span class="title">Senior Thesis Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd191">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Students will meet in seminar and will be required to write individual research papers based on the general themes or issues of the seminar. The particular themes/issues will be outlined on the American Studies Course List provided each semester by the American Studies office.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Senior Thesis Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="821" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Declared majors with senior standing</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Senior Thesis Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstdh195" data-toggle="#cb_amerstdh195">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD H195</span> 
<span class="title">Senior Honors Thesis Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstdh195">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
This is a required course for students wishing to graduate with honors in American studies. Entails writing a bachelor's thesis pertaining to the student's individual area of concentration within the American studies major. The completed thesis will be read by the thesis supervisor and one other faculty member.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Senior Honors Thesis Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="788" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Senior-standing major in American studies; completion of 101 and 102, 3.51 overall GPA, and 3.65 GPA for classes in the major</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Senior Honors Thesis Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd198" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd198">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 198</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Group Study for Advanced Undergraduates</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd198">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2021, Fall 2013<br/>
Seminars for the group study of selected topics not covered by regularly scheduled courses. Topics will vary from semester to semester. Students must have completed 60 units in order to be eligible to enroll.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Directed Group Study for Advanced Undergraduates:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="233" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Regulations set by College of Letters and Science</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Enrollment is restricted; see the section on Academic Policies-Course Number Guide in the Berkeley Bulletin.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of directed group study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Four hour of Directed group study per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Offered for pass/not pass grade only. Final exam not required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Directed Group Study for Advanced Undergraduates:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_amerstd199" data-toggle="#cb_amerstd199">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">AMERSTD 199</span> 
<span class="title">Supervised Independent Study and Research for Upper Division Majors</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_amerstd199">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Summer 2021 Second 6 Week Session<br/>
Directed individual study on special topics approved by an American studies faculty member. Enrollment restrictions apply; see the Introduction to Courses and Curricula section of this catalog.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Supervised Independent Study and Research for Upper Division Majors:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="504" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Enrollment is restricted; see the section on Academic Policies-Course Number Guide in the Berkeley Bulletin.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> individual conferences</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> American Studies/Undergraduate</p><p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Offered for pass/not pass grade only. Final exam not required. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Supervised Independent Study and Research for Upper Division Majors:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Alexander Benjamin, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>Technology, representation, landscape, urban renewal, city planning, transportation technologies and photography.<br/><a href="https://as.ugis.berkeley.edu/people/alexander-benjamin- craghead/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Cohen, <i>Associate Teaching Professor</i>. </strong>African American Studies/American Studies.<br/><a href="https://africam.berkeley.edu/people/michael-cohen/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sarah Gold McBride, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>Social and cultural history of the nineteenth-century United States, ordinary life and culture in the 19th century United States with a focus on race, gender, popular culture, material culture, popular science, popular media, and the body. .<br/><a href="https://as.ugis.berkeley.edu/people/auto-draft-2/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christine Palmer, <i>Associate Director and Lecturer</i>. </strong>20th century mass culture, folklore, race, literature, film, and cultural memory.<br/><a href="https://as.ugis.berkeley.edu/people/christine-palmer/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andrew Shanken, <i>Director and Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture/American Studies. Architecture Memory, visionary architecture, the unbuilt, paper architecture, heritage conservation, architectural representation, urban representation, diagrams, history of professions, historiography, world's fairs, expositions, California architecture, themed environments.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15666"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Affiliated Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Charles L. Briggs, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Anthropology  Linguistic and medical anthropology, social theory, modernity, citizenship and the state, race, and violence.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/charles-briggs"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mark Brilliant, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>History/American Studies 20th century US history, with a focus on political economy, civil rights, education, law, and the west.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16919"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Raul Coronado, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Ethnic Studies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/raul-coronado"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Margaret L. Crawford, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Architecture  Everyday urbanism, evolution, uses and meanings of urban space and therapid physical and social changes on villages in Chinaâ€™s Pearl River Delta .</p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Kathleen Donegan, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>English  Colonial America, early America, Native America, early Caribbean.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14551"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Chimuya Elliot, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>African American Studies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/chiyuma-elliott"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter Glazer, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Theater.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/peter-glazer"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marcial Gonzalez, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>English  Chicano and Chicana literature, twentieth-century American ethnic literatures, theory of the novel, marxism, critical theory, farm worker social movements.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dorothy J. Hale, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English  English literature, American literature, the novel, narrative theory, critical theory, Henry James, William Faulkner, the modern novel of consciousness.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14774"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Henkin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>History  US History, urban history, cultural history, History of Time.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/david-henkin"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Shari Huhndorf, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Native American Studies  Interdisciplinary Native American studies, cultural studies, gender studies, American studies, literary and visual culture.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14886"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard Hutson, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>English .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14877"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jake Kosek, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Geography.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lauren Kroiz, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Art History  History and theory of photography and new media, race and ethnic studies, the relationships between regionalism, nationalism and globalism.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michel Laguerre, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>African American Studies  Globalization, information technology, urban studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14945"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Margaretta M. Lovell, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Art History  Architecture, design, American art.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15324"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Waldo E. Martin, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>History  African American History, Modern American Culture.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16791"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David H. Miller, <i>Assistant Professor of Practice</i>. </strong>Music.<br/><a href="https://music.berkeley.edu/people/david-h-miller"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Louise A. Mozingo, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Environmental Design.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Samuel Otter, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English  African American literature, 19th century American literature, 17th and 18th century American literature, Herman Melville, race in American culture, literature and history, discourse and ideology, close reading.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15206"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Genaro M. Padilla, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English  American literature, Chicano/Latino literary and cultural studies, American autobiography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15213"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Beth Piatote, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Native American Studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15378"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leigh Raiford, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>African American Studies  Social movements, visual culture, memory, photography, African American history and culture.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15389"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Juana Maria Rodriguez, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ethnic Studies.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christine Rosen, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Business  History of business and the environment, business history, green chemistry, sustainable business strategies.<br/><a href="http://facultybio.haas.berkeley.edu/faculty-list/rosen-christine/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Caitlin Rosenthal, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>History. American capitalism, economic history, slavery.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/caitlin-rosenthal"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alex M. Saragoza, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Ethnic Studies  Ideology, modern Mexico, Latin American history, structural origins of Mexican migration, cultural formations in Mexico, Mexican cinema, radio, television.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15305"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Scott Andrew Saul, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English  African American studies, 20th century American literature and culture, performance studies, jazz studies, histories of the avante-garde.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15308"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Susan Schweik, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>English  Feminist theory, cultural studies, American poetry, disability studies, 20th-century poetry, literature and politics, war literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15427"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Shannon Steen, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Theater Studies.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bryan Wagner, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>English  Critical theory, African American literature, historiography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15699"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hertha D. Sweet Wong, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chair, Art Practice, English  American literature, native American literature, autobiography, ethnic American literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15630"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Donald McQuade, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>English, Advertising, 20th century American literature and culture, theory and practice of non-fiction, literature and popular culture, the American Renaissance, the essay as literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15104"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kathleen S. Moran, <i>Lecturer Emerita</i>. </strong>Consumerism and American popular culture, 19th and 20th century American political thought.<br/><a href="https://as.ugis.berkeley.edu/people/kathleen-moran/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

