<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">At Berkeley, graduate work in chemical and biomolecular engineering emphasizes the excitement of original research in frontier areas of applied science. <span class="s1">Graduate students may pursue a PhD in Chemical Engineering, or they may apply to the Product Development concentration to obtain an MS in Chemical Engineering</span>. While formal courses are necessary to provide scientific fundamentals and intellectual breadth, the primary characteristic of Berkeley's graduate experience is to participate in the quest for new knowledge. Graduate students and faculty collaborate as partners in scholarship, in learning, and in intellectual discovery.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Master's Program</h3>
<h3>Professional Degree in Product Development Program (MS)</h3>
<p class="Normal1">The PDP is a graduate-level degree program whose central aim is to fill the unmet need at national and international levels for graduates of chemical engineering and related disciplines who have knowledge and field experience in the complex process of transforming technical innovations into commercially successful products. In the space of one calendar year, PDP graduates will gain exposure to real-world product development practices in a range of chemical process-intensive industries including biotechnology, microelectronics, nanoscience, and consumer products (concentrations within the program). The PDP does not require a research thesis, but students will find completing the extensive coursework and field study assignment challenging. By combining elements of advanced technical knowledge with focused business-related training, the PDP aims to fill a specific niche in the “choice space” of graduate education options for engineering graduates.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">M.S. in Chemical Engineering</h3>
<p>Focusing on Chemical Engineering core courses and higher division electives this highly competitive program will test students on a) transport phenomena; b) kinetics and chemical fundamentals; and c) thermodynamics at the end of the first semester.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">PhD Program</h3>
<p class="Normal1">The PhD program is designed to enlarge the body of knowledge of the student and, more importantly, to discover and develop talent for original, productive, and creative work in chemical and biomolecular engineering. Breadth of knowledge and professional training are achieved through advanced course work. To develop the creative talents of the student, a paramount emphasis in the PhD program is placed on intensive research, a project on which students work closely with one or more members of the faculty.</p>
<p class="Normal1">PhD students may choose to add a designated emphasis (DE) to their program. A designated emphasis is a specialization, such as a new method of inquiry or an important field of application, which is relevant to two or more existing doctoral degree programs. Designated emphases open to students in this PhD program include Nanoscale Science and Engineering (NSE), Energy Sciences and Technology (DEEST), Communication, Computation and Statistics, Computational and Genomic Biology, and New Media.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1"><strong>M.S. in Bioprocess Engineering</strong></h3>
<p>The <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/bioprocess-engineering/">Master of Bioprocess Engineering (MBPE) </a>program is designed to provide students with a unique opportunity to integrate classroom fundamentals, hands-on laboratory applications, and heavy interaction with a range of biotechnology companies spanning the biopharmaceutical, industrial biotech, and food tech industries.&quot;</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the Program</h3>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Admission is granted by the University's Graduate Division on the recommendation of the department. Applicants generally are required to provide the following: evidence of superior performance in the last two years of undergraduate studies; test scores for the aptitude portion of the Graduate Record Examination (the advanced GRE or subject test is not required); and three letters of recommendation from professors or colleagues familiar with the applicant's academic and professional aptitudes. International students whose native language is not English must provide evidence of English language proficiency. The weight of evidence from all sources determines admission. Students do not need a master's degree to apply for a doctoral degree. Most applicants will have completed a typical undergraduate program in chemical engineering. However, admission may be granted to students with undergraduate degrees in a related discipline. In this case, necessary background courses in chemical engineering are taken as part of the program for the first year.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext name="Doctoral Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h4 class="Normal1">Curriculum</h4>
<p>A total of 18 units of letter-graded graduate courses must be taken during residence in the graduate program. In the first semester, a minimum of 9 units must be obtained from the core chemical engineering courses in the areas of mathematics, thermodynamics, reaction engineering, and transport phenomena. In addition, students are required to take the <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 375">CHM ENG 375</span></span> pedagogy course and two semesters in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 300">CHM ENG 300</span></span>. Students should be registered full time with a minimum of 12 units. These include CHM ENG 299 and colloquium series CHM ENG 298.</p>
<p>Additional units must be obtained from graduate level or upper division elective courses so that the total number of units taken is 18. Students  may take classes in other departments such as Engineering, Physics, Chemistry, etc. They are strongly encouraged to pursue additional courses of specific relevance to their thesis research and to explore other areas of technical, professional, or personal interest. </p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">9 units: Chemical Engineering graduate core courses</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 230">CHM ENG 230</span></td><td>Mathematical Methods in Chemical Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 240">CHM ENG 240</span></td><td>Thermodynamics for Chemical Product and Process Design</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 244">CHM ENG 244</span></td><td>Kinetics and Reaction Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 245">CHM ENG 245</span></td><td>Catalysis</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 250">CHM ENG 250</span></td><td>Transport Processes</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 274">CHM ENG 274</span></td><td>Biomolecular Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">9-12 units: Graduate or upper division electives</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"/><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<mastersdegreerequirementstext name="Master's Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Professional Master's with Product Development Concentration</h3>
<p>The Master's PDP program places equal emphasis on advanced course work in new product development principles, specific industry practices, and the field study assignment. Successful completion of each of these elements is a prerequisite to graduation. The specific courses taken in the PDP program are selected in consultations between the student, the PDP executive director, and a faculty adviser. Upon entrance to the program, students will be required to declare an industry area specialization so that an appropriate academic schedule can be constructed. Students must complete a minimum of 28 units with at least 18 of those units from letter-graded courses which include a minimum of 12 units in graduate-level (i.e., 200 series) courses.</p>
<p>Specific coursework to pursue an industry track will vary based on the individual student's interests and the availability of course offerings in a given year.</p>
<p>For examples of representative curricula for each industry track, please visit:</p>
<p><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/grad/cbe/pdp/graduation-requirements">http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/grad/cbe/pdp/graduation-requirements</a></p>
<h3>M.S. in Chemical Engineering</h3>
<p>Highly competitive admission and program. Students have to complete a total of 24 semester units are required for the MS. Of the 24 units, Academic Senate regulations state that a <em>minimum</em> of 12 units must be in 200-level courses in Chemical Engineering (230, 240, 244, 250 and 274). Additional 12 units in upper division/graduate courses electives as approved by our Graduate Advisor and 6 units in 298 and 299.</p>
<p>There is a comprehensive exam given by at least 2 Senate faculty testing on a) transport phenomena; b) kinetics and chemical fundamentals; and c) thermodynamics at the end of the first semester. Time for completion of the degree is 2 semesters.</p>
]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng230" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng230">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 230</span> 
<span class="title">Mathematical Methods in Chemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng230">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Fall 2018<br/>
The course aims to introduce a variety of mathematical and computational methods useful in solving research problems pertaining to chemical and biomolecular systems. The course covers a wide range of topics from linear algebra and matrices, differential equations, and stochastic methods. Even though the focus is primarily on analytical methods, most of the concepts will be demonstrated with computations and applications. The goal of the course</span><span class="deschide"> is to ensure that the students are aware of a wide range of computational methods that can be useful in their research and to provide the students with sufficient background in applied mathematics that can be useful in reading the science and engineering literature.<br/></span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Mathematical Methods in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="931" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Math 53 and 54 or equivalent; open to seniors with consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Mathematical Methods in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng236" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng236">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 236</span> 
<span class="title">Physics-Inspired Machine Learning</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng236">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Machine learning in the context of scientific problems is an exciting emerging area of research, and often requires the development of new methods that can incorporate and exploit the inductive biases and structure needed for such problems. There are also now numerous examples of concepts in physics historically influencing machine learning methods development more broadly. This course will give an overview of different physics-inspired machine learning methods</span><span class="deschide">, and the connections between concepts in physics (numerical methods, dynamical systems, symmetries, conservation laws) and machine learning.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Physics-Inspired Machine Learning:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="178" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Physics-Inspired Machine Learning:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng240" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng240">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 240</span> 
<span class="title">Thermodynamics for Chemical Product and Process Design</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng240">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Topics covered include molecular thermodynamics of pure substances and mixtures, interfacial thermodynamics, statistical mechanics, and computer simulations.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Thermodynamics for Chemical Product and Process Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="747" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Math 53 and 54 or equivalent; 141 or equivalent; open to seniors with consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Thermodynamics for Chemical Product and Process Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng244" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng244">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 244</span> 
<span class="title">Kinetics and Reaction Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng244">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Molecular processes in chemical systems, kinetics and catalysis. Interaction of mass and heat transfer in chemical processes. Performance of systems with chemical reactors.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Kinetics and Reaction Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="967" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 142 or equivalent; open to seniors with consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Kinetics and Reaction Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng245" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng245">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 245</span> 
<span class="title">Catalysis</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng245">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2020, Spring 2019, Spring 2018<br/>
Adsorption and kinetics of surface reactions; catalyst preparation and characterization; poisoning, selectivity, and empirical activity patterns in catalysis; surface chemistry, catalytic mechanisms and modern experimental techniques in catalytic research; descriptive examples of industrial catalytic systems.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Catalysis:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="601" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 244 or Chemistry 223, or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Catalysis:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng246" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng246">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 246</span> 
<span class="title">Principles of Electrochemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng246">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2012, Fall 2010, Fall 2009<br/>
Electrode processes in electrolysis and in galvanic cells. Charge and mass transfer in ionic media. Criteria of scale-up.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Principles of Electrochemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="598" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Principles of Electrochemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng248" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng248">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 248</span> 
<span class="title">Applied Surface and Colloid Chemistry</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng248">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2020, Spring 2014<br/>
Principles of surface and colloid chemistry with current applications; surface thermodynamics, wetting, adsorption from solution, disperse systems, association colloids, interacting electrical double layers and colloid stability, kinetics of coagulation, and electrokinetics.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Applied Surface and Colloid Chemistry:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="857" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Applied Surface and Colloid Chemistry:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng250" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng250">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 250</span> 
<span class="title">Transport Processes</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng250">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Basic differential relations of mass, momentum, and energy including creeping, laminar, and turbulent flow, boundary layers, convective-diffusion in heat and mass transfer, and simultaneous multicomponent mass and energy transport. Analytic mathematical solution of the equations of change using classical techniques including: separation of variables, similarity solutions, and Laplace and Fourier transforms.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Transport Processes:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="789" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering 150A, 150B; Mathematics 53 and 54, or equivalent; open to seniors with consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Transport Processes:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng256" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng256">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 256</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Transport Phenomena</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng256">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2020, Fall 2018, Fall 2016<br/>
Formulation and rigorous analysis of the laws governing the transport of momentum, heat, and mass, with special emphasis on chemical engineering applications. Detailed investigation of laminar flows complemented by treatments of turbulent flow systems and hydrodynamic stability.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Transport Phenomena:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="679" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 230</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Transport Phenomena:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmengc268" data-toggle="#cb_chmengc268">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG C268</span> 
<span class="title">Physicochemical Hydrodynamics</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmengc268">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow ">Terms offered: Spring 2017, Fall 2013, Fall 2011, Spring 2011<br/>
An introduction to the hydrodynamics of capillarity and wetting. Balance laws and short-range forces. Dimensionless numbers, scaling and lubrication approximation. Rayleigh instability. Marangoni effect. The moving contact line. Wetting and short-range forces. The dynamic contact angle. Dewetting. Coating flows. Effect of surfactants and electric fields. Wetting of rough or porous surfaces. Contact angles for evaporating systems</span><span class="deschide">.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Physicochemical Hydrodynamics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="237" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> A first graduate course in fluid mechanics sucs as 260A-260B</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Morris</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> MEC ENG C268</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Physicochemical Hydrodynamics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmengc270" data-toggle="#cb_chmengc270">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG C270</span> 
<span class="title">Protein Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmengc270">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2015, Fall 2014, Fall 2010<br/>
An in-depth study of the current methods used to design and engineer proteins. Emphasis on how strategies can be applied in the laboratory. Relevant case studies presented to illustrate method variations and applications. Intended for graduate students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Protein Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="274" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Tullman-Ercek</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BIO ENG C219</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Protein Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng274" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng274">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 274</span> 
<span class="title">Biomolecular Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng274">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Fundamentals in biomolecular engineering. Structures, dynamics, and functions of biomolecules. Molecular tools in biotechnology. Metabolic and signaling networks in cellular engineering. Synthetic biology and biomedical engineering applications.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Biomolecular Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="682" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Biomolecular Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng275" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng275">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 275</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Bioprocess Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng275">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This course is designed for students interested in obtaining advanced training in bioprocess engineering for applications in the biopharmaceutical, industrial biotech, and food tech industries. Emphasis will be placed on integrated application of quality by design (QbD) framework, good manufacturing practice (GMP), statistical experimental design, and other advanced concepts addressing current industry needs.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Bioprocess Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="906" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> CHMENG 170A, CHMENG 170B concurrent (or consent of instructor)</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Bioprocess Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng275l" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng275l">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 275L</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Bioprocess Engineering Laboratory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng275l">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This pilot-scale laboratory course is designed for students interested in obtaining advanced training in bioprocess engineering for applications in the biopharmaceutical, industrial biotech, and food tech industries. Featured equipment (and experiments) include: Sartorius ambr250 (design of experiments), ABEC 300L bioreactor (fermentation), Alfa Laval disc stack centrifuge (liquid-solid separation), Alfa Laval M20 filtration skid (tangential</span><span class="deschide"> flow filtration), and GE ÄKTA Avant chromatography unit (protein purification).</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Bioprocess Engineering Laboratory:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="747" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> CHMENG 170A, CHMENG C170L, CHMENG 170B concurrent (or consent of instructor)</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 8 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Eight hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Bioprocess Engineering Laboratory:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng293c" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng293c">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 293C</span> 
<span class="title">Curricular Practical Training Internship</span> 
<span class="hours">0.0 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng293c">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This is an independent study course for international students doing internships under the Curricular Practical Training program.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Curricular Practical Training Internship:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="744" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Zero hour of independent study per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Curricular Practical Training Internship:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmengc294a" data-toggle="#cb_chmengc294a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG C294A</span> 
<span class="title">Mechanics and Physics of Lipid Bilayers</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmengc294a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2017<br/>
Lipid bilayers constitute the membrane that encloses every animal cell and many of its interior structures, including the nuclear envelope, the organelles and the endoplasmic reticulum. This is a unique course devoted to modern developments in this exceptionally active field of research, ranging from models based on continuum theory to recent developments based on statistical mechanics.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Mechanics and Physics of Lipid Bilayers:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="518" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Student Learning Outcomes:</strong> To expose students to advanced current work on the mechanics and physics of lipid bilayers (a very active field of current research relevant to biomechanics and biophysics)</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Mechanical Engineering 185 or equivalent</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Steigmann</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> MEC ENG C285E</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Mechanics and Physics of Lipid Bilayers:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng295b" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng295b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 295B</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Electrochemical, Hydrodynamic, and Interfacial Phenomena</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng295b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2011, Spring 2011, Fall 2010<br/>
Current and advanced study in chemical engineering, primarily for advanced graduate students.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Electrochemical, Hydrodynamic, and Interfacial Phenomena:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="342" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Open to properly qualified graduate students</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Electrochemical, Hydrodynamic, and Interfacial Phenomena:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng295k" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng295k">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 295K</span> 
<span class="title">Design of Functional Interfaces</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng295k">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2011, Spring 2005, Fall 2004<br/>
This course introduces students to the concepts and techniques involved in the design and physical characterization of advanced functional materials consisting of well-defined interfaces. Throughout the course, principles of supramolecular chemistry on solid surfaces are applied to functional systems. Materials with different connectivity and structure at the active site are compared for development of understanding. Specific topics include</span><span class="deschide"> catalysis, separations, encapsulation, and biomedicine.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Design of Functional Interfaces:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="196" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Katz</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Design of Functional Interfaces:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng295n" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng295n">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 295N</span> 
<span class="title">Polymer Physics</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng295n">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2015, Spring 2010, Spring 2008<br/>
This course, which is based on Gert Strobl's book addresses the origin of some of the important physical properties of polymer liquids and solids. This includes phase transitions, crystallization, morphology of multiphase polymer systems, mechanical properties, response to mechanical and electric fields, and fracture. When possible, we will develop quantitative molecular models that predict macroscopic behavior. The course will address experimental</span><span class="deschide"> data obtained by microscopy, light and neutron scattering, rheology, and dielectric relaxation.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Polymer Physics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="390" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 230 and 240</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Polymer Physics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng295p" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng295p">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 295P</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Introduction to New Product Development</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng295p">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course is part of the product development initative sponsored by the department of chemical engineering. It focuses on real-life practices and challenges of translating scientific discovery into commercial products. Its scope is limited in most circumstances to situations where some knowledge of chemical engineering, chemistry, and related disciplines might prove to be particularly useful. The course primarily uses case studies of real-world</span><span class="deschide"> new product development situations to simulate the managerial and technical challenges that will confront students in the field. We will cover a wide range of topics including basic financial, strategic and intellectual property concepts for products, managing risk and uncertainity, the effective new product development team, the evolving role of corporate R&amp;D, the new venture product company and the ethics of post-launch product management.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Introduction to New Product Development:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="45" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Alexander</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Introduction to New Product Development:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng295q" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng295q">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 295Q</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Advanced Topics in New Product Development</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng295q">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
This course is a part of the product development initiative sponsored by the department of chemical engineering. The course builds on the coverage in 295P of real-life practices of translating scientific discovery into commercial products. We will cover a wide range of advanced product development concepts including technology road maps, decision analysis, six sigma, product portfolio optimization, and best practices for field project ma</span><span class="deschide">nagement.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Advanced Topics in New Product Development:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="676" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor. 295P recommended</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Alexander</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Topics in Chemical Engineering: Advanced Topics in New Product Development:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng295t" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng295t">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 295T</span> 
<span class="title">Hard-Technology Innovation: Proof-of-Commercial Value Method</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng295t">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This course is part of the Product Development Program initiative sponsored by the Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering. The course builds on the coverage in Chemical Engineering 295P of real-life practices of translating scientific discovery into commercial products. In this course, we will cover a new risk-reduction methodology for bringing to market complex technical inventions that initially have a high risk profile that discourages investment</span><span class="deschide"> for commercialization. The central learning objective in this course is: How might we utilize a new approach that would enable university-affiliated hard-tech innovators to sufficiently de-risk their venture propositions so that they become “fundable” by investors?<br/></span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Hard-Technology Innovation: Proof-of-Commercial Value Method:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="398" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Instructor approval needed</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Alexander, Joshi, Sciamanna</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Hard-Technology Innovation: Proof-of-Commercial Value Method:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmengc295a" data-toggle="#cb_chmengc295a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG C295A</span> 
<span class="title">The Berkeley Lectures on Energy: Energy from Biomass</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmengc295a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2015, Fall 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
After an introduction to the different aspects of our global energy consumption, the course will focus on the role of biomass. The course will illustrate how the global scale of energy guides the biomass research. Emphasis will be places on the integration of the biological aspects (crop selection, harvesting, storage, and distribution, and chemical composition of biomass) with the chemical aspects to convert biomass to energy. The course aims</span><span class="deschide"> to engage students in state-of-art research.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Berkeley Lectures on Energy: Energy from Biomass:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="364" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Biology 1A; Chemistry 1B or 4B, Mathematics 1B</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit under special circumstances: Repeatable when topic changes with consent of instructor.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Bell, Blanch, Clark, Smit, C. Somerville</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BIO ENG C281/CHEM C238/PLANTBI C224</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Berkeley Lectures on Energy: Energy from Biomass:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmengc295l" data-toggle="#cb_chmengc295l">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG C295L</span> 
<span class="title">Implications and Applications of Synthetic Biology</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmengc295l">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2007<br/>
Explore strategies for maximizing the economic and societal benefits of synthetic biology and minimizing the risks; create &quot;seedlings&quot; for future research projects in synthetic biology at UC Berkeley; increase multidisciplinary collaborations at UC Berkeley on synthetic biology; and introduce students to a wide perspective of SB projects and innovators as well as policy, legal, and ethical experts.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Implications and Applications of Synthetic Biology:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="230" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Arkin, Keasling</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BIO ENG C230</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Implications and Applications of Synthetic Biology:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmengc295r" data-toggle="#cb_chmengc295r">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG C295R</span> 
<span class="title">Applied Spectroscopy</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmengc295r">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2009, Spring 2007, Spring 2002<br/>
After a brief review of quantum mechanics and semi-classical theories for the interaction of radiation with matter, this course will survey the various spectroscopies associated with the electromagnetic spectrum, from gamma rays to radio waves. Special emphasis is placed on application to research problems in applied and engineering sciences. Graduate researchers interested in systematic in situ process characterization, analysis, or discovery</span><span class="deschide"> are best served by this course.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Applied Spectroscopy:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="242" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in engineering, physics, chemistry, or chemical engineering; courses: quantum mechanics, linear vector space theory</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Reimer</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> AST C295R</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Applied Spectroscopy:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmengc295z" data-toggle="#cb_chmengc295z">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG C295Z</span> 
<span class="title">Energy Solutions: Carbon Capture and Sequestration</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmengc295z">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2015, Spring 2014, Spring 2013<br/>
After a brief overview of the chemistry of carbon dioxide in the land, ocean, and atmosphere, the course will survey the capture and sequestration of CO2 from anthropogenic sources. Emphasis will be placed on the integration of materials synthesis and unit operation design, including the chemistry and engineering aspects of sequestration. The course primarily addresses scientific and engineering challenges and aims</span><span class="deschide"> to engage students in state-of-the-art research in global energy challenges.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Energy Solutions: Carbon Capture and Sequestration:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="543" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Chemistry 4B or 1B, Mathematics 1B, and Physics 7B, or equivalents</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Bourg, DePaolo, Long, Reimer, Smit</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> CHEM C236/EPS C295Z</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Energy Solutions: Carbon Capture and Sequestration:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng296" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng296">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 296</span> 
<span class="title">Special Study for Graduate Students in Chemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 6 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng296">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2016, Fall 2015, Spring 2015<br/>
Special laboratory and theoretical studies.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Special Study for Graduate Students in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="733" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Individual conferences.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> The grading option will be decided by the instructor when the class is offered. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Special Study for Graduate Students in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng298" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng298">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 298</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Chemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng298">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Lectures, reports, and discussions on current research in chemical engineering. Sections are operated independently and directed toward different topics.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Seminar in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="62" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Open to properly qualified graduate students with consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Seminar in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng298b" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng298b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 298B</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Bioprocess Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng298b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Weekly seminar with industry partners invited to give presentations on bio-based research, technologies, equipment, processes, and/or products. Provides an interactive interface for students and the bioprocess industry. Offered Fall and Spring semesters.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Seminar in Bioprocess Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="47" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> CBE 170A and CBE 170B (can be taken concurrently)</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One and one-half hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Seminar in Bioprocess Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng298c" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng298c">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 298C</span> 
<span class="title">Colloquium in Chemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng298c">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Lectures, reports, and discussions on current research in chemical engineering.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Colloquium in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="778" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Open to properly qualified graduate students with consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of colloquium per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two to three hours of colloquium per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Colloquium in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng299" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 299</span> 
<span class="title">Research in Chemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Research.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Research in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="756" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 2.5-30 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1.5-22.5 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>10 weeks - 1.5-18 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Individual conferences.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Research in Chemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng300" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng300">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 300</span> 
<span class="title">Professional Preparation: Supervised Teaching of Chemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng300">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2020, Spring 2019, Spring 2016<br/>
Discussion, problem review and development, guidance of large scale laboratory experiments, course development, supervised practice teaching.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Professional Preparation: Supervised Teaching of Chemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="389" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing, appointment as a Graduate Student Instructor, or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Individual conferences and participation in teaching activities.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Professional Preparation: Supervised Teaching of Chemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng375" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng375">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 375</span> 
<span class="title">Professional Preparation: Supervised Teaching of Chemical Engineering</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng375">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2020, Fall 2019, Fall 2018<br/>
Discussion, problem review and development, guidance of large scale laboratory experiments, course development, supervised practice teaching.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Professional Preparation: Supervised Teaching of Chemical Engineering:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="564" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing, appointment as a Graduate Student Instructor, or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Zero hours of independent study per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Professional Preparation: Supervised Teaching of Chemical Engineering:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_chmeng602" data-toggle="#cb_chmeng602">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">CHM ENG 602</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Studies for Graduate Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_chmeng602">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2019, Spring 2019, Fall 2018<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required of candidates for the Ph.D.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Studies for Graduate Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="298" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in Ph.D. program</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Course does not satisfy unit or residence requirements for doctoral degree.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Individual conferences.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Chemical &amp; Biomolecular Engineering/Graduate examination preparation</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Studies for Graduate Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Keith Alexander, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>New Product Development, Technology Commercialization.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nitash P. Balsara, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical engineering, synthesis and characterization of soft microstructured polymer materials, nucleation, neutron scattering, depolarized light scattering.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/nitash-p-balsara"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alexis T. Bell, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Understanding the fundamental relationships between the structure and composition of heterogeneous catalysts and their performance .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/alexis-t-bell"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Elton J. Cairns, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Electrochemistry and electrocatalysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/elton-j-cairns"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Carlo Carraro, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Douglas S. Clark, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biochemical engineering and biocatalysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/douglas-clark"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David B. Graves, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plasma processing and electronic materials.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/david-b-graves"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Teresa Head-Gordon, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational chemistry, biophysics, bioengineering, biomolecules, materials, computational science.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14816"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Enrique Iglesia, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical engineering, catalytic materials, heterogeneous catalysis, chemical reaction engineering, methane and biomass coversion processes, refining processes, hydrogen generation, alkane activation deoxygenatiion and desulfurization catalysis, zeolites.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/enrique-iglesia"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alexander Katz, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical engineering, nanoengineering, catalytic imprinted silicas, catalysts in biological systems, catalysis, chemical sensing.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/alexander-katz"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jay Keasling, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microorganism metabolic engineering for environmentally friendly product   .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jay-d-keasling"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sanjay Kumar, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biomaterials, molecular and cellular bioengineering, stem cells, cancer biology, translational medicine.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sanjay-kumar"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Markita Landry, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Nanomaterials, single-molecule fluorescence microscopy, biophysics.<br/><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/landry"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jeffrey R. Long, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Inorganic and solid state chemistry, synthesis of inorganic clusters and solids, controlling structure, tailoring physical properties, intermetal bridges, high-spin metal-cyanide clusters, magnetic bistability.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15072"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Roya Maboudian, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Surface and interfacial science and engineering, thin-film science and technology, micro-/nano-systems technology, harsh-environment sensors, silicon carbide, biologically-inspired materials synthesis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/roya-maboudian"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Brian Maiorella, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kranthi K. Mandadapu, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical Mechanics, Continuum Mechanics â€” Polycrystalline Materials, Biological Membranes, Bacterial Motility.<br/><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/mandadapu"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bryan D. McCloskey, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Electrochemical energy storage, electrocatalysis, molecular and ionic transport through polymers .<br/><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/mccloskey"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ali Mesbah, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Process Systems and Control.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/ali-mesbah"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Susan J. Muller, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical engineering, fluid mechanics, Rheology, complex fluids, microfabrication processes, Genetic Engineering of Protein Polymers, Finite Element Modeling of Bubbles, Stress Fluids, Taylor-Couette instabilities.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/susan-j-muller"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John M. Prausnitz, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular thermodynamics of phase equilibria.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/john-m-prausnitz"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Clayton J. Radke, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Surface and colloid science technology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/clayton-j-radke"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Jeffrey A. Reimer, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Materials chemistry, applied spectroscopy, alternative energy, nuclear spintronics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jeffrey-reimer"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Schaffer, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Neuroscience, biomolecular engineering, bioengineering, stem cell biology, gene therapy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15415"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Karthik Shekhar, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Cellular and systems biology, statistical inference, single-cell genomics.<br/><a href="https://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/shekhar"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Berend Smit, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular simulations, multi-scale modeling, catalysts, soft-condensed matter, biological membranes, clays.<br/><a href="http://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/smit"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rui Wang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Theoretical Polymer and Soft Materials,  Electrostatics at Interfaces, Structure and Dynamics of Ion-Containing Polymers, Complex Polymer Networks towards the Design of Smart Materials.<br/><a href="https://chemistry.berkeley.edu/faculty/cbe/wang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Wenjun Zhang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Natural product biosynthesis and engineering for health and bioenergy applications.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/wenjun-zhang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Negar Beheshti, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dean C. Draemel, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sudhir Joshi, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jason Ryder, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gregory R. Schoofs, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steve Sciamanna, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George Tyson, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marjorie Went, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Harvey W. Blanch, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Biochemical Engineering.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/harvey-w-blanch"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Morton Denn, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jean M. J. Frechet, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Materials chemistry, catalysis, drug delivery, analytical chemistry, organic synthesis, polymer science, macromolecules, chiral recognition, control of molecular architecture at the nanometer scale, reactive surfaces.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14685"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Simon Goren, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>C. Judson King, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Separation processes, spray drying, and higher education.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/c-judson-king"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Scott Lynn, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John S. Newman, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Chemical engineering, electrochemical systems, lithium batteries, industrial electrochemical processes, methanol fuel cells.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/john-s-newman"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Michael C. Williams, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

