<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Art Practice</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The two-year Master of Fine Arts (MFA) Program supports 12 graduate students per year and strives to graduate working artists who will continue to demonstrate significant artistic, critical and cultural impacts across a wide array of disciplines. Incoming MFA students are expected to already be deeply engaged in their creative practice and possess technical proficiency in their chosen media. Graduate coursework and independent study are designed to help students develop a critical understanding of their creative work in the multiple contexts of specific localities and global contemporary art. Our graduate students are encouraged to take university-wide and cross-disciplinary courses linked to their research interests, studying and collaborating with faculty and graduate students in areas as diverse as Geography, Environmental Sciences, Classics, Art History, Disability Studies, Philosophy, Cognitive Science, Interactive Design, Rhetoric, Film Studies, and Comparative Literature.</p>
<p>The Program helps students develop a working relationship to audiences by facilitating the exposure of graduate student work through museums and galleries, public art, online, publications, and through other forms of engagement and dissemination. <span>Peer-to-peer discussion and critique form the heart of Berkeley’s MFA Program. Students respond to their peers’ work and learn to think, speak, and write critically about art’s functions and possibilities.  A </span><a href="https://art.berkeley.edu/lecture-series" target="_blank">Visiting Artist Lecture Series</a><span>, along with studio visits, offers graduate students the chance to connect with internationally-known artists. Students also have opportunities to teach, and they are mentored and closely supported by a faculty member. Exhibitions in the first and second years of study require students to maintain a rigorous pace of creative research and establish a professional art practice. The final thesis exhibition, completed after the second year of study, is held at the Berkeley Art Museum.</span></p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<mastersdegreerequirementstext name="Master's Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h4><strong>Curriculum</strong></h4>
<h5><strong>Unit requirements to complete the program: 64 units in two years</strong></h5>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 294">ART 294</span></td><td>Seminar for M.F.A. Students (Students enroll in this class every semester)</td><td class="hourscol">16</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 218">ART 218</span></td><td>Seminar: Theory and Criticism (Students enroll in this class twice, every fall semester)</td><td class="hourscol">8</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 290">ART 290</span></td><td>Independent Study (First year)</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 295">ART 295</span></td><td>Independent Study for M.F.A. Students (Second year)</td><td class="hourscol">4-12</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Electives appropriate to the student's course of study are chosen in conjunction with their advising faculty</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Two upper division electives, commonly studio courses</span></td><td class="hourscol">6-8</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">One visual cultures elective, commonly a theory course</span></td><td class="hourscol">3-4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>Students will enroll in <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 290">ART 290</span></span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ART 295">ART 295</span></span> independent study multiple times in their first and second years, respectively. Independent study units cover studio work in collaboration with faculty mentors, and preparation for the MFA show. Scheduling of independent study units in each semester is dependent on the student's greater academic plan.</p>
]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3> Art Practice</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art218" data-toggle="#cb_art218">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 218</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar: Theory and Criticism</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art218">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Weekly meetings will provide a forum for the discussion of issues related to assigned readings in the fields of esthetics, theory and art criticism.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Seminar: Theory and Criticism:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="314" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Seminar: Theory and Criticism:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art229" data-toggle="#cb_art229">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 229</span> 
<span class="title">NEW MEDIA METHODS</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art229">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2014<br/>
In this methods course we will study key languages of new media innovation, ranging from flow charts to scripting languages and circuit diagrams. Our study method involves the creation and application of sensing devices in an urban context, and engages students in establishing chains of references which connect ground truth to data, data to information, information to people, people to actions, and actions to policies. Taking into account technical, political, cultural</span><span class="deschide"> and literacy questions we seek to connect our data production work with information needs of<br/>
underserved communities in the Bay Area region.<br/></span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>NEW MEDIA METHODS:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="296" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>NEW MEDIA METHODS:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art290" data-toggle="#cb_art290">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 290</span> 
<span class="title">Independent Study</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art290">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022<br/>
Individual projects by first-year graduate students with one assigned instructor.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Independent Study:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="66" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Hours to be arranged.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Independent Study:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art294" data-toggle="#cb_art294">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 294</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar for M.F.A. Students</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art294">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Studio work emphasizing various aspects of form. Group criticism. Intended especially for M.F.A. candidates.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Seminar for M.F.A. Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="524" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the M.F.A. program</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Seminar for M.F.A. Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art295" data-toggle="#cb_art295">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 295</span> 
<span class="title">Independent Study for M.F.A. Students</span> 
<span class="hours">4 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art295">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022<br/>
Special study for MFA students under the guidance of MFA Committee members as well as other faculty.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Independent Study for M.F.A. Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="945" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the M.F.A. program</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0-0 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Zero hour of independent study per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Independent Study for M.F.A. Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art298" data-toggle="#cb_art298">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 298</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Group Study</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art298">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2019, Spring 2018, Spring 2017<br/>
Directed group study for MFA students in specialized topics, group research, and/or interdisciplinary work.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Directed Group Study:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="162" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Directed Group Study:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art299" data-toggle="#cb_art299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 299</span> 
<span class="title">Supervised Independent Study for Graduate Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Spring 2020<br/>
Special projects by MFA students undertaken with a specific faculty member.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Supervised Independent Study for Graduate Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="219" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and consent of instructor, graduate adviser, and Department Chair</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0-0 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Zero hour of independent study per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Supervised Independent Study for Graduate Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_art301" data-toggle="#cb_art301">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">ART 301</span> 
<span class="title">The Teaching of Art: Practice</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_art301">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
MFA course utilizing aspects of pedagogical and andragogical teaching, the interactive lecture, collaborative learning, simulations, and brainstorming-freewriting, this semester-long seminar will focus on these various intergrative teaching approaches, to facilitate communication in the diverse and wide-ranging arena which is fine arts today. Discussion of course aims, instructional methods, grading standards, and special problems in the teaching</span><span class="deschide"> of art practice.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Teaching of Art: Practice:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="162" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Practice of Art/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Teaching of Art: Practice:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Allan deSouza, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Photography, contemporary art, Art Pedagogy, performance, postcolonial studies, Contemporary African Art, South Asian Art.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/allan-desouza"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kenyatta A.C. Hinkle, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Visual Art, painting, Drawing, performance, social practice, Experimental Poetics, African studies, African-American Studies.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/kenyatta-ac-hinkle"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Asma Kazmi, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Transdisciplinary, performative, relational works.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/kazmi-asma"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jill S. Miller, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Visual arts.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jill-miller"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Greg Niemeyer, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Art, film studies, digital media installations, photography.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15179"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Brody Reiman, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Sculpture and installation.<br/><a href="https://art.berkeley.edu/brody-reiman"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stephanie Syjuco, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Visual art, installation, cultural objects, archives, social practice.<br/><a href="http://art.berkeley.edu/people/stephanie-syjuco-assistant-professor"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anne Walsh, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Video, performance, audio, photography, text.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/anne-walsh"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Chris Christion, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Aida Gamez, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nicki Green, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Dana Hemenway, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Carrie Hott, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Randy M. Hussong, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christina Klein-Tross, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher S. Kubick, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Indira M. Morre, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Craig K. Nagasawa, <i>Continuing Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Leila Weefur, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Jerrold Ballaine, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Squeak Carnwath, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Art, painting, printmaking.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14480"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anne Healy, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Melchert, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary Lovelace O'Neal, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard Shaw, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Katherine D. Sherwood, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Art and Disability.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16293"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Simpson, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Brian Wall, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

