<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Food Systems</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<div>
<div class="m_4384408139246321857gmail_signature">
<p>The Graduate Certificate in Food Systems (GCFS) responds to an escalating need to empower new leaders with the capacity to create innovative solutions to pressing food and agriculture challenges. Building on UC Berkeley’s strength as a multi-disciplinary pioneer in food systems studies, the Certificate in Food Systems prepares Masters and Doctoral students to think critically about the multi-level, multi-system factors that affect food production, distribution, and consumption locally, nationally, and globally. This interdisciplinary program complements students’ primary fields of study by addressing the ecological, social, health, political, policy, legal, and economic dimensions of food and agriculture and providing graduates with the necessary theoretical framework and practical skills that can be applied across diverse and emerging food-systems challenges.</p>
<p>The GCFS is hosted by the School of Public Health, College of Natural Resources, and Goldman School of Public Policy, and administered by the Berkeley Food Institute. Students from any graduate program at UC Berkeley are eligible to complete the certificate.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div class="m_4384408139246321857gmail_signature">
<p>Students pursuing the certificate take three courses: a required core course entitled “PH HLTH 207: Transforming Food Systems: From Agroecology to Population Health,” and a minimum of two elective courses totaling a minimum of 6 units. Courses not on the electives list will be considered on a case by case basis.</p>
<p>We encourage students to take all certificate courses outside their primary degrees; however one course can overlap with primary degree requirements.</p>
</div>
</div>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>Any UC Berkeley graduate student in good standing (GPA of 3.0 or better) may apply. Completion of the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScC3b1o0Tpea1qZ8V4DK8ttQmDqT0Z3YIAmuzyaWpp2fToRxg/viewform" target="_blank">Application for Admission Form</a> is required before completing the certificate core course. Applications will be considered on a rolling basis.</p>
<p>Complete the Application for Admission Form to plan out your certificate coursework. You are encouraged to apply prior to taking the core course, though it is not required. Applications will be considered on a rolling basis. For students in 2-year masters programs, you are encouraged to take the core course and/or at least one elective during your first year to ensure you are able to complete the certificate requirements.</p>
<p>This application for admission signals a student’s interest in the Graduate Certificate in Food Systems, but does not guarantee that the certificate will be awarded, nor guarantee a seat in GCFS-approved courses.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<certificaterequirementstext name="Certificate Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Graduate Certificate in Food Systems consists of 3 courses (totaling a minimum of 9 units), each of which must be taken for a letter grade.</p>
<ul>
	<li>Required core course – <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PB HLTH 207">PB HLTH 207</span></span>: Transforming Food Systems: From Agroecology to Population Health (3 units, taught each fall)</li>
	<li>Two elective courses, chosen from the list below, totaling a minimum of 6 units. Courses not on the electives list will be considered on a case by case basis, via submission of the Elective Petition Form.</li>
</ul>
<p>We encourage students to take all certificate courses outside their primary degrees; however one course can overlap with primary degree requirements.</p>
<h4>Core Course</h4>
<p><strong><span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PB HLTH 207">PB HLTH 207</span> Transforming the Food System: From Agroecology to Population Health</span> </strong>is held every fall and taught by Kristine Madsen, Associate Professor in the Joint Medical Program/Public Health Nutrition. The course is conducted as a weekly seminar with guest lectures by UC Berkeley's preeminent food systems scholars and other experts in the field. It takes a solutions-oriented approach to addressing the pressing problems in current food systems through strategies used by the disciplines of agroecology, policy, law, public health, and business in working to improve food systems and apply their varied approaches to real-world case studies. Through weekly readings, discussions, and problem-solving sessions with Berkeley’s leading food systems experts, students will gain a broad understanding of food systems and the leverage points that can be targeted to improve the health of people and the planet.</p>
<p><strong>The Fall 2022 core course will be held on Thursdays, 2–5pm, for in-person instruction (pending latest public health guidelines). It will be taught by Kristen Madsen, Professor at the School of Public Health. Look for class # 29919 in the <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/graduate/degree-programs/food-systems/classes.berkeley.edu" target="_blank">Class Schedule</a> or CalCentral's schedule of classes.</strong></p>
<h4>Elective Courses</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">The following electives count toward the Graduate Certificate in Food Systems. Note that not every course is offered on a yearly basis. Check guide.berkeley.edu for the most up to date course descriptions and class schedule.</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CY PLAN C256">CY PLAN C256/PB HLTH C233</span></td><td>Healthy Cities</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENE,RES 275">ENE,RES 275</span></td><td>Water and Development</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ESPM 226">ESPM 226</span></td><td>Interdisciplinary Food and Agriculture Studies</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ESPM 230">ESPM 230</span></td><td>Sociology of Agriculture</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ESPM 261">ESPM 261</span></td><td>Sustainability and Society</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ESPM 279">ESPM 279</span></td><td>Seminar on Pastoralism</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ESPM 280">ESPM 280</span></td><td>Seminar in Range Ecosystem Planning and Policy</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 292N">MBA 292N</span></td><td>Course Not Available (Food Innovation Studio – This course is by application; contact the professor for instructions.)</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">MBA 292.22 Plant Futures (This course is by application; contact the professor for instructions) &amp; <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 293">MBA 293</span> </span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUSCTX 260">NUSCTX 260</span></td><td>Metabolic Bases of Human Health and Diseases Graduate Level</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PB HLTH 206B">PB HLTH 206B</span></td><td>Food and Nutrition Policies and Programs</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PB HLTH 206D">PB HLTH 206D</span></td><td>Programs and Policies in Global Nutrition</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PB HLTH 207A">PB HLTH 207A</span></td><td>Public Health Aspects of Maternal and Child Nutrition</td><td class="hourscol">2,3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PB HLTH 266A">PB HLTH 266A</span></td><td>Foodborne diseases</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PB HLTH 271G">PB HLTH 271G</span></td><td>Health Implications of Climate Change</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PUB POL 290">PUB POL 290</span></td><td>Special Topics in Public Policy (The Social Safety Net, Poverty, and Income Inequality - Spring)</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PUB POL 290">PUB POL 290</span></td><td>Special Topics in Public Policy (The Fight for Food Justice: Mass Movement or Consumer Culture - Fall every other year)</td><td class="hourscol">3-4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h4>Elective Petitions</h4>
<p>Students can petition for graduate courses beyond the standard elective list to count toward the certificate. Particularly 290 Special Topics and 299 Independent Study courses will be considered on a case by case basis, as topics pertain to food systems. Students must submit the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeR391EqEyvbScKvRv3O0ucjbBuksJC72qOOdxTMfOuZCp0eQ/viewform" target="_blank">Elective Petition Form</a> <strong>at least one month prior </strong>to enrolling in the proposed course. Electives proposed by the petition must be approved before taking the class.</p>
<h4><span>Certificate Completion</span></h4>
<p>Students submit the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScF8Bxbo8c_O6h-k5-CkHyou-tP_s2kxmH5f5oNPY54WDq9eg/viewform?usp=sf_link" target="_blank">Certificate Completion Form</a> at the point that all requirements for the Graduate Certificate in Food Systems are complete. Submit this form by April 15 of your graduating year in order for the certificate to appear on your transcript. If you have certificate courses in progress during your final semester, you can indicate this on the form. Final grades will be verified prior to award of the certificate.</p>
<p>Completion of the GCFS will be noted in the memorandum section of the student’s official transcript (not on the diploma). At the time of completion, each student receives a physical certificate signed by the deans of Berkeley Public Health, Rausser College of Natural Resources, and Goldman School of Public Policy.</p>
<p>If you have any questions, please contact Berkeley Food Institute at <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/graduate/degree-programs/food-systems/mailto:foodinstitute@berkeley.edu">foodinstitute@berkeley.edu.</a></p>
]]>
</certificaterequirementstext>
<programbenefitstext name="Program Benefits">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Graduate Certificate in Food Systems provides a unique opportunity for making connections with students from across the campus with a shared interest in food systems. Typically students from ten different Berkeley degree programs participate in the core course; together they make an interdisciplinary intellectual community not typically found within students' primary degree programs.</p>
<p>The core course and certificate provides an integrated and structured overview of food systems such that graduates understand complex &quot;production webs,&quot; how each aspect of these systems feeds into and depends on other aspects, and how different disciplines (ecology, business, policy, law, public health) have approached challenges in food systems. Through the certificate, students are exposed to multidisciplinary experiences and trained in analytical and applied skills. Thus, students who complete the certificate are better contributors to the multidisciplinary teams that are increasingly leading food systems changes. Further, students will be able to assess the strengths and weaknesses of various strategies (e.g., legal, political, or market-based) that they might pursue as they work to improve food systems during their careers.</p>
]]>
</programbenefitstext>
<facultytext name="Faculty">
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://sph.berkeley.edu/kristine-madsen" target="_blank">Kristine Madsen</a>, Associate Professor in the Joint Medical Program/Public Health Nutrition, serves as the director for the Graduate Certificate in Food Systems.</p>
]]>
</facultytext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

