<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Microbiology</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Microbiology is composed of 53 faculty from diverse departments, colleges, and schools (Plant and Microbial Biology; Molecular and Cell Biology; Public Health; Civil and Environmental Engineering; Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering; Environmental Science, Policy, and Management; Nutritional Sciences and Toxicology; Optometry; and Integrative Biology) and is administered by the Department of Plant and Microbial Biology.</p>
<p>The group awards a PhD degree in Microbiology. Students in the group have access to diverse disciplines through an integrated program of study that allows each student to pursue specialized interests. Students gain a breadth of understanding of microbiology from the molecular to the cellular levels of organization, as well as the interactions of microbes—beneficial and pathogenic—with other organisms.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/microbiology/">Microbiology</a>: PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Rodrigo P. P. Almeida, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Disease ecology, vector, plant disease, Xylella fastidiosa, emerging.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16863"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lisa Alvarez-Cohen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Environmental microbiology, biodegradation of environmental contaminants, microbial carbon cycling, molecular tools for microbial ecology, metagenomics, biological hazardous waste treatment, bioremediation of groundwater pollutants such as PCE, TCE, DCE, VC, TCA, DCA, MTBE, BTEX, PBDEs, NDMA, Dioxane, PFOS, PFOA, fire-fighting foams.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13943"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rachel B. Brem, <i>Associate Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics of regulatory variation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14468"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven Brenner, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, computational biology, evolutionary biology, bioengineering, structural genomics, computational genomics, cellular activity, cellular functions, personal genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14469"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Thomas D. Bruns, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microbial biology, plant biology, fungi, nucleic acid sequences, basidomycetes, ectomycorrhizal fungi communities.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14423"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bob B. Buchanan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biotechnology, environmental policy, plant biology, thioredoxin.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14407"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jamie Cate, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular basis for protein synthesis by the ribosome, RNA, antibiotics, a thermophilic bacterium, escherichia coli.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14485"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michelle Chang, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Biochemistry, enzymology, synthetic biology, biophysics .<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/michelle-chang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Coates, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Environmental microbiology, Bioremediation, alternative energy production, biogeochemistry.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/john-coates"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Laurent Coscoy, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Immunology, viruses, viral infection, immune responses, immune evasion.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13882"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Eugene Dueber, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Synthetic biology, Metabolic Engineering.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16684"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary K. Firestone, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Soils, environmental policy, environmental science, policy and management, wildlife, miicrobial biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14669"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Suzanne Fleiszig, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Immunology, eye, microbiology, infectious disease, corneal physiology, tear film physiology, bacterial pathogenesis, contact lenses, pseudomonas aeruginosa, epithelial cell biology, innate immunity.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/gertrude-buehring"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>N. Louise Glass, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biofuels, biotechnology, fungal genetics, fungal cell biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14717"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Britt Glaunsinger, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Virology, gene expression, herpesvirus.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14718"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Igor V. Grigoriev, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Genomics, fungi, algae, eukaryotes, computational biology, bioinformatics, genome annotation.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16280"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eva Harris, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/eva-harris"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jay Keasling, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microorganism metabolic engineering for environmentally friendly product   .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jay-d-keasling"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nicole King, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, developmental biology, biology, choanoflagellates, multicellularity, evolution of animals, comparative genomics, eukaryotes, host-microbe interactions, bacterial signals.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14922"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Arash Komeili, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Microbiology, Biomineralization, bacterial organelles, Magnetic Nanoparticles.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14931"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer Lewis, <i>Assistant Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Plant-pathogen interactions, plant immunity, type III effector proteins.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16277"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven E. Lindow, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microbial ecology, microbial biology, plant biology, plant frost control, bacterial plant diseases, plant disease epidemiology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15320"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fenyong Liu, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15029"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Krishna K. Niyogi, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, plant and microbial biology, algae, photosynthesis, antioxidants.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15353"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Celine Pallud, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Biogeochemistry, iron reduction, metals and contaminants, soil aggregates, selenium kinetics of organic matter degradation, nitrate reduction, soil and environmental biogeophysics, biogeochemical cycles, fate and transport of nutrients, sulfate reduction, wetland soils, littoral sediments, spatial variation in biogeochemical processes.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15367"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel A. Portnoy, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mammalian cells, molecular and cellular basis of microbial pathogenesis, defense against infection, listeria monocytogenes, cell biology of infection, mechanisms of secretion.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15237"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lee Riley, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Public health, infectious diseases, molecular epidemiology, global health, tuberculosis, drug-resistant infections, slum health.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15036"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Jasper D. Rine, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biology, cell biology, DNA replication, gene regulation, saccharomyces cerevisiae, genetic analysis, genome, cholesterol biosynthetic pathway, modification of proteins, prenylated proteins.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13905"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kathleen Ryan, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Bacterial cell cycle regulation, signal transduction, and regulated proteolysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15294"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Savage, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Synthetic biology and metabolism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15309"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Randy W. Schekman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Saccharomyces cerevisiae, organelle assembly, intracellular protein transport, assembly of cellular organelles, Alzheimer's Disease.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13908"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Shapira, <i>Assistant Professor in Residence</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, aging, host-pathogen interactions.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14351"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Chris Somerville, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biochemistry, biotechnology, bioenergy, cell biology, biofuels, cell walls, polysaccharides, cellulose, arabidopsis, cellulose synthase.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15475"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Shauna Somerville, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Powdery mildew disease, cell wall integrity sensing, plant-fungal interactions, plant cell walls.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15474"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Chelsea Specht, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular evolution, adaptation, plant systematics, evolution of development (evo-devo), evolution of form and function, plant morphology, comparative phylogenetics, floral developmental evolution, diversification rates.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14316"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sarah Stanley, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Mechanisms of pathogenesis and immune subversion in tuberculosis, protective immunity to tuberculosis, metabolic interactions between hosts and pathogens, development of novel therapeutics for tuberculosis, scientific capacity building, tuberculosis.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sarah-stanley"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Brian J. Staskawicz, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biotechnology, plant and microbial biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15492"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Richard S. Stephens, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular genetics, microbiology, infectious disease, pathogenesis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15497"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michiko Taga, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, genetics, microbial biology, chemical biology, cofactors, nutrient exchange, microbial communities.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15519"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Taylor, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Evolution, fungi, phylogenomics, mycology, population genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14243"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Matthew Traxler, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Danielle Tullman-Ercek, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Bioenergy, synthetic biology, protein engineering, bionanotechnology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14161"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Russell E. Vance, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Immunology, microbiology, infectious disease, molecular and cell biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14144"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Matthew D. Welch, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Biology, cell motility, the role of the actin cytoskeleton in cell locomotion, shape change, actin filament assembly, bacterial and viral pathogens.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15607"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mary Wildermuth, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Plant-pathogen interactions.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/mary-wildermuth"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Patricia Zambryski, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Microbial biology, plant biology, plant intercellular communication via plasmodesmata, Agrobacterium, bacterial type IV secretion.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14305"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Wenjun Zhang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Natural product biosynthesis and engineering for health and bioenergy applications.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/wenjun-zhang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Affiliated Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Sangwei Lu, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Pathogenesis and stress response of Salmonella serovars, foodborne diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sangwei-lu"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

