<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Course Threads</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-130e363a-7fff-c011-0c91-ef4c2a9ff26d">A Course Thread is a series of three courses offered through multiple departments and disciplines. The classes in each series are related to one another by an intellectual theme. </span>Any UC Berkeley undergraduate can complete a Course Thread and be<span> eligible to receive a certificate. </span>Students may then participate in an end-of-semester symposium at the Townsend Center to receive a certificate of completion of their thread.</p>
<p><span>The organization of a Course Thread is far more flexible and less demanding than a major or minor. </span>Course Threads consist of 1- and 2-unit courses. Because they are not fulfilling a major or minor, all courses are weighted equally, regardless of unit value. </p>
<p><span>To find classes offered within a course thread, go to the <a href="https://classes.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Class Schedule</a> in the Berkeley Academic Guide, scroll down through the filters on the left,</span> and use the Course Threads filters to find classes relevant to the thread in which you would like to participate. </p>
<p>If you would like to count a course toward your Course Thread that isn't already approved, you can <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/course-threads/#contacts">contact your Course Thread advisor </a>with a 200-word justification that highlights which parts of the course syllabus are most relevant to your completion of the Course Thread. Please include the syllabus and your unofficial transcript as attachments. You must gain approval from the Course Thread’s advisor in order for the requested course to count towards the certificate.</p>
<h3>Course Thread Options</h3>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Carceral Geographies: Beyond the Prison | Legal Studies: </span></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Prison and its affiliated domains—probation, parole, intensive policing—have long and complex genealogies. The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/carceral-geographies/">Carceral Geographies Course Thread</a> examines the nature and experience of prison and its related spaces.</span> </p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Culture and Globalization | ISF: </span></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Our world is transnationally connected through migration, markets, and media, yet our mental maps and cultural policies still tend to reaffirm the ideas of fixed territory and “authentic” heritage. The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/culturalforms/">Culture and Globalization Course Thread</a> explores how cultural mediation and interdependence operate on local and global scales. </span></p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Historical and Modern City | ISF: </span></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/schwane/">Historical and Modern City Course Thread</a> introduces students to historical, theoretical, aesthetic, and other approaches to the city through a variety of interdisciplinary methodologies.</span></p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Human Rights | ISF: </span></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/humanrights/">Human Rights Course Thread</a> encourages students to explore questions of how human rights are intertwined with fields as disparate as postcolonial literature and medical ethics, as well as with the more familiar fields of politics and international law.</span></p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Humanities &amp; Environment | ISF: </span></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/humanitiesenvironment/">Humanities &amp; Environment Course Thread</a> promotes new approaches to understanding the ways that humans imagine, represent, and interact with the natural world. Students explore challenging questions about how our imagined relations with the natural world have contributed to our strained relations with the environment.</span></p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Law &amp; Humanities | Rhetoric</span>: </h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/law-humanities/">Law &amp; Humanities Course Thread</a> illuminates the importance of the humanities for exploring questions of law and literature, law and history, law and philosophy, law and music, and law and the visual arts. Through this Thread, students consider what law is and where it resides.</span></p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Sciences &amp; Society | CSTMS</span>: </h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">From climate change and nuclear risk to new developments in biomedicine, the pressing problems of our time are simultaneously scientific and social, technological and political, ethical and economic. The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/sciences-and-society/">Sciences &amp; Society Course Thread</a> gives students opportunities to consider how scientific questions intersect with historical, cultural, and social issues.</span></p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Technologies of Writing | ISF: </span></h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">While technologies of writing—from clay tablets to electronic media—have changed dramatically over time, the underlying human processes of adapting forms and functions to various media and to the social needs of the time are nevertheless comparable. The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/visiblelanguage/">Technologies of Writing Course Thread</a> investigates technologies of writing as cultural practices.</span></p>
<h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">Visual Cultures | ISF</span>: </h5>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-fae09f17-7fff-353c-92f4-0f17d49d472a">A single image can reflect and influence social change, provide a historical record, offer opportunities for personal and aesthetic expression, serve as legal and scientific “proof,” and be used to forge an identity. The <a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/#/visibilities/">Visual Cultures Course Thread</a> examines the image’s role in shaping aesthetics, politics, and social culture. </span></p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<certificaterequirementstext name="Certificate Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-2eb631fb-7fff-7356-598a-f722b27e675b">To earn the Course Threads certificate:</span></strong></p>
<ol>
	<li><span>Successfully complete the courses in one thread (from at least two different departments). </span></li>
	<li><span><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/course-threads/#contacts">Contact your Course Thread representative</a> to confirm that you have completed eligible courses in the thread. Be sure to send them a copy of your unofficial transcript.</span></li>
	<li><a href="https://coursethreads.berkeley.edu/sign-up-form">Sign up</a> to present in a Course Threads Symposium. You will be contacted by the Townsend Center for the Humanities with further details about the Symposium date. Symposium registration for the current semester closes the last Monday of formal classes, a week before RRR week.</li>
	<li>Participate in an RRR week Course Threads Symposium at the Townsend Center (220 Stephens Hall) and give a five- to ten-minute presentation about your experience with your Course Thread's theme. </li>
</ol>
<p>Students may receive only one certificate per semester.</p>
]]>
</certificaterequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

