<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Political Economy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>The Designated Emphasis (DE) in Political Economy gives PhD students at UC Berkeley the opportunity to strengthen their training in interdisciplinary political economy, to join a vibrant intellectual community that cuts across academic units on campus, and to earn an extra credential along with their doctoral degree. This program has multiple benefits for faculty and graduate students as well as for the campus community more broadly, positioning Berkeley at the cutting edge of the study of interdisciplinary political economy, both nationally and internationally.</span></p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>PhD students in any department may apply. All applications must be reviewed and approved by the Executive Committee of the Graduate Group. In order to gain such approval, students must have taken one core course (or be enrolled in one) before applying to the Designated Emphasis.</p>
<p>They must commit to fulfilling the DE requirements and present a tentative plan for doing so (with proposed courses, dates for those courses, and a target date for the Qualifying Examination).</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequirementstext name="Designated Emphasis Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Curriculum</h3>
<p>Students in the DE must take three courses from the list below, or two courses from the list plus a third course with substantial political economy content with the approval of the DE head graduate advisor. At least two of the three courses must be taken outside of the student’s home department. And the three courses must be from at least two different departments.</p>
<h4><strong>Core Course List</strong></h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="POL SCI 209A">POL SCI 209A</span></td><td>Comparative Political Economy</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="POL SCI 226A">POL SCI 226A</span></td><td>International Political Economy</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="POL SCI 279">POL SCI 279</span></td><td>Selected Topics in American Government</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SOCIOL 280Q">SOCIOL 280Q</span></td><td>Advanced Study in Substantive Sociological Fields: Economy and Society</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="SOCIOL 290">SOCIOL 290</span></td><td>Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="HISTORY 280D">HISTORY 280D</span></td><td>Advanced Studies: Sources/General Literature of the Several Fields: United States (When topic is Economic History)</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 210A">ECON 210A</span></td><td>Introduction to Economic History</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 215A">ECON 215A</span></td><td>Political Economics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 215B">ECON 215B</span></td><td>Political Economics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ECON 260A">ECON 260A</span></td><td>Comparative Economics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="GEOG 215">GEOG 215</span></td><td>Seminar in Comparative and International Development</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ESPM 217">ESPM 217</span></td><td>Political Economy of Climate Change</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="LAW 217">LAW 217</span></td><td>Course Not Available (When taught by Prof. Grewal and subject is Political Economy related)</td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHDBA 279A">PHDBA 279A</span></td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHDBA 279B">PHDBA 279B</span></td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>DE students are encouraged to embrace the spirit of the program, and not only to satisfy the minimum formal requirements. In particular, they are encouraged to take at least two courses that stretch them beyond the most prevalent approaches to political economy in their home disciplines.</p>
<p>DE students will also be required to participate in DE workshops to be held about once a month during the fall and spring semesters. They will also be encouraged to participate in Network for a New Political Economy (N2PE) programs.</p>
<p>Since the Economics Department and the Haas School political economy programs overlap, students in one of these units may only count one course in the other unit as an “outside” course. Thus, an Economics student could count one Haas course as an outside course, but would have to take at least one course outside of both Economics and Haas.</p>
<p>The History Department offers a variety of seminars with the number 280, so only those that focus on political economy will count for this program. In case of doubt, check with the graduate student affairs officer.</p>
<h3>Examination and Dissertation Requirements</h3>
<p>Students must be admitted to the DE before the qualifying examination. The qualifying examination must include examination of knowledge within the DE.</p>
<p>Students must have at least one DE faculty member on their Qualifying Exam and Dissertation Committees. They should choose that member(s) from the Designated Emphasis affiliated faculty roster. Students may also request approval from the graduate adviser for another faculty member, who has substantial expertise in political economy, and whose own work is relevant to that of the student.</p>
<p>The dissertation topic must incorporate study within the Designated Emphasis.</p>
<h3>Designated Emphasis Conferral Process</h3>
<p>The Designated Emphasis will be awarded solely in conjunction with the doctoral degree and will be signified on the student’s transcript.</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

