<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Statistics</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Department of Statistics offers the Master of Arts (MA) and Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) degrees.</p>
<h3>Master of Arts (MA)</h3>
<p>The Statistics MA program prepares students for careers that require statistical skills. It focuses on tackling statistical challenges encountered by industry rather than preparing for a PhD. The program is for full-time students and is designed to be completed in two semesters (fall and spring).</p>
<p>There is no way to transfer into the PhD program from the MA program. Students must apply to the PhD program.</p>
<h3>Doctor of Philosophy (PhD)</h3>
<p>The Statistics PhD program is rigorous, yet welcoming to students with interdisciplinary interests and different levels of preparation. The standard PhD program in statistics provides a broad background in probability theory and applied and theoretical statistics.</p>
<p>There are two designated emphasis (DE) tracks available to students in the PhD program who wish to pursue interdisciplinary work formally: <a href="https://data.berkeley.edu/decdse">Computational and Data Science and Engineering</a> and <a href="http://ccb.berkeley.edu/academics/designated-emphasis/">Computational and Genomic Biology</a>.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<div class="clearfix">
<div class="cola">
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/graduate/degree-programs/statistics/#AdmitBerkeley">Admission to the University</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="colb">
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/graduate/degree-programs/statistics/#AdmitProgram">Admission to the Program</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a id="AdmitBerkeley" name="AdmitBerkeley"/>Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant has completed a basic degree from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 on a 9-point scale (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates, but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without the need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts: </strong>Applicants may upload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. Unofficial transcripts must contain specific information including the name of the applicant, name of the school, all courses, grades, units, &amp; degree conferral (if applicable). </li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, by the recommender, not the Graduate Admissions.</li> 	<li> 	<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Evidence of English language proficiency:</span> </strong>All applicants who have completed a basic degree from a country or political entity in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to institutions from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement:</p> 	<ul> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses in English as a Second Language,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses conducted in a language other than English,</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and</span></p> 		</li> 		<li> 		<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">courses of a non-academic nature.</span></p> 		</li> 	</ul> 	</li> </ol> <p style="margin-left:30pt"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-7a006b7d-7fff-5bf6-e871-4a34569dad42">Applicants who have previously applied to Berkeley must also submit new test scores that meet the current minimum requirement from one of the standardized tests. Official TOEFL score reports must be sent directly from Educational Test Services (ETS). The institution code for Berkeley is 4833 for Graduate Organizations. Official IELTS score reports must be sent electronically from the testing center to University of California, Berkeley, Graduate Division, Sproul Hall, Rm 318 MC 5900, Berkeley, CA 94720. TOEFL and IELTS score reports are only valid for two years prior to beginning the graduate program at UC Berkeley. </span></span>Note: score reports can not expire before the month of June.</p> <div> </div> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a>. </p>
<h3><a id="AdmitProgram" name="AdmitProgram"/>Admission to the Program</h3>
<p>In addition to the minimum requirements listed above, the following materials are required for admission:</p>
<ol>
	<li><strong><a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">The Online Graduate Application for Admission and Fellowships</a>:</strong></li>
	<li><strong><a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/state_purpose.shtml" target="_blank">Statement of Purpose</a> : </strong>Why are you applying to this program? What are your expectations for this degree? Where do you want this degree to take you, professionally and personally? How will your professional and personal experiences add value to the program?</li>
	<li><strong><a href="http://www.grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/personal_statement.shtml">Personal History </a></strong><strong><a href="http://www.grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/personal_statement.shtml" target="_blank">Statement</a> : </strong>What past experiences made you decide to go into this field? How will your personal history help you succeed in this program and your future goals? </li>
	<li><strong>GRE General Test Scores:</strong><span class="apple-converted-space"> T</span>he GRE is no longer required for applicants applying to the MA or PhD program.  For the PhD program, while it is not required, if you wish to include your GRE Math Subject test you will have the option to do so.</li>
	<li><strong>Descriptive List of Upper Division/Graduate Statistics and Math Coursework: </strong>Please include a Descriptive List of Upper Division/Graduate Statistics and Math Coursework. List the department, course number and title, instructor, grade, school, texts used and subject matter covered for all upper division and graduate level statistics and math courses you have taken. You should also include courses outside statistics and math departments that have a significant quantitative component. This list should be uploaded as a PDF document via the online application.</li>
	<li><strong>Resume:</strong> Include a full resume/CV listing your experience and education.</li>
</ol>
<p>The application process is entirely online. All supplemental materials such as transcripts and the descriptive list of courses must be uploaded as PDF files via the online application by the application deadline. Please do not mail copies of your transcripts, statement of purpose, letters of recommendations, GRE and TOEFL scores, resumes, or any other documents as they will not be included with your application.</p>
<p class="Normal1">For more information about graduate programs in statistics, including admission information, please visit our <a href="https://statistics.berkeley.edu/academics/programs" target="_blank">graduate programs page</a>.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext name="Doctoral Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Normative Time Requirements</h3>
<h4>Normative Time to Advancement</h4>
<p class="Normal1CxSpFirst">In the first year, students must perform satisfactorily in preliminary course work. In the summer, students are required to embark on a short-term research project, internship, graduate student instructorship, reading course, or on another research activity.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpLast">In the second and third years, students continue to take courses, serve as a graduate student instructor, find an area for the oral qualifying exam, a potential thesis adviser and pass the oral qualifying exam in the spring semester of second year or in the fall semester of third year. With the successful passing of the exam, students then advance to candidacy.</p>
<h4>Normative Time in Candidacy</h4>
<p class="Normal1CxSpFirst">In the third and fourth years, students finalize a thesis topic, continue to conduct research and make satisfactory progress.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpLast">By the end of the fifth year, students are expected to finish their thesis and give a lecture based on their work in a department seminar.</p>
<h4 class="Normal1CxSpLast">Total Normative Time</h4>
<p>Total normative time is five years.</p>
<h3>Time in Advancement </h3>
<h4>Curriculum</h4>
<p>During their first year, students are normally expected to take four of the following seven core PhD courses in Probability, Theoretical Statistics, and Applied Statistics:</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Courses Required</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 204">STAT 204</span></td><td>Probability for Applications</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT C205A">STAT C205A</span></td><td>Probability Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT C205B">STAT C205B</span></td><td>Probability Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 210A">STAT 210A</span></td><td>Theoretical Statistics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 210B">STAT 210B</span></td><td>Theoretical Statistics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 215A">STAT 215A</span></td><td>Statistical Models: Theory and Application</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 215B">STAT 215B</span></td><td>Statistical Models: Theory and Application</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="listsum"><td colspan="2">Total Units</td><td class="hourscol">28</td></tr></tbody></table>

<p>A member of the PhD program committee may consent to substitute courses at a comparable level in other disciplines for some of these departmental graduate courses. These requirements can also be altered by the PhD program committee.</p>
<p><span>Students are required to take five additional graduate courses beyond the four required in the first year, resulting in a total of nine graduate courses required for completion of their PhD. In their second year, students are required to take three graduate courses, at least two of them from the department offerings, and in their third year, they are required to take at least two graduate courses. Students are allowed to change the timing of these five courses with approval of their faculty mentor.</span></p>
<p><span>Of the nine required graduate courses, students are required to take for credit a total of 24 semester units of courses in the department numbered 204-272 inclusive. A member of the PhD Program Committee may consent to substitute courses at a comparable level in other disciplines for some of these departmental graduate courses. In addition, the committee member may waive part of this unit requirement.</span></p>
<h4 class="Normal1">Qualifying Examination</h4>
<p>The qualifying examination is intended to determine whether students are ready to enter the research phase and are on track toward successfully completing the PhD. It consists of a 50-minute lecture by the student on a topic selected jointly by the student and the thesis adviser. The topic usually involves the student's research. </p>
<h3>Time in Candidacy </h3>
<h4 class="Normal1">Advancement </h4>
<p class="Normal1">Advancing to candidacy means a student is ready to write a doctoral dissertation. Students must apply for advancement to candidacy once they have successfully passed the qualifying examination. </p>
<h4 class="Normal1">Dissertation Presentation/Finishing Talk</h4>
<p class="Normal1">The Ph.D. degree is granted upon completion of an original thesis acceptable to a committee of at least three faculty members. The majority or at least half of the committee must consist of faculty from Statistics and must be members of the Academic Senate. The thesis should be presented at an appropriate seminar in the department prior to filing</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Required Professional Development</h3>
<p>Students enrolled in the graduate program before fall 2016 are required to serve as a <a href="http://statistics.berkeley.edu/employment/gsi-and-reader" target="_blank">Graduate Student Instructor</a> (GSI) for a minimum of 20 hours (equivalent to a 50% GSI appointment) during a regular academic semester by the end of their third year in the program.</p>
<p>Effective with the fall 2016 entering class, students are required to serve as a <a href="http://statistics.berkeley.edu/employment/gsi-and-reader" target="_blank">Graduate Student Instructor</a> (GSI) for a minimum of two regular academic semesters and complete at least 40 hours prior to graduation (20 hours is equivalent to a 50% GSI appointment for a semester) for a course numbered 150 and above.</p>
]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<mastersdegreerequirementstext name="Master's Degree Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Unit Requirements</h3>
<p class="Normal1">In order to obtain the MA in Statistics, admitted MA students must complete a minimum of 24 units of courses and pass a comprehensive examination.</p>
<p class="Normal1">In extremely rare cases, a thesis option may be considered by the MA advisers. Typically, this will be when either the option has been offered to the student at the time of admission, or if the student arrives with substantial progress in research in an area of interest to our faculty. </p>
<h3>Curriculum</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Courses Required</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 201A">STAT 201A</span></td><td>Introduction to Probability at an Advanced Level</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 201B">STAT 201B</span></td><td>Introduction to Statistics at an Advanced Level</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 243">STAT 243</span></td><td>Introduction to Statistical Computing</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 230A">STAT 230A</span></td><td>Linear Models</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 222">STAT 222</span></td><td>Masters of Statistics Capstone Project</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Elective</span></td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p class="Normal1">The capstone will consist of a team-based learning experience that will give students the opportunity to work on a real-world problem and carry out a substantial data analysis project. It will culminate with a written report and an oral presentation of findings. The elective will depend on the student’s interests and will be decided in consultation with advisers.</p>
<h4 class="Normal1">Capstone/Thesis (Plan I)</h4>
<p class="Normal1">If approved for the thesis option, you must find three faculty to be on your thesis committee. Though not required, it is strongly encouraged that one of the faculty members is from outside the Statistics Department. Both you and the thesis committee chair must agree on the topic of your thesis. Further information on how to file a thesis is available on the <a href="http://statistics.berkeley.edu/programs/graduate/masters">MA program web page</a>. </p>
<h4 class="Normal1">Capstone/Comprehensive Exam (Plan II) </h4>
<p class="Normal1">On a Saturday shortly after the spring semester begins in January, students will take a comprehensive exam on the theoretical foundations of statistics. <span id="docs-internal-guid-5a6d8d54-7fff-4b52-de98-4734d8ec9609">There will be a 3-hour exam on the material of</span> <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 201A">STAT 201A</span></span> and <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 201B">STAT 201B</span></span>. All students taking the exam will receive copies of previous examinations. </p>
]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Statistics</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat200a" data-toggle="#cb_stat200a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 200A</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Probability and Statistics at an Advanced Level</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat200a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2011, Fall 2010<br/>
Probability spaces, random variables, distributions in probability and statistics, central limit theorem, Poisson processes, transformations involving random variables, estimation, confidence intervals, hypothesis testing, linear models, large sample theory, categorical models, decision theory.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Probability and Statistics at an Advanced Level:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="360" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Multivariable calculus and one semester of linear algebra</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for Statistics 200A after completing Statistics 201A-201B.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Probability and Statistics at an Advanced Level:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat200b" data-toggle="#cb_stat200b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 200B</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Probability and Statistics at an Advanced Level</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat200b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2019, Spring 2012, Spring 2011<br/>
Probability spaces, random variables, distributions in probability and statistics, central limit theorem, Poisson processes, transformations involving random variables, estimation, confidence intervals, hypothesis testing, linear models, large sample theory, categorical models, decision theory.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Probability and Statistics at an Advanced Level:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="749" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Multivariable calculus and one semester of linear algebra</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for Statistics 200A-200B after completing Statistics 201A-201B.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Probability and Statistics at an Advanced Level:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc200c" data-toggle="#cb_statc200c">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C200C</span> 
<span class="title">Principles and Techniques of Data Science</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc200c">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Spring 2020<br/>
Explores the data science lifecycle: question formulation, data collection and cleaning, exploratory, analysis, visualization, statistical inference, prediction, and decision-making. Focuses on quantitative critical thinking and key principles and techniques: languages for transforming, querying and analyzing data; algorithms for machine learning methods: regression, classification and clustering; principles</span><span class="deschide"> of informative visualization; measurement error and prediction; and techniques for scalable data processing. Research term project.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Principles and Techniques of Data Science:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="844" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI C8">COMPSCI C8</span> / <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="INFO C8">INFO C8</span> / <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT C8">STAT C8</span> or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENGIN 7">ENGIN 7</span>; and either <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI 61A">COMPSCI 61A</span> or COMPSCI 88. Corequisites: <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MATH 54">MATH 54</span> or <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EECS 16A">EECS 16A</span></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DATA C200">DATA C200</span>\<span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="COMPSCI C200A">COMPSCI C200A</span>\<span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT C200C">STAT C200C</span> after completing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="DATA C100">DATA C100</span>.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 6 hours of lecture, 2 hours of discussion, and 2 hours of laboratory per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture, 1 hour of discussion, and 1 hour of laboratory per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 6 hours of lecture, 2 hours of discussion, and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one hour of discussion and one hour of laboratory per week. Six hours of lecture and two hours of discussion and two hours of laboratory per week for 8 weeks. Six hours of lecture and two hours of discussion and two hours of laboratory per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Statistics C200C/Computer Science C200A</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> COMPSCI C200A/DATA C200</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Principles and Techniques of Data Science:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat201a" data-toggle="#cb_stat201a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 201A</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Probability at an Advanced Level</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat201a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Distributions in probability and statistics, central limit theorem, Poisson processes, modes of convergence, transformations involving random variables.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Probability at an Advanced Level:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="90" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Undergraduate probability at the level of Statistics 134, multivariable calculus (at the level of Berkeley’s Mathematics 53) and linear algebra (at the level of Berkeley’s Mathematics 54)</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 201A">STAT 201A</span> after completing <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 200A">STAT 200A</span>.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Probability at an Advanced Level:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat201b" data-toggle="#cb_stat201b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 201B</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Statistics at an Advanced Level</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat201b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Estimation, confidence intervals, hypothesis testing, linear models, large sample theory, categorical models, decision theory.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Statistics at an Advanced Level:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="285" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Undergraduate probability at the level of Statistics 134, multivariable calculus (at the level of Berkeley’s Mathematics 53) and linear algebra (at the level of Berkeley’s Mathematics 54)</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for Statistics 201B after completing Statistics 200B.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Statistics at an Advanced Level:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat204" data-toggle="#cb_stat204">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 204</span> 
<span class="title">Probability for Applications</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat204">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2019, Spring 2017<br/>
A treatment of ideas and techniques most commonly found in the applications of probability: Gaussian and Poisson processes, limit theorems, large deviation principles, information, Markov chains and Markov chain Monte Carlo, martingales, Brownian motion and diffusion.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Probability for Applications:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="95" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for Statistics 204 after completing Statistics 205A-205B.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Evans</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Probability for Applications:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc205a" data-toggle="#cb_statc205a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C205A</span> 
<span class="title">Probability Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc205a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021, Fall 2019<br/>
The course is designed as a sequence with Statistics C205B/Mathematics C218B with the following combined syllabus. Measure theory concepts needed for probability. Expection, distributions. Laws of large numbers and central limit theorems for independent random variables. Characteristic function methods. Conditional expectations, martingales and martingale convergence theorems. Markov chains. Stationary processes. Brownian motion.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Probability Theory:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="682" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> MATH C218A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Probability Theory:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc205b" data-toggle="#cb_statc205b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C205B</span> 
<span class="title">Probability Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc205b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
The course is designed as a sequence with with Statistics C205A/Mathematics C218A with the following combined syllabus. Measure theory concepts needed for probability. Expection, distributions. Laws of large numbers and central limit theorems for independent random variables. Characteristic function methods. Conditional expectations, martingales and martingale convergence theorems. Markov chains. Stationary processes. Brownian motion.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Probability Theory:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="171" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> MATH C218B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Probability Theory:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc206a" data-toggle="#cb_statc206a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C206A</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Topics in Probability and Stochastic Process</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc206a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2020, Fall 2016, Fall 2015, Fall 2014<br/>
The topics of this course change each semester, and multiple sections may be offered. Advanced topics in probability offered according to students demand and faculty availability.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Topics in Probability and Stochastic Process:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="52" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics C205A-C205B or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> MATH C223A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Topics in Probability and Stochastic Process:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc206b" data-toggle="#cb_statc206b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C206B</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Topics in Probability and Stochastic Processes</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc206b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
The topics of this course change each semester, and multiple sections may be offered. Advanced topics in probability offered according to students demand and faculty availability.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Topics in Probability and Stochastic Processes:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="368" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> MATH C223B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Topics in Probability and Stochastic Processes:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat210a" data-toggle="#cb_stat210a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 210A</span> 
<span class="title">Theoretical Statistics</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat210a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
An introduction to mathematical statistics, covering both frequentist and Bayesian aspects of modeling, inference, and decision-making. Topics include statistical decision theory; point estimation; minimax and admissibility; Bayesian methods; exponential families; hypothesis testing; confidence intervals; small and large sample theory; and M-estimation.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="122" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Linear algebra, real analysis, and a year of upper division probability and statistics</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat210b" data-toggle="#cb_stat210b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 210B</span> 
<span class="title">Theoretical Statistics</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat210b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Introduction to modern theory of statistics; empirical processes, influence functions, M-estimation, U and V statistics and associated stochastic decompositions; non-parametric function estimation and associated minimax theory; semiparametric models; Monte Carlo methods and bootstrap methods; distributionfree and equivariant procedures; topics in machine learning. Topics covered may vary with instructor.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="450" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 210A and a graduate level probability course; a good understanding of various notions of stochastic convergence</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat212a" data-toggle="#cb_stat212a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 212A</span> 
<span class="title">Topics in Theoretical Statistics</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat212a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2021, Fall 2015, Fall 2012<br/>
This course introduces the student to topics of current research interest in theoretical statistics. Recent topics include information theory, multivariate analysis and random matrix theory, high-dimensional inference. Typical topics have been model selection; empirical and point processes; the bootstrap, stochastic search, and Monte Carlo integration; information theory and statistics; semi- and non-parametric modeling; time series and survival</span><span class="deschide"> analysis.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Topics in Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="87" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 210 or 205 and 215</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 216A-216B and 217A-217B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Topics in Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat212b" data-toggle="#cb_stat212b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 212B</span> 
<span class="title">Topics in Theoretical Statistics</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat212b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2016<br/>
This course introduces the student to topics of current research interest in theoretical statistics. Recent topics include information theory, multivariate analysis and random matrix theory, high-dimensional inference. Typical topics have been model selection; empirical and point processes; the bootstrap, stochastic search, and Monte Carlo integration; information theory and statistics; semi- and non-parametric modeling; time series and survival analysis.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Topics in Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="903" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 210 or 205 and 215</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 216A-216B and 217A-217B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Topics in Theoretical Statistics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat215a" data-toggle="#cb_stat215a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 215A</span> 
<span class="title">Statistical Models: Theory and Application</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat215a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Applied statistics with a focus on critical thinking, reasoning skills, and techniques. Hands-on-experience with solving real data problems with high-level programming languages such as R. Emphasis on examining the assumptions behind standard statistical models and methods. Exploratory data analysis (e.g., graphical data summaries, PCAs, clustering analysis). Model formulation, fitting, and validation and testing. Linear regression and generalizations</span><span class="deschide"> (e.g., GLMs, ridge regression, lasso).</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistical Models: Theory and Application:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="671" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Linear algebra, calculus, upper division probability and statistics, and familiarity with high-level programming languages. Statistics 133, 134, and 135 recommended</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistical Models: Theory and Application:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat215b" data-toggle="#cb_stat215b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 215B</span> 
<span class="title">Statistical Models: Theory and Application</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat215b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Course builds on 215A in developing critical thinking skills and the techniques of advanced applied statistics. Particular topics vary with instructor. Examples of possible topics include planning and design of experiments, ANOVA and random effects models, splines, classification, spatial statistics, categorical data analysis, survival analysis, and multivariate analysis.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistical Models: Theory and Application:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="956" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 215A or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistical Models: Theory and Application:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat222" data-toggle="#cb_stat222">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 222</span> 
<span class="title">Masters of Statistics Capstone Project</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat222">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
The capstone project is part of the masters degree program in statistics. Students engage in professionally-oriented group research under the supervision of a research advisor. The research synthesizes the statistical, computational, economic, and social issues involved in solving complex real-world problems.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Masters of Statistics Capstone Project:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="552" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 201A-201B, 243. Restricted to students who have been admitted to the one-year Masters Program in Statistics beginning fall 2012 or later</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar and 1 hour of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of laboratory and three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Masters of Statistics Capstone Project:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat230a" data-toggle="#cb_stat230a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 230A</span> 
<span class="title">Linear Models</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat230a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Theory of least squares estimation, interval estimation, and tests under the general linear fixed effects model with normally distributed errors. Large sample theory for non-normal linear models. Two and higher way layouts, residual analysis. Effects of departures from the underlying assumptions. Robust alternatives to least squares.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Linear Models:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="262" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Matrix algebra, a year of calculus, two semesters of upper division or graduate probability and statistics</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Linear Models:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat232" data-toggle="#cb_stat232">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 232</span> 
<span class="title">Experimental Design</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat232">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Fall 2018<br/>
This course will review the statistical foundations of randomized experiments and study principles for addressing common setbacks in experimental design and analysis in practice. We will cover the notion of potential outcomes for causal inference and the Fisherian principles for experimentation (randomization, blocking, and replications). We will also cover experiments with complex structures (clustering in units, factorial design, hierarchy</span><span class="deschide"> in treatments, sequential assignment, etc). We will also address practical complications in experiments, including noncompliance, missing data, and measurement error.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Experimental Design:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="347" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 134 and Statistics 135 and experience with Software R, or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Experimental Design:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat238" data-toggle="#cb_stat238">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 238</span> 
<span class="title">Bayesian Statistics</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat238">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2016<br/>
Bayesian methods and concepts: conditional probability, one-parameter and multiparameter models, prior distributions, hierarchical and multi-level models, predictive checking and sensitivity analysis, model selection, linear and generalized linear models, multiple testing and high-dimensional data, mixtures, non-parametric methods. Case studies of applied modeling. In-depth computational implementation using Markov chain Monte Carlo and other techniques. Basic theory</span><span class="deschide"> for Bayesian methods and decision theory. The selection of topics may vary from year to year.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Bayesian Statistics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="175" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> develop Bayesian models for new types of data<br/>implement Bayesian models and interpret the results<br/>read and discuss Bayesian methods in the literature<br/>select and build appropriate Bayesian models for data to answer research questions<br/>understand and describe the Bayesian perspective and its advantages and disadvantages compared to classical methods</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Probability and mathematical statistics at the level of Stat 134 and Stat 135 or, ideally, Stat 201A and Stat 201B</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one hour of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Bayesian Statistics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat239a" data-toggle="#cb_stat239a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 239A</span> 
<span class="title">The Statistics of Causal Inference in the Social Science</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat239a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2015, Fall 2014<br/>
Approaches to causal inference using the potential outcomes framework. Covers observational studies with and without ignorable treatment assignment, randomized experiments with and without noncompliance, instrumental variables, regression discontinuity, sensitivity analysis and randomization inference. Applications are drawn from a variety of fields including political science, economics, sociology, public health and medicine.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Statistics of Causal Inference in the Social Science:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="690" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> At least one graduate matrix based multivariate regression course in addition to introductory statistics and probability</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of lecture and 1-2 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one to two hours of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. This is part one of a year long series course. A provisional grade of IP (in progress) will be applied and later replaced with the final grade after completing part two of the series. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Sekhon</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Statistics of Causal Inference in the Social Science:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat239b" data-toggle="#cb_stat239b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 239B</span> 
<span class="title">Quantitative Methodology in the Social Sciences Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat239b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2016, Spring 2015<br/>
A seminar on successful research designs and a forum for students to discuss the research methods needed in their own work, supplemented by lectures on relevant statistical and computational topics such as matching methods, instrumental variables, regression discontinuity, and Bayesian, maximum likelihood and robust estimation. Applications are drawn from political science, economics, sociology, and public health. Experience with R is assumed.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Quantitative Methodology in the Social Sciences Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="18" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 239A or equivalent</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of lecture and 1-2 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one to two hours of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. This is part two of a year long series course. Upon completion, the final grade will be applied to both parts of the series. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Quantitative Methodology in the Social Sciences Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc239a" data-toggle="#cb_statc239a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C239A</span> 
<span class="title">The Statistics of Causal Inference in the Social Science</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc239a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Approaches to causal inference using the potential outcomes framework. Covers observational studies with and without ignorable treatment assignment, randomized experiments with and without noncompliance, instrumental variables, regression discontinuity, sensitivity analysis and randomization inference. Applications are drawn from a variety of fields including political science, economics, sociology, public health and medicine.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>The Statistics of Causal Inference in the Social Science:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="36" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> POL SCI C236A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>The Statistics of Causal Inference in the Social Science:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc239b" data-toggle="#cb_statc239b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C239B</span> 
<span class="title">Quantitative Methodology in the Social Sciences Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc239b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017<br/>
A seminar on successful research designs and a forum for students to discuss the research methods needed in their own work, supplemented by lectures on relevant statistical and computational topics such as matching methods, instrumental variables, regression discontinuity, and Bayesian, maximum likelihood and robust estimation. Applications are drawn from political science, economics, sociology, and public health. Experience with R is assumed.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Quantitative Methodology in the Social Sciences Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="674" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> POL SCI C236B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Quantitative Methodology in the Social Sciences Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat240" data-toggle="#cb_stat240">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 240</span> 
<span class="title">Nonparametric and Robust Methods</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat240">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2021, Fall 2017<br/>
Standard nonparametric tests and confidence intervals for continuous and categorical data; nonparametric estimation of quantiles; robust estimation of location and scale parameters. Efficiency comparison with the classical procedures.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Nonparametric and Robust Methods:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="396" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> A year of upper division probability and statistics</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Nonparametric and Robust Methods:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc241a" data-toggle="#cb_statc241a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C241A</span> 
<span class="title">Statistical Learning Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc241a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2021, Fall 2020<br/>
Classification regression, clustering, dimensionality, reduction, and density estimation. Mixture models, hierarchical models, factorial models, hidden Markov, and state space models, Markov properties, and recursive algorithms for general probabilistic inference nonparametric methods including decision trees, kernal methods, neural networks, and wavelets. Ensemble methods.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistical Learning Theory:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="731" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Bartlett, Jordan, Wainwright</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> COMPSCI C281A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistical Learning Theory:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc241b" data-toggle="#cb_statc241b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C241B</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Topics in Learning and Decision Making</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc241b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2017<br/>
Recent topics include: Graphical models and approximate inference algorithms. Markov chain Monte Carlo, mean field and probability propagation methods. Model selection and stochastic realization. Bayesian information theoretic and structural risk minimization approaches. Markov decision processes and partially observable Markov decision processes. Reinforcement learning.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Topics in Learning and Decision Making:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="980" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Bartlett, Jordan, Wainwright</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> COMPSCI C281B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Topics in Learning and Decision Making:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat243" data-toggle="#cb_stat243">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 243</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Statistical Computing</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat243">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Concepts in statistical programming and statistical computation, including programming principles, data and text manipulation, parallel processing, simulation, numerical linear algebra, and optimization.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Statistical Computing:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="158" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Student Learning Outcomes:</strong> Become familiar with concepts and tools for reproducible research and good scientific computing practices.<br/>
Operate effectively in a UNIX environment and on remote servers.<br/>
Program effectively in languages including R and Python with an advanced knowledge of language functionality and an understanding of general programming concepts.<br/>
Understand in depth and make use of principles of numerical linear algebra, optimization, and simulation for statistics-related research.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Statistical Computing:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat244" data-toggle="#cb_stat244">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 244</span> 
<span class="title">Statistical Computing</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat244">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2011, Spring 2010, Spring 2009<br/>
Algorithms in statistical computing: random number generation, generating other distributions, random sampling and permutations. Matrix computations in linear models. Non-linear optimization with applications to statistical procedures. Other topics of current interest, such as issues of efficiency, and use of graphics.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistical Computing:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="372" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Knowledge of a higher level programming language</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistical Computing:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc245a" data-toggle="#cb_statc245a">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C245A</span> 
<span class="title">Introduction to Modern Biostatistical Theory and Practice</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc245a">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
Course covers major topics in general statistical theory, with a focus on statistical methods in epidemiology. The course provides a broad theoretical framework for understanding the properties of commonly-used and more advanced methods. Emphasis is on estimation in nonparametric models in the context of contingency tables, regression (e.g., linear, logistic), density estimation and more. Topics include maximum likelihood and loss-based estimation</span><span class="deschide">, asymptotic linearity/normality, the delta method, bootstrapping, machine learning, targeted maximum likelihood estimation. Comprehension of broad concepts is the main goal, but practical implementation in R is also emphasized. Basic knowledge of probability/statistics and calculus are assume</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Introduction to Modern Biostatistical Theory and Practice:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="609" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 200A (may be taken concurrently)</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Hubbard</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> PB HLTH C240A</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Introduction to Modern Biostatistical Theory and Practice:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc245b" data-toggle="#cb_statc245b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C245B</span> 
<span class="title">Biostatistical Methods: Survival Analysis and Causality</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc245b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021, Fall 2020<br/>
Analysis of survival time data using parametric and non-parametric models, hypothesis testing, and methods for analyzing censored (partially observed) data with covariates. Topics include marginal estimation of a survival function, estimation of a generalized multivariate linear regression model (allowing missing covariates and/or outcomes), estimation of a multiplicative intensity model (such as Cox proportional hazards model) and estimation</span><span class="deschide"> of causal parameters assuming marginal structural models. General theory for developing locally efficient estimators of the parameters of interest in censored data models. Computing techniques, numerical methods, simulation and general implementation of biostatistical analysis techniques with emphasis on data applications.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Biostatistical Methods: Survival Analysis and Causality:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="207" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 200B (may be taken concurrently)</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> van der Laan</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> PB HLTH C240B</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Biostatistical Methods: Survival Analysis and Causality:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc245c" data-toggle="#cb_statc245c">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C245C</span> 
<span class="title">Biostatistical Methods: Computational Statistics with Applications in Biology and Medicine</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc245c">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021, Fall 2020<br/>
This course provides an introduction to computational statistics, with emphasis on statistical methods and software for addressing high-dimensional inference problems in biology and medicine. Topics include numerical and graphical data summaries, loss-based estimation (regression, classification, density estimation), smoothing, EM algorithm, Markov chain Monte-Carlo, clustering, multiple testing, resampling, hidden Markov models, in</span><span class="deschide"> silico experiments.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Biostatistical Methods: Computational Statistics with Applications in Biology and Medicine:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="238" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 200A or equivalent (may be taken concurrently)</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Dudoit</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> PB HLTH C240C</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Biostatistical Methods: Computational Statistics with Applications in Biology and Medicine:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc245d" data-toggle="#cb_statc245d">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C245D</span> 
<span class="title">Biostatistical Methods: Computational Statistics with Applications in Biology and Medicine II</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc245d">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2017, Fall 2015, Fall 2013<br/>
This course and Pb Hlth C240C/Stat C245C provide an introduction to computational statistics with emphasis on statistical methods and software for addressing high-dimensional inference problems that arise in current biological and medical research. The courses also discusses statistical computing resources, with emphasis on the R language and environment (www.r-project.org). Programming topics to be discussed include: data structures, functions</span><span class="deschide">, statistical models, graphical procedures, designing an R package, object-oriented programming, inter-system interfaces. The statistical and computational methods are motivated by and illustrated on data structures that arise in current high-dimensional inference problems in biology and medicine.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Biostatistical Methods: Computational Statistics with Applications in Biology and Medicine II:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="921" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 200A-200B or Statistics 201A-201B (may be taken concurrently) or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Dudoit</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> PB HLTH C240D</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Biostatistical Methods: Computational Statistics with Applications in Biology and Medicine II:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc245e" data-toggle="#cb_statc245e">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C245E</span> 
<span class="title">Statistical Genomics</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc245e">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2013, Fall 2012, Fall 2010, Fall 2009<br/>
Genomics is one of the fundamental areas of research in the biological sciences and is rapidly becoming one of the most important application areas in statistics. This is the first course of a two-semester sequence, which provides an introduction to statistical and computational methods for the analysis of meiosis, population genetics, and genetic mapping. The second course is Statistics C245F/Public Health C240F. The courses are primarily</span><span class="deschide"> intended for graduate students and advanced undergraduate students from the mathematical sciences.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistical Genomics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="87" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 200A and 200B or equivalent (may be taken concurrently). A course in algorithms and knowledge of at least one computing language (e.g., R, matlab) is recommended</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and One hour of Discussion per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Dudoit, Huang, Nielsen, Song</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> PB HLTH C240E</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistical Genomics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc245f" data-toggle="#cb_statc245f">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C245F</span> 
<span class="title">Statistical Genomics</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc245f">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Spring 2020, Spring 2018, Spring 2017<br/>
Genomics is one of the fundamental areas of research in the biological sciences and is rapidly becoming one of the most important application areas in statistics. The first course in this two-semester sequence is Public Health C240E/Statistics C245E. This is the second course, which focuses on sequence analysis, phylogenetics, and high-throughput microarray and sequencing gene expression experiments. The courses</span><span class="deschide"> are primarily intended for graduate students and advanced undergraduate students from the mathematical sciences.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistical Genomics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="144" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and one hour of discussion per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Dudoit, Huang, Nielsen, Song</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> PB HLTH C240F</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistical Genomics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc247c" data-toggle="#cb_statc247c">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C247C</span> 
<span class="title">Longitudinal Data Analysis</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc247c">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2021, Fall 2019<br/>
Course covers statistical issues surrounding estimation of effects using data on units followed through time. Course emphasizes a regression model approach for estimating associations of disease incidence modeling, continuous outcome data/linear models &amp; longitudinal extensions to nonlinear models forms (e.g., logistic). Course emphasizes complexities that repeated measures has on the estimation process &amp; opportunities it provides if data</span><span class="deschide"> is modeled appropriately. Most time is spent on 2 approaches: mixed models based upon explicit (latent variable) maximum likelihood estimation of the sources of the dependence, versus empirical estimating equation approaches (generalized estimating equations). Primary focus is from the analysis side.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Longitudinal Data Analysis:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="407" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p><p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> After successfully completing the course, you will be able to:<br/>
•<br/>
frame data science questions relevant to longitudinal studies as the estimation of statistical parameters generated from regression,<br/>
<br/>•<br/>
derive consistent statistical inference in the presence of correlated, repeated measures data using likelihood-based mixed models and estimating equation approaches (generalized estimating equations; GEE),<br/>•<br/>
implement the relevant methods using R.<br/>•<br/>
interpret the regression output, including both coefficients and variance components and</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 142, 145, 241 or equivalent courses in basic statistics, linear and logistic regression</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Hubbard</p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> PB HLTH C242C</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Longitudinal Data Analysis:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat248" data-toggle="#cb_stat248">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 248</span> 
<span class="title">Analysis of Time Series</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat248">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Spring 2020<br/>
Frequency-based techniques of time series analysis, spectral theory, linear filters, estimation of spectra, estimation of transfer functions, design, system identification, vector-valued stationary processes, model building.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Analysis of Time Series:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="883" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 102 or equivalent</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture and Two hours of Laboratory per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Analysis of Time Series:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat251" data-toggle="#cb_stat251">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 251</span> 
<span class="title">Stochastic Analysis with Applications to Mathematical Finance</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat251">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2008, Spring 2006, Spring 2005<br/>
The essentials of stochastic analysis, particularly those most relevant to financial engineering, will be surveyed: Brownian motion, stochastic integrals, Ito's formula, representation of martingales, Girsanov's theorem, stochastic differential equations, and diffusion processes. Examples will be taken from the Black-Scholes-Merton theory of pricing and hedging contingent claims such as options, foreign market derivatives, and interest rate</span><span class="deschide"> related contracts.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Stochastic Analysis with Applications to Mathematical Finance:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="419" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 205A or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Stochastic Analysis with Applications to Mathematical Finance:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat254" data-toggle="#cb_stat254">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 254</span> 
<span class="title">Modern Statistical Prediction and Machine Learning</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat254">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023<br/>
This course is about statistical learning methods and their use for data analysis. Upon completion, students will be able to build baseline models for real world data analysis problems, implement models using programming languages and draw conclusions from models. The course will cover principled statistical methodology for basic machine learning tasks such as regression, classification, dimension reduction and clustering. Methods discussed will include</span><span class="deschide"> linear regression, subset selection, ridge regression, LASSO, logistic regression, kernel smoothing methods, tree based methods, bagging and boosting, neural networks, Bayesian methods, as well as inference techniques based on resampling, cross validation and sample splitting.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Modern Statistical Prediction and Machine Learning:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="399" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> <span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="STAT 135">STAT 135</span>, the combination of DATA/STAT/COMPSCI C100 and DATA/STAT C140, or equivalent</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Modern Statistical Prediction and Machine Learning:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat256" data-toggle="#cb_stat256">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 256</span> 
<span class="title">Causal Inference</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat256">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
This course will focus on approaches to causal inference using the potential outcomes framework. It will also use causal diagrams at an intuitive level. The main topics are classical randomized experiments, observational studies, instrumental variables, principal stratification and mediation analysis. Applications are drawn from a variety of fields including political science, economics, sociology, public health, and medicine. This course is a</span><span class="deschide"> mix of statistical theory and data analysis. Students will be exposed to statistical questions that are relevant to decision and policy making.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Causal Inference:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="401" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 201B or Statistics 210A</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Causal Inference:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat259" data-toggle="#cb_stat259">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 259</span> 
<span class="title">Reproducible and Collaborative Statistical Data Science</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat259">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Spring 2021<br/>
A project-based introduction to statistical data analysis. Through case studies, computer laboratories, and a term project, students will learn practical techniques and tools for producing statistically sound and appropriate, reproducible, and verifiable computational answers to scientific questions. Course emphasizes version control, testing, process automation, code review, and collaborative programming. Software tools may include Bash</span><span class="deschide">, Git, Python, and LaTeX.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Reproducible and Collaborative Statistical Data Science:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="502" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Statistics 133, Statistics 134, and Statistics 135 (or equivalent)</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for Statistics 259 after taking Statistics 159.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of lecture and two hours of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Reproducible and Collaborative Statistical Data Science:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat260" data-toggle="#cb_stat260">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 260</span> 
<span class="title">Topics in Probability and Statistics</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat260">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2023, Spring 2022, Fall 2021<br/>
Special topics in probability and statistics offered according to student demand and faculty availability.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Topics in Probability and Statistics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="202" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Topics in Probability and Statistics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_statc261" data-toggle="#cb_statc261">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT C261</span> 
<span class="title">Quantitative/Statistical Research Methods in Social Sciences</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_statc261">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Spring 2016, Spring 2015, Spring 2014<br/>
Selected topics in quantitative/statistical methods of research in the social sciences and particularly in sociology. Possible topics include: analysis of qualitative/categorical data; loglinear models and latent-structure analysis; the analysis of cross-classified data having ordered and unordered categories; measure, models, and graphical displays in the analysis of cross-classified data; correspondence analysis, association analysis, and</span><span class="deschide"> related methods of data analysis.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Quantitative/Statistical Research Methods in Social Sciences:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="700" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of Lecture per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> SOCIOL C271D</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Quantitative/Statistical Research Methods in Social Sciences:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat272" data-toggle="#cb_stat272">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 272</span> 
<span class="title">Statistical Consulting</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat272">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Fall 2022, Spring 2022<br/>
To be taken concurrently with service as a consultant in the department's drop-in consulting service. Participants will work on problems arising in the service and will discuss general ways of handling such problems. There will be working sessions with researchers in substantive fields and occasional lectures on consulting.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistical Consulting:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="373" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Some course work in applied statistics and permission of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of session per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two hours of session per week and individual meetings as necessary.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistical Consulting:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat278b" data-toggle="#cb_stat278b">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 278B</span> 
<span class="title">Statistics Research Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat278b">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Special topics, by means of lectures and informational conferences.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistics Research Seminar:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="8" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two or more hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistics Research Seminar:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat298" data-toggle="#cb_stat298">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 298</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Study for Graduate Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat298">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Special tutorial or seminar on selected topics.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Directed Study for Graduate Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="652" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 1-16 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Zero hours of Independent study per week for 15 weeks. One to Twelve hour of Independent study per week for 8 weeks. One to Sixteen hour of Independent study per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Directed Study for Graduate Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat299" data-toggle="#cb_stat299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study Leading to Higher Degrees</span> 
<span class="hours">0.5 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Individual study</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study Leading to Higher Degrees:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="314" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-36 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 4-45 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 3-36 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>10 weeks - 2.5-27 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Work hours to be arrange based on unit value. Offered for 1-6 units during Summer Session.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study Leading to Higher Degrees:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat375" data-toggle="#cb_stat375">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 375</span> 
<span class="title">Professional Preparation: Teaching of Probability and Statistics</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat375">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Discussion, problem review and development, guidance of laboratory classes, course development, supervised practice teaching.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Professional Preparation: Teaching of Probability and Statistics:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="92" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and appointment as a graduate student instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of lecture and 4 hours of laboratory per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One or two hours of lecture and two to four of laboratory per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Statistics 300</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Professional Preparation: Teaching of Probability and Statistics:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat601" data-toggle="#cb_stat601">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 601</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study for Master's Candidates</span> 
<span class="hours">0.5 - 8 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat601">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the graduate adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the master's comprehensive examinations. Units may not be used to meet either unit or residence requirements for a master's degree.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study for Master's Candidates:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="537" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit up to a total of 16 units.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0.5-8 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 1.5-20 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1-15 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>10 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One-half to eight hours of independent study per week. One to twelve hours of independent study per week for 10 weeks. One to fifteen hours of independent study per week for 8 weeks. One and one-half to twenty hours of independent study per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate examination preparation</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study for Master's Candidates:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat602" data-toggle="#cb_stat602">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 602</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Candidates</span> 
<span class="hours">0.5 - 8 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat602">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2023, Spring 2023, Fall 2022<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the graduate adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for certain examinations required of candidates for the Ph.D. degree.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study for Doctoral Candidates:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="360" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> One year of full-time graduate study and permission of the graduate adviser</p><p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Course does not satisfy unit or residence requirements for doctoral degree.</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit up to a total of 16 units.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0.5-8 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>6 weeks - 1.5-20 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>8 weeks - 1-15 hours of independent study per week<br/><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"/>10 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One-half to eight hours of independent study per week. One to twelve hours of independent study per week for 10 weeks. One to fifteen hours of independent study per week for 8 weeks. One and one-half to twenty hours of independent study per week for 6 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate examination preparation</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study for Doctoral Candidates:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_stat700" data-toggle="#cb_stat700">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">STAT 700</span> 
<span class="title">Statistics Colloquium</span> 
<span class="hours">0.0 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_stat700">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
The Statistics Colloquium is a forum for talks on the theory and applications of Statistics to be given to the faculty and graduate students of the Statistics Department and other interested parties.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Statistics Colloquium:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="788" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-2 hours of colloquium per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to two hours of colloquium per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Statistics/Graduate examination preparation</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> The grading option will be decided by the instructor when the class is offered. </p><p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Statistics 999</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Statistics Colloquium:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>* Ani Adhikari, <i>Teaching Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter L. Bartlett, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Statistics, machine learning, statistical learning theory, adaptive control.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14413"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andrew Bray, <i>Associate Teaching Professor</i>. </strong><br/><a href="https://statistics.berkeley.edu/people/andrew-bray"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Bentley Brown, <i>Assistant Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Applications in Biology and Medicine.</p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer Chayes, <i>Professor and Associate Provost and Dean, Division of Computing, Data Science, and Society</i>. </strong>Phase transitions in computer science, structural and dynamical properties of networks, graphons, machine learning, ethical decision making, climate change.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jennifer-chayes"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peng Ding, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical causal inference, missing data, Bayesian statistics, applied statistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/peng-ding"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sandrine Dudoit, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genomics, classification, statistical computing, biostatistics, cross-validation, density estimation, genetic mapping, high-throughput sequencing, loss-based estimation, microarray, model selection, multiple hypothesis testing, prediction, RNA-Seq.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14232"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Steven N. Evans, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Genetics, random matrices, superprocesses and other measure-valued processes, probability on algebraic structures -particularly local fields, applications of stochastic processes to biodemography, mathematical finance, phylogenetics and historical linguistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14291"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Avi Feller, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Applied statistics, theoretical statistics, Bayesian statistics, machine learning, statistics in social sciences.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/avi-feller"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Will Fithian, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Theoretical and Applied Statistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/will-fithian"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Shirshendu Ganguly, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Probability theory, statistical mechanics.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/shirshendu-ganguly"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Vadim Gorin, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Integrable probability, random matrices, asymptotic representation theory.<br/><a href="https://www.stat.berkeley.edu/~vadicgor/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Adityanand Guntuboyina, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Nonparametric and high-dimensional statistics, shape constrained statistical estimation, empirical processes, statistical information theory.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/adityanand-guntuboyina"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alan Hammond, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical mechanics.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/alan-hammond"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Erin Hartman, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Causal inference and survey design and analysis.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/erin-hartman"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Giles Hooker, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Data analysis for dynamical systems and differential equations, machine learning and data mining, functional data analysis.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/giles-hooker"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Haiyan Huang, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Applied statistics, functional genomics, translational bioinformatics, high dimensional and integrative genomic/genetic data analysis, network modeling, hierarchical multi-lable classification.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14871"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jiantao Jiao, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Artificial intelligence, control and intelligent systems and robotics, communications and networking.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jiantao-jiao"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael I. Jordan, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computer science, artificial intelligence, bioinformatics, statistics, machine learning, electrical engineering, applied statistics, optimization.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13970"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael William Mahoney, <i>Associate Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical Computing, Applications in the Physical and Environmental Sciences, Applications in the Social Sciences, High Dimensional Data Analysis, Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning .<br/><a href="https://statistics.berkeley.edu/people/michael-mahoney"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jon Mcauliffe, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Bioinformatics, machine learning, nonparametrics, convex optimization, statistical computing, prediction, supervised learning.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15334"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Song Mei, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Data science, statistics, machine learning.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/song-mei"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rasmus Nielsen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical and computational aspects of evolutionary theory and genetics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15178"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher Paciorek, <i>Adjunct Professor</i>. </strong>Environmental statistics, statistical computing, spatial statistics, Bayesian statistics.<br/><a href="https://statistics.berkeley.edu/people/christopher-paciorek"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fernando Perez, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>High-level languages, interactive and literate computing, and reproducible research.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/fernando-perez"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sam Pimentel, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Causal inference, health services & policy analysis, biostatistics, discrete optimization.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sam-pimentel"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Elizabeth Purdom, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Computational biology, bioinformatics, statistics, data analysis, sequencing, cancer genomics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14345"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Juliet Shaffer, <i>Teaching Professor Emerita</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alistair Sinclair, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Algorithms, applied probability, statistics, random walks, Markov chains, computational applications of randomness, Markov chain Monte Carlo, statistical physics, combinatorial optimization.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15454"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Yun Song, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Computational biology, population genomics, applied probability and statistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14178"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Philip B. Stark, <i>Distinguished Professor</i>. </strong>Astrophysics, law, statistics, litigation, causal inference, inverse problems, geophysics, elections, uncertainty quantification, educational technology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15490"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jacob Steinhardt, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Artificial intelligence, machine learning.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/jacob-steinhardt"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bernd Sturmfels, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Mathematics, combinatorics, computational algebraic geometry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15683"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ryan Tibshirani, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>High-dimensional statistics, nonparametric estimation, distribution-free inference, machine learning, convex optimization, numerical methods, tracking and forecasting epidemics.<br/><a href="https://statistics.berkeley.edu/people/ryan-tibshirani"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mark J. Van Der Laan, <i>Distinguished Professor</i>. </strong>Statistics, computational biology and genomics, censored data and survival analysis, medical research, inference in longitudinal studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15566"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martin Wainwright, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Statistical machine learning, High-dimensional statistics, information theory, Optimization and algorithms.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15701"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bin Yu, <i>Distinguished Professor</i>. </strong>Neuroscience, remote sensing, networks, statistical machine learning, high-dimensional inference, massive data problems, document summarization .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14282"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nikita Zhivotovskiy, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Mathematical statistics, probability, and learning theory.<br/><a href="https://statistics.berkeley.edu/people/nikita-zhivotovskiy"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Thomas Bengtsson, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Fletcher H. Ibser, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Eaman Jahani, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Adam R. Lucas, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Libor Pospisil, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gaston Sanchez Trujillo, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Shobhana Murali Stoyanov, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Visiting Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Benson Au, <i>Visiting Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Wooseok Ha, <i>Visiting Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Yan Shuo Tan, <i>Visiting Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>David Aldous, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Mathematical probability, applied probability, analysis of algorithms, phylogenetic trees, complex networks, random networks, entropy, spatial networks.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14271"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter J. Bickel, <i>Professor Emeritus &amp; Professor of the Graduate School</i>. </strong>Statistics, machine learning, semiparametric models, asymptotic theory, hidden Markov models, applications to molecular biology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13924"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David R. Brillinger, <i>Professor Emeritus &amp; Professor of the Graduate School</i>. </strong>Risk analysis, statistical methods, data analysis, animal and fish motion trajectories, statistical applications in engineering and science, sports statistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14352"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ching-Shui Cheng, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Statistics, statistical design of experiments, combinatorial problems, efficient experimental design.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14522"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nicholas P. Jewell, <i>Professor Emeritus &amp; Professor of the Graduate School</i>. </strong>AIDS, statistics, epidemiology, infectious diseases, Ebola Virus Disease, SARS, H1N1 influenza, adverse cardiovascular effects of pharmaceuticals, counting civilian casualties during conflicts.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14892"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael J. Klass, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Statistics, mathematics, probability theory, combinatorics independent random variables, iterated logarithm, tail probabilities, functions of sums.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14990"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Pressley W. Millar, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Statistics, Martingales, Markov processes, Gaussian processes, excursion theory, asymptotic statistical decision theory, nonparametrics, robustness, stochastic procedures, asymptotic minimas theory, bootstrap theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13971"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>* Deborah Nolan, <i>Professor Emerita</i>. </strong>Statistics, empirical process, high-dimensional modeling, technology in education.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14572"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James W. Pitman, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Fragmentation, statistics, mathematics, Brownian motion, distribution theory, path transformations, stochastic processes, local time, excursions, random trees, random partitions, processes of coalescence.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13987"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Roger A. Purves, <i>Senior Teaching Professor</i>. </strong>Statistics, foundations of probability, measurability.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15246"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John A. Rice, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Transportation, astronomy, statistics, functional data analysis, time series analysis.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/13988"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Terence P. Speed, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Genomics, statistics, genetics and molecular biology, protein sequences.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14262"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Aram Thomasian, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kenneth Wachter, <i>Professor Emeritus &amp; Professor of the Graduate School</i>. </strong>Mathematical demography stochastic models, simulation, biodemography, federal statistical system.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14563"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

