<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Haas School of Business</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Introduction to the College</h2>
<p>As the second-oldest business school in the United States, the Haas School of Business at the University of California, Berkeley is one of the world's leading producers of new ideas and knowledge in all areas of business.</p>
<p>At Haas, teamwork and collaboration are the hallmark of the undergraduate program. Entering the program in cohorts, students are members of a close-knit, supportive peer network. Through their diversity of ideas and backgrounds and shared experiences at Haas, they build bonds that will last a lifetime.</p>
<p>The Haas School of Business offers an outstanding business administration program to about 700 undergraduate students each year. Haas undergraduates study with faculty who are leading experts in their fields. The Haas Undergraduate Program gives students the knowledge and skills needed to embark in today’s business world.</p>
<p>The school’s mission is “to develop leaders who redefine how we do business.” The school’s distinctive culture is defined by four defining leadership principles:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Question the status quo</li>
	<li>Confidence without attitude</li>
	<li>Students always</li>
	<li>Beyond yourself</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/degree-programs/business-administration/" target="_blank">Explore the undergraduate major</a> available through the Haas School of Business.</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<ucandcampusrequirementstext name="UC and Campus Requirements">
<![CDATA[
 <h3>University of California Requirements</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">Entry Level Writing</a></p> <p>All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by satisfying the Entry Level Writing Requirement (ELWR). <span style="font-size:1em">The </span><a href="https://admission.universityofcalifornia.edu/elwr/requirements/test-scores-grades.html" style="font-size: 1em;">UC Entry Level Writing Requirement website</a><span style="font-size:1em"> provides information on how to satisfy the requirement</span></p> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American History and American Institutions</a></p> <p>The American History and Institutions (AH&amp;I) requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</p> <h3>Campus Requirement</h3> <p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/education/#earningyourdegreetext" target="_blank">American Cultures</a></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-c47924ad-7fff-1b30-99f8-3c345cb2b997">The American Cultures requirement is a Berkeley campus requirement, one that all undergraduate students at Berkeley need to pass in order to graduate. You satisfy the requirement by passing, with a grade not lower than C- or P, an American Cultures course. You may take an American Cultures course any time during your undergraduate career at Berkeley. The requirement was instituted in 1991 to introduce students to the diverse cultures of the United States through a comparative framework. Courses are offered in more than fifty departments in many different disciplines at both the lower and upper division level.</span></p> <div> </div>
]]>
</ucandcampusrequirementstext>
<collegerequirementstext name="College Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>University of California Requirements</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/haas-business/entry-level-writing-requirement/" target="_blank">Entry Level Writing</a></p>
<p>All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by satisfying the Entry Level Writing Requirement. satisfaction of this requirement is also a prerequisite to enrollment in all reading and composition courses at UC Berkeley. </p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/haas-business/american-history-institutions-requirement/" target="_blank">American History and American Institutions</a></p>
<p>The American History and Institutions requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</p>
<h3>Campus Requirement</h3>
<p>The following campus requirements are prerequisites for admission to the undergraduate business major.</p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2022-23/undergraduate/colleges-schools/haas-business/american-cultures-requirement/" target="_blank">American Cultures</a></p>
<p>American Cultures (AC) is the one requirement that all undergraduate students at UC Berkeley need to take and pass in order to graduate. The requirement offers an exciting intellectual environment centered on the study of race, ethnicity, and culture of the United States. AC courses offer students opportunities to be part of research-led, highly accomplished teaching environments, grappling with the complexity of American culture.</p>
<h3>College Requirements</h3>
<p>The following are requirements for the Haas Undergraduate Program:</p>
<ul>
	<li>A minimum of 120 units</li>
	<li>Complete General University Requirements:
	<ul>
		<li>American History</li>
		<li>American Institutions</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>Berkeley campus requirement:
	<ul>
		<li>American Cultures</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>Completion of degree in four or eight semesters, not including summer session</li>
</ul>
<h3>Breadth Requirements</h3>
<p>The undergraduate breadth requirements provide Berkeley students with a rich and varied educational experience outside of their major program. As the foundation of a liberal arts education, breadth courses give students a view into the intellectual life of the University while introducing them to a multitude of perspectives and approaches to research and scholarship. Engaging students in new disciplines and with peers from other majors, the breadth experience strengthens interdisciplinary connections and context that prepares Berkeley graduates to understand and solve the complex issues of their day.</p>
<h4>Seven Course Breadth Requirement</h4>
<p>Students must successfully complete the seven course breadth sequence to earn a BS degree from the Haas School. Although breadth coursework is not required for admission, students are encouraged to spread breadth courses over 4 years.</p>
<ul>
	<li>Arts and Literature</li>
	<li>Biological Science</li>
	<li>Historical Studies</li>
	<li>International Studies</li>
	<li>Philosophy and Values</li>
	<li>Physical Science</li>
	<li>Social and Behavioral Sciences</li>
</ul>
<p>Haas students should adhere to the <a href="https://haas.berkeley.edu/undergrad/academics/courses/breadth-courses/" target="_blank">seven course breadth guidelines</a> outlined on the Haas Undergraduate website. </p>
<p>Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate credit will not satisfy the Seven Course Breadth requirement. A Level exams are accepted. Please <a href="http://haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/contact.html" target="_blank">contact</a> a Haas Adviser to determine how your A Level exams can be applied to breadth requirements.</p>
<p>Breadth courses may be taken at a California Community College. Please follow the most current Articulation Agreement between the community college and UC Berkeley for the business administration major. This information can be found at <a href="http://www.assist.org" target="_blank">www.assist.org</a>  by selecting the community college followed by UC Berkeley then the business administration major.<br/>
 </p>
]]>
</collegerequirementstext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>The highly competitive Haas Undergraduate Program, leading to a BS in Business Administration, accepts applications from freshman, transfer and continuing UC Berkeley applicants.</p>
<p><strong><u>FRESHMAN APPLICANTS:</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>Global Management Program (GMP)</strong><br/>
The selective Global Management Program blends rigorous business and general education with broad cultural understanding, preparing students to lead in financial services, communications, social sector solutions, foreign affairs, management consulting, and more.</p>
<p>Study in the four-year program begins in the summer with orientation and courses at UC Berkeley and includes the Berkeley Global Edge experience as a mandatory component—completed in fall of freshman year.</p>
<p>For further information, please see the <a href="https://haas.berkeley.edu/gmp/" target="_blank">GMP web site</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Management, Entrepreneurship &amp; Technology (M.E.T.)</strong></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-2fbbed59-7fff-3494-3050-22d30afe4d7a">The Management, Entrepreneurship, &amp; Technology (M.E.T.) program at the </span><a href="http://www.haas.berkeley.edu/">Haas School of Business</a><span> and the </span><a href="http://engineering.berkeley.edu/">College of Engineering</a><span> at Berkeley is a fully integrated, two-degree program. In four years, students earn a full Bachelor of Science degree in Business from Berkeley Haas and choice of a Bachelor of Science in Bioengineering (BioE), Civil Engineering (CE), Electrical Engineering &amp; Computer Sciences (EECS), Industrial Engineering &amp; Operations Research (IEOR), Materials Science &amp; Engineering (MSE), or from Berkeley Engineering.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-2fbbed59-7fff-3494-3050-22d30afe4d7a">For further information, please see the </span><a href="http://met.berkeley.edu/">M.E.T. website</a>.</p>
<p><strong><u>TRANSFER &amp; CONTINUING UC BERKELEY APPLICANTS:</u></strong></p>
<p>The Haas Undergraduate Program accepts applications from both transfer and continuing UC Berkeley applicants. All applicants must satisfy the minimum eligibility requirements:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Prerequisite courses (see list for <a href="http://haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/ucb_prereq.html">continuing UC Berkeley </a>or <a href="http://haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/transfer_prereq.html" target="_blank">transfer students</a>)</li>
	<li>Minimum of 60 semester or 90 quarter units.</li>
</ul>
<p>All courses required for admission must be completed by the end of the spring semester prior to starting at the Haas School of Business. Before applying to the school, visit the <a href="http://haas.berkeley.edu/undergrad" target="_blank">website</a> which contains complete information concerning academic qualifications for admission with details about prerequisites and degree requirements. Because there are many more applicants than spaces available, completion of the prerequisites does not guarantee admission.</p>
<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-f9db814f-7fff-1a71-7001-61435c7c0479">Management, Entrepreneurship &amp; Technology (M.E.T.)</span></strong></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-f9db814f-7fff-1a71-7001-61435c7c0479">Beginning Fall 2021, current UC Berkeley College of Engineering sophomores majoring in a M.E.T. academic track (BioE, CE, EECS, IEOR, ME, or MSE) are eligible to apply to the M.E.T. program during the fall of their sophomore year. If admitted, students will join M.E.T. during their junior year.</span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-f9db814f-7fff-1a71-7001-61435c7c0479">Continuing UC Berkeley students who intend to apply to the M.E.T. program must develop an academic plan of study that will satisfy the degree requirements of both the College of Engineering and Haas School of Business. Applicants are welcome to use the </span><a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1NcECQmnmUAfOA53PDLz7_Tn_Z-StUxw3?usp=sharing">M.E.T. Four-Year Plan Worksheet</a> for their engineering track to create a manageable plan that meets all of the degree requirements. The plan of study may not exceed the maximum of 20.5 units per semester for each of the 4 semesters while in M.E.T. (summer does not apply). </p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-f9db814f-7fff-1a71-7001-61435c7c0479">Students enrolled in any other College at UC Berkeley, or admitted as junior transfers to UC Berkeley, are NOT eligible to apply to the M.E.T. Program. In addition, we cannot review applications from students who have already earned a bachelor’s degree.</span>  For more information, see: <a href="https://met.berkeley.edu/continuing-student-admissions/">https://met.berkeley.edu/continuing-student-admissions/</a></p>
<p><strong><span id="docs-internal-guid-bd24d83c-7fff-e7eb-8546-0207e61aa529">Robinson Life Sciences, Business, and Entrepreneurship Program,</span> (LSBE)</strong></p>
<p><span>The Robinson Life Sciences, Business, and Entrepreneurship (LBSE) Program is designed to help students bridge scientific inquiry and research with entrepreneurship and commercial application. The program offers specialized coursework taught by award-winning faculty, networking opportunities and specialized career coaching, and mentoring opportunities within a peer-to-peer cohort of students who are working to become future leaders and innovators. </span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-59d76cce-7fff-435d-54b9-dbc720ab5eb2">In the </span>LBSE Program, students will earn a BS in Business Administration and a BA in Molecular and Cell Biology in the emphasis of your choice: Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology; Cell &amp; Developmental Biology; Genetics, Genomics, &amp; Development; Immunology &amp; Pathogenesis; or Neurobiology. Admission to the program is highly competitive and open only to students currently enrolled at UC Berkeley. Students apply to the LBSE Program during their sophomore year and must complete all prerequisite requirements for Business alongside the requirements to declare MCB. For further information, please see the <a href="https://haas.berkeley.edu/biology-business/">LBSE web site</a>.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<advisingtext name="Advising">
<![CDATA[
<p><span>Advisers are available in S450, the Haas Student Services Building, during any office hours:</span></p>
<p>Monday, Wednesday, Thursday and Friday from 9 a.m. to 4 p.m.<br/>
Tuesdays from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m.<br/>
*Closed for lunch daily 12:30 to 1:30 p.m.*</p>
<p>Advising is available by <a href="https://haasug.berkeley.edu/portal/ugadvising" target="_blank">appointment</a> or on a walk-in basis. For assistance by phone, please call 510-642-1421.</p>
]]>
</advisingtext>
<academicopportunitiestext name="Academic Opportunities">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Haas undergraduate experience offers opportunities for personal growth beyond the classroom including leadership development, career development, and close interaction with faculty and alumni. A number of programs support this design such as international study, case competitions, experiential learning workshops, student organizations, access to free tutoring services, and many more. The goal of the Undergraduate program office is to provide students with resources and opportunities to achieve their academic and career goals.</p>
<h3>International Study Opportunities</h3>
<p>Haas encourages all students to participate in international study programs as a means of broadening their education and developing a global view of business. International study can be enlightening and fulfilling on many levels, but it requires organization and self-motivation. Haas believes the benefits are well worth the effort.</p>
<h4>Information for Studying Abroad</h4>
<ul>
	<li>Program Options for Business Majors: <a href="http://www.haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/international_eap_info.html" target="_blank">EAP</a> and <span id="docs-internal-guid-c9ea1f89-7fff-54e2-7716-d7f901df153b"><a href="https://haas.berkeley.edu/undergrad/academics/global-opportunities/independent-programs/" target="_blank">Independent Program</a></span></li>
	<li><a href="http://haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/current/international/gmc.html" target="_blank">The Global Management Concentration</a> <span id="docs-internal-guid-570ad767-7fff-74b9-4ffe-8821cf9d8089">Note: GMC is being phased out. Last date to declare the GMC is Summer 2023</span>.</li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-2f6b2469-7fff-4338-9e06-ef52f90f0abb"><a href="https://haas.berkeley.edu/undergrad/academics/global-opportunities/eap/#Reciprocity" target="_blank">Information for Interested International Students &amp; EAP Reciprocity Students</a></span></li>
</ul>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-e59fa19c-7fff-c405-6572-a2367e21921e">If you have any questions about going abroad as a business major, email </span>renee@haas.berkeley.edu with your quick questions or to schedule an appointment.</p>
<h4>External Resources</h4>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-1f876343-7fff-242b-52e0-f0c365e6c1e3"><a href="http://studyabroad.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Berkeley Study Abroad (BSA)</a></span></p>
<p><span id="docs-internal-guid-0ca4145a-7fff-674f-79ee-c88f45e67a89"><a href="https://uceap.universityofcalifornia.edu/" target="_blank">Education Abroad Program (EAP)</a></span></p>
<p><a href="http://internationaloffice.berkeley.edu" target="_blank">Berkeley International Office (BIO)</a></p>
<h3>Undergraduate Case Competitions</h3>
<p>The Haas Undergraduate Program has developed an extensive case analysis competition program for both Haas undergraduate business majors and non-business majors. These competitions provide students with a variety of opportunities to develop and strengthen skills that will be critical for success during their employment search and throughout their careers.</p>
<h4><a href="http://www.haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/studentservicescasecompinternal.html#internal" target="_blank">Internal Case Competitions</a></h4>
<p>Berkeley students are able to participate in two annual competitions which are held at Haas and sponsored by the Haas Undergraduate Program.</p>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://www.haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/studentservicescasecompinternal.html#investment" target="_blank">Investment Banking Case Competition</a>, sponsored by Goldman Sachs</li>
	<li><span id="docs-internal-guid-9571324e-7fff-a545-f899-958de835c8f9">HBSA Novice Case Competition</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><a href="http://www.haas.berkeley.edu/Undergrad/studentservicescasecompexternal.html" target="_blank">External Case Competitions</a></h4>
<p>Haas selects teams of students to compete in several international competitions held at other universities. Examples include the following:</p>
<ul>
	<li>University of Auckland, New Zealand</li>
	<li>National University of Singapore</li>
	<li>Copenhagen Business School, Denmark</li>
	<li>Hong Kong University of Science and Technology</li>
	<li>Thammasat University, Thailand</li>
	<li>Sauder School of Business, University of British Columbia, Canada</li>
	<li>McGill University, Canada</li>
</ul>
<h3>Experiential Learning Program</h3>
<p>The Haas Undergraduate Program Office is proud to offer undergraduate students the ability to gain practical skills through the Experiential Learning Program workshops which are conducted throughout the academic year. Open to Haas undergraduate majors only, these non-credit workshops provide opportunities to enhance the students’ personal growth beyond the classroom setting. Workshops usually focus on one topic of general interest (i.e. Corporate Valuation) and are conducted by professional facilitators during 1 or 2 weekend days.</p>
<p>Below is a sample of some of the workshops and their brief descriptions. <strong>Actual workshop topics may vary and the semester in which they are offered may change.</strong></p>
<h3>Typical Workshops</h3>
<p><em>Finance Interview Training and Financial Statement Analysis</em> - This seminar introduces the terminology and approaches of financial statement analysis and to assist candidates seeking employment in any occupation involving financial statement analysis.</p>
<p><em>Introduction to Corporate Valuation</em> - Assists candidates seeking employment on Wall Street and in their field of finance. Through practical examples and exercises, the seminar illustrates the fundamentals of popular valuation techniques used by Wall Street practitioners.</p>
<p><em>Fundamentals of Financial Modeling</em> - Designed to develop financial modeling skills through actual hands-on construction of a financial model. Each participant will build their own interactive financial model from “scratch” to practice blending accounting, finance and Excel skills.</p>
<p><em>Mergers and Acquisitions/Leveraged Buyout</em> – Includes a conceptual discussion of both areas and hands on practical experiences in both merger analysis and leveraged buyout analysis. This session will give students the opportunity to build a standalone one page model for each area.</p>
<h3>Student Organizations</h3>
<p>Student organizations offer important services and activities for undergraduates. Each Haas-sponsored organization offers students a unique service or caters to a particular professional interest within the broad field of business. Haas values the co-curricular activities and experiential learning provided by these <a href="https://berkeleyhbsa.org/hso" target="_blank">sponsored organizations.</a> </p>
<p>For all other campus organizations not listed above, please visit the <a href="http://lead.berkeley.edu/about-student-orgs/" target="_blank">LEAD Center website</a>.</p>
]]>
</academicopportunitiestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

