<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Metabolic Biology</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Students in the Metabolic Biology Graduate Program will be engaged in research to understand metabolism and nutrition through basic and integrated research. Our inter-campus program is comprised of faculty from UC Berkeley and UCSF, and is engaged in groundbreaking research and interdisciplinary training in the areas of metabolic regulation; nutrient functions; and metabolic disorders, such as obesity, diabetes, cardiovascular disease, and cancer.</p>
<p>The graduate program fosters close interaction between students and faculty from several graduate groups, such as Molecular Toxicology, Endocrinology, Comparative Biochemistry, and Chemistry. This unique multidisciplinary environment of the program encourages Metabolic Biology students to collaborate and pursue research in a variety of fields.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/archive/2022-23/graduate/degree-programs/metabolic-biology/">Metabolic Biology</a>: MS, PhD</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Gregory W. Aponte, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Health and nutrition, nutritional sciences, signaling between the gut and the brain, neuropeptides, G-protein coupled receptors.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14587"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Danica Chen, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Aging, stem cell, diseases of aging.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14611"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Marc Hellerstein, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14828"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sona Kang, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Epigenetics, chromatin remodeling, gene expression, diabetes, metabolic diseases .<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/sona-kang"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anders Naar, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Gene expression, microRNAs, Mammalian Cell Metabolism, Metabolic Diseases, obesity, Type 2 diabetes, NAFLD/NASH, cancer therapies .<br/><a href="https://nst.berkeley.edu/people/faculty"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joseph L. Napoli, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Metabolism, nutritional biochemistry, fat-soluble vitamins, retinoids, retinoic acid, retinol, vitamin A, vitamin D, analytical biochemistry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15165"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel K. Nomura, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chemical biology, metabolism, toxicology, cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16349"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>James Olzmann, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Cell biology, organelle biogenesis, lipid droplet regulation, lipotoxicity, lipid storage, cell death, protein quality control, systems biology, metabolic disease, cancer .<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16268"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Barry Shane, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15665"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Martyn T. Smith, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cancer, genomics, toxicology, molecular epidemiology, exposome.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15044"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Andreas Stahl, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Metabolism, obesity, adipose tissue, brown fat, thermogenesis, tissue engineering, diabetes, fatty acid transport, fatty acid, stem cells.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16361"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hei Sook Sul, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Plant biology, health and nutrition, nutritional sciences and toxicology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15684"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jen-Chywan (Wally) Wang, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Steroid hormones, glucocorticoids, molecular physiology, Metabolic Diseases.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15597"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Bruce N. Ames, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Molecular biology, cancer, aging, mitochondrial decay, oxidants and antioxidants, micronutrient deficiencies and DNA damage, chronic inflammation and cancer.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14339"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

