<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Energy Science and Technology</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Designated Emphasis</h3>
<p>Reliable and economical energy is essential for society to endure. Reliance on fossil sources has now created a dependence that through progressive depletion in the not too distant future, may threaten the stability of economic systems and lead   to serious, if not irreparable, environmental damage. To avoid future catastrophic global conflicts and damaging climatic changes, present energy technologies are required to operate at their highest possible efficiencies with the lowest possible environmental impact, and new technologies need to be devised and deployed that are economic, renewable, and of low or zero climate impact.  This compelling scenario is propelling the development of a distinct area of science and technology that is focused on supporting the needs of the global energy market place. </p>
<p>The development of future, and even present-day energy sectors holds special challenges:  many supply and demand technologies have multi-decadal lifetimes, appropriate forms of governmental oversight are not widely agreed upon, and the market entry of new technologies is often effectively impeded and increasingly encumbered by national security concerns. The looming energy and climatic problems are truly global issues that complicate and accelerate other problems: many energy markets are international in nature, and over the next two decades, commercial energy use in developing nations will soon surpass that in the industrialized nations.</p>
<p>A deepening of the understanding of factors that affect efficiencies, more accurate modeling of systems and processes, study and discovery of new materials that enable innovative energy technologies, and effective management and policies are at the basis of continued dramatic change in a wide range of technologies.  This may stimulate a revolution in energy technology systems and their management that will hopefully alleviate the pressing energy needs of our present-day society and of generations to come. </p>
<p>The dominant energy sectors at present either rely on electricity generation from fossil sources, or on liquid fossil fuels for transportation.  The potential exists, for example, to change today’s electricity systems to encourage and incorporate new supply and demand-side innovations as well as innovative management policies. This would transform an enormous and vital component of U. S. infrastructure into one that provides greatly improved energy services, ensures energy diversity, is highly secure against market manipulation and terrorist attacks, and permits the provision of energy with greatly reduced regional and global environmental impacts. High efficiency combustion systems can be devised that strongly increase the conversion from hydrocarbon fuel to energy.  Based on new materials physics and materials chemistry, scientific advances and inventions in nanotechnology have opened the door to potentially affordable and efficient solar and thermoelectric power generation.  Novel nuclear reactors using designer fuel with minimal waste generation can now be conceptualized, significantly reducing fossil fuel consumption and nuclear waste, that in the coming decade will generate power without the inherent global warming from CO2 emissions. Advances in the understanding of biochemistry open the door to carbon-neutral technologies from biomass.  Similarly, dramatic transformations can be expected in transportation systems, where new fuels, such as hydrogen or alcohols, could be produced in mass by solar, biomass, or nuclear technologies, and be consumed in highly efficient fuel cell or battery-powered vehicles. All this is possible, but will require an unprecedented level of dedication to education and interdisciplinary energy study and research.</p>
<p>The Designated Emphasis in Energy Science and Technology (DEEST) advances these ongoing efforts at the University of California at Berkeley, and educates a new group of leaders for the global enterprise of creating future energy systems. </p>
<h3>Designated Emphasis in Energy Science and Technology (DEEST) </h3>
<p>The  Graduate Group in the in Energy Science and Technology has to date  eleven affiliated Ph.D. programs: Chemical Engineering, Chemistry, Nuclear Engineering, the Energy Resources Group, Materials Science and Engineering, Physics, Plant and Microbial Biology, Mechanical Engineering, EECS, the ME- Fluid Mechanics and Ocean Engineering Group, and Applied Science and Technology.  </p>
<p>The main goal of the DEEST is to enrich student’s technical education in an important field and to enhance and facilitate interactions between faculty and students in different programs by creating a flexible and integrated interdisciplinary research and teaching environment.  </p>
<h3>Academic Nature of the Designated Emphasis</h3>
<p>Students are required to complete academic work in the DEEST in addition to or as part of the full requirements of the affiliated programs. Where appropriate, affiliated Ph.D. programs may choose to recognize the DEEST as fulfilling the requirements of an outside field in their program. The Minimum Requirements are two technical courses and one additional course on Energy Management and Policy (see Section 2.4 Curricula). In addition, it is required   that the student  participate in seminars relevant to the DEEST when such are offered.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>To be admitted to the DE in Energy Science and Technology, an applicant must already be accepted into one of the affiliated PhD programs. Candidates must then submit a petition for admission to the DEEST Graduate Group Admissions Committee prior to taking the PhD qualifying examination in the affiliated program. A sponsoring faculty member in the student's affiliated program who is member of the DEEST Graduate Group must endorse the petition. As different affiliated programs have different examination requirements, the timeline for the application may vary. </p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">To be considered for admission, applicants must submit:</p>
<ol>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">The <a href="http://www.me.berkeley.edu/graduate/degree-programs/special-programs-ebs-de-deest/designated-emphasis-energy-science-and" target="_blank">DEEST petition form</a> and the Graduate Division &quot;<a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/pdf/GRAD.DEG.MAJ.CHNG.pdf" target="_blank">Change of Major or Degree Goal</a>&quot; petition to the chair of the DEEST for approval. The &quot;Change of Major or Degree Goal&quot; must also be signed by the vice-chair of the graduate studies of the applicant.</li>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">The &quot;Change of Major or Degree Goal&quot; petition to the Degrees Unit, 318 Sproul Hall, to indicate admission to the DEEST. Upon receipt of the appropriately signed petition, the addition of the DEEST will be entered into the Graduate Division and Registrar's databases.</li>
</ol>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">It is important to submit the “Graduate Petition for Change of Major Degree Goal&quot; since the student must be admitted to the DEEST before the qualifying examination. In the early stages of the DE, admission after the qualifying examination might be considered by the DE admission committee in exceptional cases, where it can be certified that a member of the DEEST Graduate Group was on the student’s qualifying exam committee, and that at least one of the student’s qualifying topics had sufficient content in the field of energy science or energy technology and engineering to meet the requirements of the DE. Such an exception must be recommended to the Graduate Division for its approval.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">The Admissions Committee of the Graduate Group for the DEEST decides on admission to the DEEST.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">For further information regarding admission to graduate programs at UC Berkeley, please see the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">Graduate Division's Admissions website</a>.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequriementstext name="Designated Emphasis Requriements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Normative Time Impact on Affiliated PhD Programs</h3>
<p class="Normal1">For students who can enroll in the DE curriculum to satisfy an outside field requirement in their PhD program of study, the DE should have little impact on normative time, as it might require only one additional class, plus one seminar per semester. Only for students who decide to join the DEEST after finishing their regular PhD coursework this might require additional time, but this problem should diminish in the future, and then be of relevance only for a small number of students.</p>
<h3>Curriculum</h3>
<p class="Normal1">The curriculum of the DE will consist of graded upper division and graduate courses with the following distribution: </p>
<p class="Normal1" style="margin-left:40px">One course required in Group A: Energy Policy and Management<br/>
Two required technical courses selected from two course groups, Group B: Energy Sciences, and Group C: Energy Technology.</p>
<p class="Normal1">The selection of courses will be maintained and regularly updated by the DE Graduate Group’s Curriculum Committee to follow developments in the field, and the offering of new relevant courses.</p>
<p class="Normal1">An initial list is given below. In addition, students are required to attend a  seminar series and discussion forum, as arranged by the curriculum committee, which is to serve as a focal point for communication and interaction between the participants. It is expected that students who elect the DEEST will do so in fields that broaden their subjects of study beyond that of their major. It is also expected that the major programs contain sufficient background to support the choice of courses for the DEEST. While the course selections do not have to focus on one technology or one science aspect, the choices in Groups B and C have been presented so as to allow a selection of coherent sets. Variations and exemptions may be allowed upon petition to the DEEST Graduate Group’s Advising Committee.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Required Group A: Energy Management and Policy </span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENE,RES C100">ENE,RES C100</span></td><td>Energy and Society</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENE,RES C200">ENE,RES C200</span></td><td>Energy and Society</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Politics of Energy and Environmental Policy</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENE,RES 280">ENE,RES 280</span></td><td>Energy Economics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CIV ENG 107">CIV ENG 107</span></td><td>Climate Change Mitigation</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MBA 212">MBA 212</span></td><td>Energy and Environmental Markets</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ESPM 261">ESPM 261</span></td><td>Sustainability and Society</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Group B:  Energy Sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Chemistry: graduate course sequence of three 1 unit course modules may serve as satisfying one 3 unit course in Group B.</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="PHYSICS 250">PHYSICS 250</span></td><td>Special Topics in Physics (this course may have different topics. Not all of these can be considered for the DEEST)</td><td class="hourscol">2-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHEM 143">CHEM 143</span></td><td>Nuclear Chemistry</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 176">CHM ENG 176</span></td><td>Principles of Electrochemical Processes</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 259">MEC ENG 259</span></td><td>Microscale Thermophysics and Heat Transfer</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Modeling Energy, Environmental, and Resource Systems</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 253">MEC ENG 253</span></td><td>Graduate Applied Optics and Radiation</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 180">NUC ENG 180</span></td><td>Introduction to Controlled Fusion</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 280">NUC ENG 280</span></td><td>Fusion Reactor Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 281">NUC ENG 281</span></td><td>Fully Ionized Plasmas</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 244">CHM ENG 244</span></td><td>Kinetics and Reaction Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 245">CHM ENG 245</span></td><td>Catalysis</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Group C: Energy Technology</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Electrical Power Systems:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="ENE,RES 254">ENE,RES 254</span></td><td>Electric Power Systems</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Nuclear Power Systems:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 225">NUC ENG 225</span></td><td>The Nuclear Fuel Cycle</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 161">NUC ENG 161</span></td><td>Nuclear Power Engineering</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 167">NUC ENG 167</span></td><td>Risk-Informed Design for Advanced Nuclear Systems</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 265">NUC ENG 265</span></td><td>Design Analysis of Nuclear Reactors</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 124">NUC ENG 124</span></td><td>Radioactive Waste Management</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 224">NUC ENG 224</span></td><td>Safety Assessment for Geological Disposal of Radioactive Wastes</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Safety Assessment for Geological Disposal of Radioactive Wastes</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">The Nuclear Fuel Cycle</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="CHM ENG 183">CHM ENG 183</span></td><td>Climate Solutions Technologies</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Renewable Resources:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Renewable Resources for Electric Generation</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Hazardous and Industrial Waste Treatment.</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 241B">MEC ENG 241B</span></td><td>Marine Hydrodynamics II</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Photovoltaics:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MAT SCI C226">MAT SCI C226</span></td><td>Photovoltaic Materials; Modern Technologies in the Context of a Growing Renewable Energy Market</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Materials Engineering:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MAT SCI 136">MAT SCI 136</span></td><td>Materials in Energy Technologies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Fuel Cells, Batteries, and Chemical Sensors: Principles, Processes, Materials, and Technology</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MAT SCI 213">MAT SCI 213</span></td><td>Environmental Effects on Materials Properties and Behavior</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="EL ENG 290Y">EL ENG 290Y</span></td><td>Advanced Topics in Electrical Engineering: Organic Materials in Electronics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 120">NUC ENG 120</span></td><td>Nuclear Materials</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 220">NUC ENG 220</span></td><td>Irradiation Effects in Nuclear Materials</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="NUC ENG 221">NUC ENG 221</span></td><td>Corrosion in Nuclear Power Systems</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Thermal Engineering:</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Thermal Environmental Control</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Computer-Aided Thermal Design</span></td><td class="hourscol"/></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 140">MEC ENG 140</span></td><td>Combustion Processes</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 246">MEC ENG 246</span></td><td>Advanced Energy Conversion Principles</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 249">MEC ENG 249</span></td><td>Machine Learning Tools for Modeling Energy Transport and Conversion Processes</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 252">MEC ENG 252</span></td><td>Heat Convection</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 253">MEC ENG 253</span></td><td>Graduate Applied Optics and Radiation</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 254">MEC ENG 254</span></td><td>Advanced Thermophysics for Applications</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 255">MEC ENG 255</span></td><td>Advanced Combustion Processes</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 256">MEC ENG 256</span></td><td>Combustion</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 257">MEC ENG 257</span></td><td>Advanced Combustion</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="MEC ENG 258">MEC ENG 258</span></td><td>Heat Transfer with Phase Change</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3>Examination Requirements</h3>
<p>The Qualifying Examination shall include examination of knowledge within the DEEST. The Qualifying Examination Committee shall include at least one member of the DEEST Graduate Group.  If a faculty member of the student’s major, the DE representative can serve either as the  chair or as an inside member of the committee.  If the DEEST representative is from an affiliated program, it is permissible for him or her to serve as either an additional inside or outside member.  Satisfactory performance on the qualifying examination for the PhD will be judged according to the established standards in the student’s major program.</p>
<h3>Dissertation Requirements</h3>
<p>The dissertation topic shall incorporate study within the DEEST. The Dissertation Committee shall include at least one faculty member of the DE to ensure that the dissertation contributes in significant manner to the interdisciplinary field of Energy Science and Technology.</p>
<h3>Degree Conferral Process</h3>
<p>Upon successful completion of the dissertation, the student’s transcript and diploma will record the designation: “Ph.D. in Affiliated Program Name with a Designated Emphasis in Energy Science and Technology.” This designation certifies that the student has participated in and successfully completed the DE in addition to the affiliated program’s requirements for the Ph.D.</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequriementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>* </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Van P. Carey, <i>Professor, Mechanical Engineering (EC Chair)</i>. </strong>Mechanical engineering, non-equilibirum thermodynamics, statistical thermodynamics, microscale thermophysics, biothermodynamics, computer aided thermal design, thermodynamic analysis of green manufacturing.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14006"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Michael Gollner, <i>Asst. Professor, Mechanical Engineering</i>. </strong>Combustion, Fire Dynamics, Wildland Fire, Fluid Mechanics.<br/><a href="https://me.berkeley.edu/people/michael-gollner/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Daniel Kammen, <i>Professor, Energy &amp; Resources Group, Nuclear Engineering</i>. </strong>Public policy, nuclear engineering, energy, resources, risk analysis as applied to global warming, methodological studies of forecasting, hazard assessment, renewable energy technologies, environmental resource management.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/daniel-kammen"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jeffrey R. Long, <i>Professor, Chemistry</i>. </strong>Inorganic and solid state chemistry, synthesis of inorganic clusters and solids, controlling structure, tailoring physical properties, intermetal bridges, high-spin metal-cyanide clusters, magnetic bistability.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15072"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bryan McCloskey, <i>Assoc. Professor, Chemical Engineering</i>. </strong>Electrochemical energy storage, electrocatalysis, molecular and ionic transport through polymers.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/bryan-mccloskey"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kristin A. Persson, <i>Professor, Materials Science</i>. </strong>Lithium-ion Batteries.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16917"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Seth Sanders, <i>Professor, EECS</i>. </strong>System theory, high frequency power conversion circuits, nonlinear circuit theory, renewable energy, electric machine design.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/seth-r-sanders"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Rachel Slaybaugh, <i>Asst. Professor, Nuclear Engineering</i>. </strong>Computational methods, high performance computing, neutron transport.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/rachel-slaybaugh"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Affiliated Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>J.Y. Chen, <i>Professor, Mechanical Engineering</i>. </strong>Computational modeling of reactive systems, turbulent flows, combustion chemical kinetics.<br/><a href="https://me.berkeley.edu/people/jyh-yuan-chen/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Christopher Dames, <i>Professor, Mechanical Engineering</i>. </strong>Nanostructured materials, thermal rectification, graphene, microscale heat transfer, nano scale heat transfer.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/christopher-e-dames"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Costas Grigoropoulos, <i>Professor, Mechanical Engineering</i>. </strong>Heat transfer, laser materials processing, nano-manufacturing, energy systems and technology.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/costas-p-grigoropoulos"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Per Peterson, <i>Professor, Nuclear Engineering</i>. </strong>Nuclear engineering, heat and mass transfer, reactor thermal hydraulics, nuclear reactor design, radioactive waste, nuclear materials management.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/per-peterson"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Lutgard De Jonghe, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Ceramic properties, advanced ceramics, silicon carbide, densification studies, microstructure development.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14536"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John S. Newman, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Chemical engineering, electrochemical systems, lithium batteries, industrial electrochemical processes, methanol fuel cells.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/john-s-newman"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

